<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_pnlJobDetails">
		
            <div id="JobDetailsHeaderRow" class="ie7fix">
                <div style="float: left; vertical-align: middle; line-height: 24px; width: auto">
                    <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlBackToResults" title="Back to search results" class="jobDetails_imgBack" href="search.aspx?pg=23">Back to search results</a>
                </div>
                <div style="float: right; margin-bottom: 25px; margin-left: 25px; text-align: right;">
                    <ul class="jobDetails_nav" style="line-height: 24px;">
<li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlPrev" title="Prev" class="jobDetails_imgPrev" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=9&amp;sort=&amp;rw=229&amp;jid=320742&amp;pp=ss">Prev</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblPageCount">

Job 230 of 500


</span>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlNext" title="Next" class="jobDetails_imgNext" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=9&amp;sort=&amp;rw=231&amp;jid=303970&amp;pp=ss">Next</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
</div>
            </div>
            

            
            <div id="JobDetailsTopRow">
                <div style="width:100%;float: left;" class="JobTitle" tabindex="-1">
               <h1>     <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobTitleText">Americas PowerApps and Flow Global Blackbelt - Developer</span>
</h1>
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div>
      
            
                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_Table1" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="100%">
                    <div style="display:table">
                        
                            <div class="jobDetails_jobDesc" style="width:60%;display:table-cell">
                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDescription" class="jobDetail_jobDesc_Content"><p>PowerApps, Flow and the Common Data Service from Microsoft are enterprise services for innovators everywhere to connect, create and share business apps with your team on any device in minutes. Harnessing the power of the Microsoft Cloud and with seamless integration to the vast Microsoft platform including Dynamics 365, Office 365 and Azure, PowerApps is enabling our customers to unlock new business agility.    <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft is seeking a talented full-stack developer who excels in their field. The ideal candidate has outstanding design, algorithm and coding skills, passion to tackle technically challenging areas and a deep desire to create breakthrough user experiences and products, via the Microsoft PowerApps, Flow and Common Data Service platforms. <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The Solution Developer will help to build the next-generation of solutions on top of PowerApps and prototypes that drive our Dynamics 365, Office 365 and Azure SaaS services. We are looking for a Solution Developer who is excited about helping customers make the most of their data and investment in the Microsoft Cloud. <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>You will have the opportunity to align PowerApps with a wide variety of data sources and technologies that are enabling the most strategic deals across Dynamics 365, Office 365 and Azure at Microsoft. In performing this role, the Solution Developer will work closely with our sales teams during the pre-sales process to take customers business requirements and build innovative Solutions that present the all up value of the Microsoft platform.    These solutions will leverage PowerApps as the x-platform and web app development too, will leverage Microsoft Flow for business automation and the Common Data Service as the data store. These assets will help our customers understand the opportunity of transforming their business using the Business Application Platform.     <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The PowerApps Solution Developer is at the forefront of business application trends and has direct access to the Product Group and the future roadmap. The ability to influence and articulate the future direction of the PowerApps strategy is important as is the ability to demonstrate how PowerApps, Microsoft Flow and the Common Data Service can leverage Microsoft’s broad array of technology and services.     <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Responsibilities:     <br></p>
<p>• Drive the One Microsoft story by designing and building demo assets that combine PowerApps with other Microsoft technologies to create compelling industry solutions.    <br></p>
<p>• This could include Dynamics 365, Office 365, IoT, Machine Learning, Power apps, Power BI, etc.<br></p>
<p>• Collaborating with the sales team to align Microsoft technology to customers business value to help solve complex business needs    <br></p>
<p>• Deliver impactful PowerApps architecture presentations that illustrate the value of the Microsoft platform.    <br></p>
<p>• Increase market share by driving partner and product team enablement activities for bridging functional gaps.     <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Basic Qualifications:<br></p>
<p>• Knowledge of Mobile Application Development, REST APIs and User Experience Design with the associated data models is a must<br></p>
<p>• 5+ years of software development experience <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Preferred Qualifications:<br></p>
<p>• Background in Microsoft SharePoint development, InfoPath solutions, Microsoft Dynamics CRM strongly desired 8+ years<br></p>
<p>• Experience with Dynamics 365, SharePoint and InfoPath are desirable<br></p>
<p> <br></p>
<p>Microsoft is an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to age, ancestry, color, family or medical care leave, gender identity or expression, genetic information, marital status, medical condition, national origin, physical or mental disability, political affiliation, protected veteran status, race, religion, sex (including pregnancy), sexual orientation, or any other characteristic protected by applicable laws, regulations and ordinances. If you need assistance and/or a reasonable accommodation due to a disability during the application or the recruiting process, please send a request to askstaff@microsoft.com.</p>
<p>
                            </p></span>
</div>
                            
                        
                        
                            <div style="padding-left: 30px;width:40%;display:table-cell;">
                                <table id="JobDetails_contentRight" role="grid" style="display:table;" summary="Job meta data"><tbody>
<tr role="row" style="display:table-row;">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeHeading">

Job #


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        
                                        <td>
                                            <div id="jobDetails_controls">
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobPostingId" style="display: none">320698</span>
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeText" style="font-weight: bold">1066857</span>
                                            </div>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationHeading">

Locations


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationText" style="font-weight: bold">United States, Other (United States)</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryHeading">

Job families


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryText" style="font-weight: bold">Sales</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_trDivision" role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionHeading">

Teams


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
			<td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionText" style="font-weight: bold">Dynamics</span>
                                        </td>
		</tr>
</tbody></table>
<div style="padding-top: 10px;">
                                    <input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnApply" value="Apply now" onclick="javascript:applyWebTrend();" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnApply" title="Apply now" class="SearchButton" style="float: left; margin-right: 8px;" type="submit"><input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnSaveJob" value="Add to job watch list" onclick="return false;" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnSaveJob" title="Add to job watch list" class="jobcartButton SearchButton" type="submit">
</div>
                                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_divServerDynamicjobtile">
                                    <div id="divDynamicjobtile" style="margin-top: 35px;">
                                        <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDynamicJobTileHtmlContent"><div class="feature-tile blue">
<a href="/" ms.title="Empower your future."><h3>Empower your future.</h3></a>
</div></span>
                                    </div>
                                </div>
                            </div>
                        
                    </div>
                    
                    
                    
                        
                            
                            



<style type="text/css">
.LinkedInTitle { font-size: 18px; color: #2D2D2D; width: 700px; padding-bottom:5px; } /*#2F89BD*/
.CompanyInsiderBlock { width:400px;}
</style>
<div class="CompanyInsiderBlock">

    
</div>


                        
                        
                        
                    
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
        
	</div></body></html>
