<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_pnlJobDetails">
		
            <div id="JobDetailsHeaderRow" class="ie7fix">
                <div style="float: left; vertical-align: middle; line-height: 24px; width: auto">
                    <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlBackToResults" title="Back to search results" class="jobDetails_imgBack" href="search.aspx?pg=19">Back to search results</a>
                </div>
                <div style="float: right; margin-bottom: 25px; margin-left: 25px; text-align: right;">
                    <ul class="jobDetails_nav" style="line-height: 24px;">
<li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlPrev" title="Prev" class="jobDetails_imgPrev" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=7&amp;sort=&amp;rw=189&amp;jid=324102&amp;pp=ss">Prev</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblPageCount">

Job 190 of 500


</span>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlNext" title="Next" class="jobDetails_imgNext" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=7&amp;sort=&amp;rw=191&amp;jid=322697&amp;pp=ss">Next</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
</div>
            </div>
            

            
            <div id="JobDetailsTopRow">
                <div style="width:100%;float: left;" class="JobTitle" tabindex="-1">
               <h1>     <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobTitleText">Business Analytics Specialist</span>
</h1>
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div>
      
            
                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_Table1" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="100%">
                    <div style="display:table">
                        
                            <div class="jobDetails_jobDesc" style="width:60%;display:table-cell">
                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDescription" class="jobDetail_jobDesc_Content"><p>Microsoft is the destination for experienced, collaborative, and passionate digital advertising professionals seeking a rewarding career and lifestyle. We offer a compelling portfolio of advertising products, innovative solutions and the opportunity to engage with some of the brightest minds in the digital industry.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft Search Advertising is a worldwide Sales, Marketing and Services organization on the cutting edge of the digital advertising industry. We are the engine that powers the buying and selling of digital advertising across all aspects of our digital portfolio including our high-growth search engine, Bing. <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The Microsoft Search Advertising Global Search Sales and Support group empowers advertisers around the world to reach their potential through paid search engine marketing (SEM) on the Microsoft Bing Ads platform. In Global Support, our mission is to empower advertising globally to achieve more through innovative services, unparalleled support, customer obsession &amp; advocacy.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>In support of our mission, the Global Support team is looking for a customer-obsessed experienced Data Analytics Specialist to join our Data and Analytics group. The DNA team manages BI infrastructure to support Global Support data needs, builds internal reporting and productivity tools; leads analytics projects that seek to drive improved customer experiences and business decisions throughout the entire Global Support footprint. This individual will also play a key role in defining our overall Global Support Business Intelligence strategy. <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Key Responsibilities:<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>•      Design, build, and deploy data models and cubes in Analysis Services to support projects ranging from shorter-term strategic questions from executives to longer term predictive and prescriptive analytical questions <br></p>
<p>•      Drive cross-functional business intelligence and analytics projects while working closely with Global Support LT to help define, develop, and deploy analytics that improve customer experiences and management visibility into operational efficiency/effectiveness<br></p>
<p>•      Manage and support BI projects related to various Global Support workflows integrating data from disparate sources and gathering requirements from many stakeholders/role-types<br></p>
<p>•      Evaluate, identify gaps or conflicts, and develop scalable solutions for existing data processes and tools used to support the Global Support businesses <br></p>
<p>•      Facilitate and work across Global Support to resolve critical technical or project issues related to data, modeling and BI Infrastructure<br></p>
<p>•      Build and maintain deep and productive partner relationships with end users, planners, product teams, etc. from a variety of world-wide teams<br></p>
<p>•      Understand how reporting impacts business decisions and help business leaders use data in accordance with statistical best practices<br></p>
<p>•      Discover trends across Search business through mining of datasets.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Key Competencies:<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>•      Demonstrated experience developing analytic approaches to complex business problems and to work in ambiguous situations and across organizational boundaries<br></p>
<p>•      Strong communications skills, particularly the ability to synthesize complex issues/scenarios into easy-to-understand concepts across both technical and non-technical audience’s and a proven ability to work with teams across multiple geographies<br></p>
<p>•      Strong knowledge of engineering methodologies including agile development and Sprint planning<br></p>
<p>•      Ability to deliver analytic rigor relative to the realities of the data; strategic ability to think and execute globally<br></p>
<p>•      Passion for leading-edge tools and technologies<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Basic Qualifications:<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>•      4 years of experience working with business analytics or bachelor’s degree (4 year)<br></p>
<p>•      Strong working knowledge of Visual Studio tools and source control (Git)<br></p>
<p>•      Strong skills and experience in Microsoft BI stack, SQL, SSIS, SSAS, SSRS, and preferred skills in big data technologies, ADL, Hadoop <br></p>
<p>•      Strong knowledge in SQL and database schema design.    Particularly Data Warehousing and Data Mart design<br></p>
<p>•      Hands-on experience managing Azure resources; familiarity with Azure Data Factory implementations and workflows <br></p>
<p>•      Ability to influence without authority and drive to completion/impact key projects<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Preferred Qualifications:<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>•      Experience in AzureML, R, Python or similar languages.<br></p>
<p>•      Exposure to Analytics, Big Data, large scale computing systems like COSMOS, Hadoop, MapReduce and other big data technologies, and machine learning<br></p>
<p>•      Experience retrieving data from Web APIs (OData, REST API, JSON, XML)<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft is an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to age, ancestry, color, family or medical care leave, gender identity or expression, genetic information, marital status, medical condition, national origin, physical or mental disability, political affiliation, protected veteran status, race, religion, sex (including pregnancy), sexual orientation, or any other characteristic protected by applicable laws, regulations and ordinances. If you need assistance and/or a reasonable accommodation due to a disability during the application or the recruiting process, please send a request to askstaff@microsoft.com.</p>
<p>
                            </p></span>
</div>
                            
                        
                        
                            <div style="padding-left: 30px;width:40%;display:table-cell;">
                                <table id="JobDetails_contentRight" role="grid" style="display:table;" summary="Job meta data"><tbody>
<tr role="row" style="display:table-row;">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeHeading">

Job #


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        
                                        <td>
                                            <div id="jobDetails_controls">
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobPostingId" style="display: none">325396</span>
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeText" style="font-weight: bold">1078468</span>
                                            </div>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationHeading">

Locations


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationText" style="font-weight: bold">United States, Seattle (WA)</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryHeading">

Job families


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryText" style="font-weight: bold">Business programs &amp; operations</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_trDivision" role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionHeading">

Teams


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
			<td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionText" style="font-weight: bold">Bing</span>
                                        </td>
		</tr>
</tbody></table>
<div style="padding-top: 10px;">
                                    <input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnApply" value="Apply now" onclick="javascript:applyWebTrend();" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnApply" title="Apply now" class="SearchButton" style="float: left; margin-right: 8px;" type="submit"><input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnSaveJob" value="Add to job watch list" onclick="return false;" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnSaveJob" title="Add to job watch list" class="jobcartButton SearchButton" type="submit">
</div>
                                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_divServerDynamicjobtile">
                                    <div id="divDynamicjobtile" style="margin-top: 35px;">
                                        <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDynamicJobTileHtmlContent"><div class="feature-tile blue">
<a href="/" ms.title="Empower your future."><h3>Empower your future.</h3></a>
</div></span>
                                    </div>
                                </div>
                            </div>
                        
                    </div>
                    
                    
                    
                        
                            
                            



<style type="text/css">
.LinkedInTitle { font-size: 18px; color: #2D2D2D; width: 700px; padding-bottom:5px; } /*#2F89BD*/
.CompanyInsiderBlock { width:400px;}
</style>
<div class="CompanyInsiderBlock">

    
</div>


                        
                        
                        
                    
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
        
	</div></body></html>
