<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_pnlJobDetails">
		
            <div id="JobDetailsHeaderRow" class="ie7fix">
                <div style="float: left; vertical-align: middle; line-height: 24px; width: auto">
                    <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlBackToResults" title="Back to search results" class="jobDetails_imgBack" href="search.aspx?pg=11">Back to search results</a>
                </div>
                <div style="float: right; margin-bottom: 25px; margin-left: 25px; text-align: right;">
                    <ul class="jobDetails_nav" style="line-height: 24px;">
<li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlPrev" title="Prev" class="jobDetails_imgPrev" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=4&amp;sort=&amp;rw=115&amp;jid=321188&amp;pp=ss">Prev</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblPageCount">

Job 116 of 500


</span>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlNext" title="Next" class="jobDetails_imgNext" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=4&amp;sort=&amp;rw=117&amp;jid=325467&amp;pp=ss">Next</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
</div>
            </div>
            

            
            <div id="JobDetailsTopRow">
                <div style="width:100%;float: left;" class="JobTitle" tabindex="-1">
               <h1>     <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobTitleText">Enterprise Information Architect/Sr Program Mgr, Services Business Solutions</span>
</h1>
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div>
      
            
                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_Table1" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="100%">
                    <div style="display:table">
                        
                            <div class="jobDetails_jobDesc" style="width:60%;display:table-cell">
                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDescription" class="jobDetail_jobDesc_Content"><p>The Data Management team inside worldwide Services Business Operations is chartered to enable positive business outcomes by driving right behaviors and decisions through strong data management and delivery.    <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The Enterprise Information Architect / Sr Program Manager is a foundational role to provide solid information architecture expertise across our worldwide Services business and data systems – on the Data Management team. You will work across a highly matrixed organization with cross-functional teams across the Services organization to provide architecture leadership to support Services business stakeholders.    You, as a technical leader, support several mission critical Microsoft Services initiatives with the goal of providing information architecture / data architecture expertise across the business and data platforms for both the current and future state architecture.    You will be responsible for data management roadmap for information architecture for data tools/systems including MDM, metadata, modeling and other tools and systems, as well as alignment with business capabilities and strategic project enablement.     Also, you are responsible for alignment with key stakeholders and peers – such as Data Governance, MDM, BI/Insights, Business Systems process teams, IT and engineering counterparts and Services business leaders. You will lead integration of complex initiatives pertaining to our business and data architectures to ensure successful implementation, execution and support.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Key Responsibilities:<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Enterprise Information Architect / Sr Program Manager <br></p>
<p>•      Work closely with business and system owners to drive Information Architecture best practices for Microsoft worldwide Services business<br></p>
<p>•      Provide thought leadership in Information Architecture across business and data systems <br></p>
<p>•      Lead and drive successful end-to-end data architecture and integration for strategic SAP ECC ERP implementation, including focus on data management components such as SAP MDG <br></p>
<p>•      Establish and govern worldwide Services Enterprise Information Architecture and roadmap including strategic business capabilities and priorities alignment<br></p>
<p>•      Evolve existing roles and responsibilities related to IA data management and ensure clear accountability for stewardship of the company’s principal information assets<br></p>
<p>•      Enhance existing enterprise-wide Data Management framework, with a focus on improvement of data quality and the protection of sensitive data through modifications to organization behavior policies and standards, principles, governance metrics, processes, related tools and data architecture <br></p>
<p>•      Facilitate the development and implementation of data quality standards, data protection standards and adoption requirements across the enterprise <br></p>
<p>•      Serve as a liaison between Business and Functional areas and technology to ensure that data related business requirements and rules for data quality and protections are clearly defined, communicated and well understood <br></p>
<p>•      Develop &amp; maintain inventory of the enterprise information maps, including authoritative systems, owners <br></p>
<p>•      Define indicators of performance and quality metrics and ensure compliance with data related policies, standards, roles and responsibilities, and adoption requirements <br></p>
<p>•      Provide leadership to Business, Functional areas, IT business and operations functions, to achieve their objectives; resolve issues related to Information Architecture<br></p>
<p>•      Provide progress reports to major initiative Steering Committees, Services leadership and IT Leadership as needed and oversee periodic updates to the Information Architecture Roadmap<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>To be successful in this role, you will possess as many of the following skills / experiences as possible:<br></p>
<p>•      Strong business systems and process focus with ability to tie-business processes, to business systems, to data systems and design systems accordingly<br></p>
<p>•      Hands-on expertise with Data Architecture and Modeling tools such as ERStudio, ERwin etc.<br></p>
<p>•      Familiarity with Enterprise Architecture tools such as Sparx or other<br></p>
<p>•      Hands-on knowledge of data architecture support activities such as data flow diagrams, source system analysis, source-to-target mappings etc. <br></p>
<p>•      Working knowledge of Business Architecture and capability mapping <br></p>
<p>•      Familiarity with Enterprise architecture frameworks such as TOGAF or Zachman<br></p>
<p>•      Experience with data protection and security protocols in Information Architecture, specific knowledge of GDPR compliance requirements<br></p>
<p>•      Expert knowledge of industry leading data virtualization, data quality, data profiling, and master data management practices and tools<br></p>
<p>•      Knowledge of various distributed computing data platforms and impacts on information architectures<br></p>
<p>•      Exceptional communication and negotiation skills via all modes and across all levels – executive level and tactical team <br></p>
<p>•      Excels at navigation and driving results across large matrixed organizations <br></p>
<p>•      Thrives in highly empowered role to execute broad assignments<br></p>
<p>•      Demonstrated consulting skills, with change management concepts and strategies, including communication plans, culture change and performance measurement system design<br></p>
<p>•      Collaborative team player orientation towards work relationships, strong cultural awareness <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Qualifications:<br></p>
<p>•      10 years expert level knowledge and experience managing programs requiring Enterprise Information Architecture concepts, best practices, tools and methods for Data Management<br></p>
<p>•      5 plus years expert level knowledge and experience of/with data architecture and modeling in both transitional system and data systems<br></p>
<p>•      Full life-cycle data implementation experience with SAP MDG or other large MDM tools / implementations with complex system integrations<br></p>
<p>•      Full life-cycle ERP implementation with Information Architecture focus and deliverables demonstrated<br></p>
<p>•      PMP certification or strong process-oriented project management skills preferred, Agile or scrum methodology preferred<br></p>
<p>•      A Bachelor’s degree, or equivalent experience.    MBA preferred<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Location:    Microsoft Headquarters, Redmond, WA<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Who we are<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>In Microsoft Services Business Operations (SBO), our goal is to power Worldwide Services through a common operating model that simplifies and improves customer and employee experiences. Our team drives a broad range of shared services functions that include Operations, Services Insights, Role Excellence, and Business Solutions &amp; Tools for both the Enterprise Services and Customer Services and Support businesses. <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft Digital, Services &amp; Success<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>With over 22,000 employees worldwide, we are dedicated to delivering on Microsoft’s mission to empower every person and every organization on the planet to achieve more. We are the voice of support services, the trusted advisor of consulting services, and the source of the world’s best enterprise strategies. Simply put, Services helps customers and partners get the most out of their technology investments. For more information, visit www.microsoft.com/Services.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Join us and be one who empowers billions! That’s incredible reach. When you combine that with your own inspiration, plus the freedom and support to make your ideas happen, you can make a huge impact on how people work and live all over the world.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft is an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to age, ancestry, color, family or medical care leave, gender identity or expression, genetic information, marital status, medical condition, national origin, physical or mental disability, political affiliation, protected veteran status, race, religion, sex (including pregnancy), sexual orientation, or any other characteristic protected by applicable laws, regulations and ordinances. If you need assistance and/or a reasonable accommodation due to a disability during the application or the recruiting process, please send a request to askstaff@microsoft.com.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>wwdss</p>
<p>
                            </p></span>
</div>
                            
                        
                        
                            <div style="padding-left: 30px;width:40%;display:table-cell;">
                                <table id="JobDetails_contentRight" role="grid" style="display:table;" summary="Job meta data"><tbody>
<tr role="row" style="display:table-row;">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeHeading">

Job #


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        
                                        <td>
                                            <div id="jobDetails_controls">
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobPostingId" style="display: none">307872</span>
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeText" style="font-weight: bold">1066460</span>
                                            </div>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationHeading">

Locations


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationText" style="font-weight: bold">United States, Redmond (WA)</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryHeading">

Job families


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryText" style="font-weight: bold">Business programs &amp; operations</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_trDivision" role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionHeading">

Teams


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
			<td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionText" style="font-weight: bold">Consulting services</span>
                                        </td>
		</tr>
</tbody></table>
<div style="padding-top: 10px;">
                                    <input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnApply" value="Apply now" onclick="javascript:applyWebTrend();" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnApply" title="Apply now" class="SearchButton" style="float: left; margin-right: 8px;" type="submit"><input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnSaveJob" value="Add to job watch list" onclick="return false;" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnSaveJob" title="Add to job watch list" class="jobcartButton SearchButton" type="submit">
</div>
                                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_divServerDynamicjobtile">
                                    <div id="divDynamicjobtile" style="margin-top: 35px;">
                                        <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDynamicJobTileHtmlContent"><div class="feature-tile blue">
<a href="/" ms.title="Empower your future."><h3>Empower your future.</h3></a>
</div></span>
                                    </div>
                                </div>
                            </div>
                        
                    </div>
                    
                    
                    
                        
                            
                            



<style type="text/css">
.LinkedInTitle { font-size: 18px; color: #2D2D2D; width: 700px; padding-bottom:5px; } /*#2F89BD*/
.CompanyInsiderBlock { width:400px;}
</style>
<div class="CompanyInsiderBlock">

    
</div>


                        
                        
                        
                    
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
        
	</div></body></html>
