<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_pnlJobDetails">
		
            <div id="JobDetailsHeaderRow" class="ie7fix">
                <div style="float: left; vertical-align: middle; line-height: 24px; width: auto">
                    <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlBackToResults" title="Back to search results" class="jobDetails_imgBack" href="search.aspx?pg=17">Back to search results</a>
                </div>
                <div style="float: right; margin-bottom: 25px; margin-left: 25px; text-align: right;">
                    <ul class="jobDetails_nav" style="line-height: 24px;">
<li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlPrev" title="Prev" class="jobDetails_imgPrev" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=7&amp;sort=&amp;rw=177&amp;jid=307817&amp;pp=ss">Prev</a>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblPageCount">

Job 178 of 500


</span>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <a id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_hlNext" title="Next" class="jobDetails_imgNext" href="jobdetails.aspx?gl=&amp;jc=&amp;ct=&amp;rg=&amp;ss=&amp;pg=7&amp;sort=&amp;rw=179&amp;jid=325907&amp;pp=ss">Next</a>
                        </li>
                    </ul>
</div>
            </div>
            

            
            <div id="JobDetailsTopRow">
                <div style="width:100%;float: left;" class="JobTitle" tabindex="-1">
               <h1>     <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobTitleText">Technical Solutions Professional - MTC</span>
</h1>
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
            <div>
      
            
                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_Table1" border="0" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0" width="100%">
                    <div style="display:table">
                        
                            <div class="jobDetails_jobDesc" style="width:60%;display:table-cell">
                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDescription" class="jobDetail_jobDesc_Content"><p>MTC Technical Architect - Data and AI     Microsoft envisions a world where passionate innovators come to collaborate, envisioning what can be and taking their careers places they simply couldn’t anywhere else.    This is a world of more possibility, more innovation, more openness, and sky’s-the-limit thinking - a cloud enabled world.        <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft Technology Centers (MTC) are collaborative environments that provide the place, experience and expertise to help our enterprise customers achieve their Digital Transformation by leveraging the power of Microsoft Cloud solutions and services.    We live Microsoft’s mission to empower every person and every organization on the plant to achieve more, with a focus on our three bold ambitions - reinvent productivity &amp; business processes, build the intelligent cloud platform, create more personal computing.    MTCs engage early in the project life-cycle where the customer is just beginning to define the vision, imagine what is possible and determine if it’s feasible.    <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The role requires an affinity for evangelism and competitive engagement.    The ability to win hearts and minds, and to explain abstract technical concepts in a business value context, is a must.     The Microsoft Technology Center (MTC) in Houston is looking for a Data &amp; AI Architect with deep technical, hands-on experience in designing, building and tuning, consolidating and managing complex data solutions.    While exposure to the broad SQL platform is desired, the emphasis of this role is increasingly on business insight (BI) solutions, Open Source platforms (Hadoop), Azure Data Services and data warehouses.    <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>As a MTC architect, you will be a senior technical solutions leader and accelerate customers’ digital transformation journey through Microsoft Big Data, Advanced Analytics and Artificial intelligence. You will deliver Strategy Briefings, Architecture Design Sessions and Proofs of Concept (POC) to articulate the business opportunity, propose and validate solution architecture, and transfer knowledge on best practices to Data Scientists, Business Decision Makers (BDMs), and App Dev Leads. <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Primary accountabilities include influenced revenue &amp; pipeline, customer satisfaction, customer facing time and contribution to design/delivery of innovative solutions that can be showcased at Houston MTC and beyond. The position requires deep technical expertise in the following areas:     <br></p>
<p>•      Analyzing large data sets, creating actionable insights and visualization by leveraging Microsoft Business Intelligence capabilities, including in-depth, hands-on knowledge of warehouse architecture, analytics, reporting tools, and SQL operational expertise     <br></p>
<p>•      Experience with Hadoop, Big Data and SQL-based appliances; preferred expertise with Python or R     Deep focus on Data/IoT related Azure services including Analytics, Data + Storage (SQL Database, Document DB, MySQL Database, SQL Data Warehouse, SQL Server Stretch Database, Azure Search), Intelligence, Hybrid Integration, Compute (SQL VMs, Oracle VMs, Biztalk VMs)        <br></p>
<p>•      Building data models for business intelligence, including competitive BI technologies e.g., Oracle, Tableau, Cognos     Strong software development skills are a must using both common Microsoft tools and common Open Source platforms     <br></p>
<p>•      High-level expertise in sophisticated identity, authentication, security, privacy, and compliance requirements, and experience integrating them into cloud and hybrid solutions required.     Industry leading experience with cloud, hybrid infrastructures, networking and adjacent technologies, architecture designs, migrations, and industry standards        <br></p>
<p>•      Deep understanding of cloud computing technologies, business drivers, and emerging computing trends including Machine Learning and Cognitive Services     Certification in domain-specific (Microsoft or competitive) technologies required     Certification in the following technologies preferred: cloud application development technologies (including OSS technologies) and Azure architecture and development exams (70-532 and/or 70-534)    <br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>The successful candidate will also:     <br></p>
<p>• 10+ years of success in consultative/complex technical sales and deployment projects    <br></p>
<p>• Have demonstrated experience and competency in customer engagement and collaboration     <br></p>
<p>• Have superior presentation skills and experience engaging with senior level executives     <br></p>
<p>• Be able to communicate complex concepts in a simple, business value context     <br></p>
<p>• Be a self-starter who takes ownership of opportunities; works independently, manages multiple simultaneous projects, and deals well with ambiguity and last-minute changes     <br></p>
<p>• Have the ability and passion necessary to maintain technical excellence with emerging technologies, including competitive technologies, while continuing to manage customer opportunities    <br></p>
<p>• Have a commitment to customer and partner satisfaction, including internal customers, strong listening, communication and presentation skills, and the ability to thrive in a competitive team environment <br></p>
<p>• Participate in internal Microsoft technical communities and in the broader industry events and publish blogs, whitepapers, reference architecture etc in area of expertise.        <br></p>
<p>• Have experience associated with the energy industry     <br></p>
<p>• Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science, Information Technology, or related field required or equivalent work experience combined with a minimum of 7 years of relevant work experience <br></p>
<p>• Modest travel (15%) outside of the Houston greater area is required.<br></p>
<p><br></p>
<p>Microsoft is an equal opportunity employer. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to age, ancestry, color, family or medical care leave, gender identity or expression, genetic information, marital status, medical condition, national origin, physical or mental disability, political affiliation, protected veteran status, race, religion, sex (including pregnancy), sexual orientation, or any other characteristic protected by applicable laws, regulations and ordinances. If you need assistance and/or a reasonable accommodation due to a disability during the application or the recruiting process, please send a request to askstaff@microsoft.com.</p>
<p>
                            </p></span>
</div>
                            
                        
                        
                            <div style="padding-left: 30px;width:40%;display:table-cell;">
                                <table id="JobDetails_contentRight" role="grid" style="display:table;" summary="Job meta data"><tbody>
<tr role="row" style="display:table-row;">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeHeading">

Job #


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        
                                        <td>
                                            <div id="jobDetails_controls">
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobPostingId" style="display: none">320285</span>
                                                <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCodeText" style="font-weight: bold">1069250</span>
                                            </div>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationHeading">

Locations


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblLocationText" style="font-weight: bold">United States, Houston (TX)</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryHeading">

Job families


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
                                        <td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobCategoryText" style="font-weight: bold">Sales</span>
                                        </td>
                                    </tr>
<tr id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_trDivision" role="row">
<th role="rowheader">
                                            <h2><span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionHeading">

Teams


</span></h2>
                                        </th>
			<td>
                                            <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblJobDivisionText" style="font-weight: bold">Sales</span>
                                        </td>
		</tr>
</tbody></table>
<div style="padding-top: 10px;">
                                    <input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnApply" value="Apply now" onclick="javascript:applyWebTrend();" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnApply" title="Apply now" class="SearchButton" style="float: left; margin-right: 8px;" type="submit"><input name="ctl00$ContentPlaceHolder1$JobDetails2$btnSaveJob" value="Add to job watch list" onclick="return false;" id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_btnSaveJob" title="Add to job watch list" class="jobcartButton SearchButton" type="submit">
</div>
                                <div id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_divServerDynamicjobtile">
                                    <div id="divDynamicjobtile" style="margin-top: 35px;">
                                        <span id="ContentPlaceHolder1_JobDetails2_lblDynamicJobTileHtmlContent"><div class="feature-tile blue">
<a href="/sales" ms.title="Microsoft Sales. Sales dynamo? If your version of the ABCs is “always be closing,” check out our jobs."><h3>Microsoft Sales. Sales dynamo? If your version of the ABCs is “always be closing,” check out our jobs.</h3></a>
</div></span>
                                    </div>
                                </div>
                            </div>
                        
                    </div>
                    
                    
                    
                        
                            
                            



<style type="text/css">
.LinkedInTitle { font-size: 18px; color: #2D2D2D; width: 700px; padding-bottom:5px; } /*#2F89BD*/
.CompanyInsiderBlock { width:400px;}
</style>
<div class="CompanyInsiderBlock">

    
</div>


                        
                        
                        
                    
                </div>
                <div style="clear: both; height: 0px! important;">
                </div>
            </div>
        
	</div></body></html>
