<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113164615">Sensor Test - Validation Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113164615</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 18, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is responsible for all research, design, development, calibration, test and qualification of camera &amp; sensing hardware for Apple products. This team is seeking for an exceptional sensing hardware Test/Validation Engineer with responsibilities of developing and deploying the test infrastructure for the mass production of various sensing hardware for Apple product line.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>At least 3 years of relevant experience</li>
<li>Good fundamental EE skills</li>
<li>Exceptional HW/SW problem solving skill.</li>
<li>Good SW development skills. Especially the position requires the proficient C/C++ programing and various algorithm prototyping and development skill. Objective-C Experience is plus. Also, the board level FW development experience would be highly appreciated.</li>
<li>Familiarity with mechanical design would be big plus.</li>
<li>Experience with prototyping the solutions, bench testing methodology and testing environments for any sensing hardware would be big plus.</li>
<li>Professional Level Optical Engineering expertise would be big plus.</li>
<li>Familiarity with processing mass production test result would be big plus (statistical analysis) </li>
<li>Strong communication, documentation and presentation skill</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of Sensing Hardware would be big plus.</li>
<li>Self-motivated professional</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Responsibilities:
Develop the prototype test solution (HW/SW) for the characterization, calibration and testing various sensing hardware.
Authoring the test plan documentation and Test &amp; Calibration SW
Design, develop and deploy the test/calibration infrastructure for MP
Performing the large scale build data analysis
Deliver executive level presentation
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS Electrical Engineering or equivalent</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Frequent travel to both Apple and suppliers' facilities will be required for the test infrastructure bring up. </p>
</div></body></html>
