<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112953416">Senior Database Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112953416</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 4, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As a member of the Systems &amp; Tools team within Supplier Responsibility, you will design and develop solutions to support our work in creating the most safe, fair, and environmentally responsible supply chain in the world.  A self starter who can manage multiple projects and priorities, the candidate should have several years experience with database development, and maintenance of business-critical, multi-user solutions.  Candidate can quickly scope program management, data, and analytics needs, and transform them into clean solutions to present products that deliver immediate impact to internal business partners.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Collaborative team player, converting requirements into technical architecture, balancing potential complexity with consideration to required scope &amp; schedule limitations</li>
<li>Deep relational database experience with FileMaker a must, plus other platforms (MySQL, Oracle, etc.). </li>
<li>Proficient in the full database lifecycle of design, implementation, support and maintenance activities</li>
<li>Experienced in building clear user facing workflows with optimal UX and UI, considering web publishing constraints</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Hands-on solution architect who will analyze business requirements using a combination of business acumen, process expertise, available data to implement high performing business solutions.
Deliver UX flows, wireframes, mockups, and interactive prototypes, collaborating with business users to gather feedback to be translated into high quality code
Design, develop, service, and tune database solutions.
Establish and maintain security and integrity controls
Seamlessly integrate systems with data visualization technologies such as Tableau
Investigate and resolve database alerts, performance, and availability, escalating issues as appropriate
Create and maintain documentation and standard operating procedures in relation to database usage and management</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S. in Bachelors degree in Computer Science, Software Engineering, or Business Information Systems (or equivalent work experience)
5-10 years experience in a database application development capacity</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Ability to manage multiple projects and tasks simultaneously with problem-solving and analytical skills
Excellent troubleshooting, customer service, and communication skills, developing strong cross-functional relationships
Highly analytical with a passion for simplicity
Self driven, with a consistent track record of going beyond what is expected while focused on the details
</p>
</div></body></html>
