<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53378919">Building Automation Engineer - Apple Park </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53378919</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We have a new and exciting opportunity for a Building Automation Engineer at Apple Park. The primary responsibilities are to ensure that buildings are operating at the highest levels of occupant comfort while maintaining critical environments without compromising efficiency.

Close coordination in utilizing the building automation system with all Real Estate &amp; Development groups is expected, including but not limited to the Facility Service Center (FSC), Environmental Health and Safety (EH&amp;S), Maintenance &amp; Operations, Critical Services, Global Data Center Services &amp; Energy Efficiency partners.

The work schedule for this position will be Wednesday through Saturday or Sunday through Wednesday: Day, Swing and Graveyard shifts available.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience with Automated Logic Corporation (ALC) building automation systems</li>
<li>Experience with lighting control systems - interior and exterior (Lutron experience a plus)</li>
<li>Experience with the development and implementation of control sequences of operation as related to building operation and energy efficiency</li>
<li>Experience with all varieties of commercial HVAC systems focusing on the coordination between chilled water central plants, variable air volume and radiant systems</li>
<li>Familiarity with building automation communication protocols (BACnet, Modbus and LONworks) as well as control network architecture</li>
<li>Familiarity with HVAC and electrical controls installation, field devices and control panel knowledge</li>
<li>Ability to manage and prioritize multiple projects with a constant focus on deadlines</li>
<li>Excellent project management skills</li>
<li>Excellent organizational and problem solving skills</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills (both verbal and written)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Essential Duties and Responsibilities:
Demonstrating a positive and approachable demeanor is very important while displaying strong analytical skills along with the ability to internalize complex issues and data with ease and efficiency to problem solve. The ability to operate with an entrepreneurial spirit by taking initiative and always challenging themselves and the team to improve our clients’ experience.
Actively practicing teamwork and innovation while being focused on results. Ability to multi-task and deal with ambiguity in a results oriented environment.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor of Science in Engineering or Applicable Building Engineering Experience
LEED Accreditation Beneficial
ALC Certification a plus</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">User experience with Apple products a plus
Experience in network architecture a plus
</p>
</div></body></html>
