<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83668870">HomePod Lead Test Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83668870</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 14, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Work and contribute towards the engineering of Apple HomePod technologies in the Interactive Media Group (IMG) at Apple. IMG provides the media and graphics foundation across all of Apple's innovative products, including iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, Apple TV, iTunes, and macOS. Developing cutting-edge software techniques, IMG takes the media experience to the next level.

We are looking for an outstanding software quality engineer with a strong technical background and understanding of Media and Wi-Fi technologies. In this role, you will be responsible for developing and conducting tests for HomePod product in the IMG Quality Engineering group at Apple.




</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in Wireless Data Transmission testing</li>
<li>Proficiency in Python, Perl and/or shell scripting</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple tasks and prioritize work accordingly</li>
<li>Solid knowledge of various video and audio media formats</li>
<li>Familiarity with iOS, macOS, Unix, and Xcode</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Your focus will be to develop, maintain and execute HomePod feature and functional test plans across a variety of network topologies to ensure the highest quality of HomePod functionality before it reaches our customers’ hands. Testing will comprise of Functional, Feature, Regression testing and Automation development. Automation will be key to this role’s success.

You will be also be responsible for the development of methodical testing strategies, creating &amp; tracking high quality bug reports, and reporting on project progress &amp; risk analysis. You will work very closely with the HomePod development, project management and cross-functional QA teams to ensure great quality for this amazing product.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S. in Computer Science or equivalent experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
