<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56555170">Marketing Recruiter</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56555170</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking to hire an experienced Recruiter to join our Marketing and Marcom Recruitment team.  The person hired will be responsible for providing the highest level of staffing services to Apple’s business leaders and candidates through Apple’s sourcing and selection processes performing full lifecycle recruitment while maintaining excellent relationships.  A high level of creativity, short- and long-term recruiting vision, business acumen and personal organization is required.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>7 to 10 years recruiting/sourcing experience, with at least 3 years of experience supporting creative teams.</li>
<li>Posses an understanding of marketing and advertising industries</li>
<li>Experience recruiting creative, account management and production roles.</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal communications skills, including ability to articulate an inspiring vision, clearly translate it into executable strategy</li>
<li>Proven ability to work in a fast paced environment and manage multiple tasks and projects simultaneously.</li>
<li>Excellent project management, personal organization and time management skills</li>
<li>Proven strong interpersonal and communication skills, with the ability to lead &amp; manage recruitment drives.</li>
<li> </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Work with hiring managers to provide creative recruitment solutions to meet the needs of the business
Gain in-depth understanding of the business functions and provide proactive solutions to ensure staffing goals and deadlines are met
Source, pre-screen and interview candidates
Develop and maintain networks both internally and externally in the organization to identify key talent and build ongoing pipelines
Be experienced in pro-active sourcing, including use of social networks and other alternative sourcing methodologies in order to ensure a robust pipeline of potential candidates
Determines appropriate recruiting sources for advertising and posting positions. Promotes the company image to candidates and external service providers
Manage the offer generation and approval process
Maintain responsibility for entry, maintenance and integrity of data using Apple’s internal systems
Provide analysis of Recruitment stats and activities to business partners on a regular basis
Negotiates and/or supports hiring manager in developing new hire compensation package/offers
Partner with key lines of business to stay informed of trends and upcoming hiring needs
Communicate tactfully, professionally, diplomatically and confidentially at all times, providing detailed updates regularly
Have a strong “can do” attitude with genuine commitment to customer service
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA or BS degree preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
