<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113003915">Digital Fulfillment Escalations Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113003915</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 7, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Americas Retail Fulfillment Operations Team (RFO) is looking for a Digital Fulfillment Escalations Analyst to drive the Apple Online Store (AOS) fulfillment performance to ensure a world class customer experience. The ideal candidate must be passionate about Apple’s products and customers and able to utilize his or her analytic skills to deliver creative, value-added solutions to the Operations organization at Apple.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience/expertise in Apple Online Store Service/Escalations/Support preferred</li>
<li>Understanding of Apple’s order fulfillment process</li>
<li>Understanding of AOS policies, programs and procedures</li>
<li>Excel and SAP skills</li>
<li>Strong verbal and written communication skills</li>
<li>Organizational skills and ability to multi-task</li>
<li>Excellent data analysis and presentation skills</li>
<li>Detail oriented and self-motivated individual able to function effectively when working independently or in a team</li>
<li>Ability to operate in a fast paced, rapidly changing environment</li>
<li>Ability to maintain poise and a positive attitude in a challenging environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Act as an escalation point for Operations related Executive Escalations working with Ops partners to provide root cause and corrective actions
- Investigate and resolve post ship fulfillment issues in partnership with Logistics
- Review Customer Satisfaction surveys for trends and customer experience impacts, and work cross functionality to provide solutions and improve the customer experience
- Participate in project planning and testing for fulfillment related projects
- Work cross-functionally across Operations, AOS, and the regions to determine best practices and provide an amazing customer experience
- Participate in execution activities including new product introductions
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors Degree </p>
</div></body></html>
