<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112930011">Reliability Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112930011</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 29, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Are you passionate about the development, characterization, and failure analysis of next-generation materials? If so, we are looking for a well-qualified individual to join us in Apple's Materials Reliability Group by taking on an influential role, tasked with assessing material-level reliability.

If you excel in the following focus areas, you may be a great fit for our team.
Identifying high-risk failure modes at the material level, especially early in the design cycle
Developing new stress conditions based on material physics and any novel user behaviors the new material may enable
Identifying and implementing the necessary equipment and test specifications critical for validating material performance
Assessing product-facing reliability through stress test data and material understanding
Identifying failures from experimental testing to investigate root cause through failure analysis
Supporting vendor testing by traveling and collaborating with global teams to implement novel solutions

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>We're looking for you to possess the following technical attributes to excel within our team:</li>
<li>Deep understanding of materials science including mechanical, electrical, and optical behavior of materials</li>
<li>Experience working in a lab environment with focus on understanding root cause of material failures</li>
<li>Experience with Failure Mode Effects Analysis and reliability prediction modeling</li>
<li>Expertise in materials characterization, both with standard techniques (SEM/EDS, XPS, XRD, FIB, FTIR, etc) and with creative non-standard techniques that would enable new technologies</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with metallurgical principals and techniques</li>
<li>Strong background in optically clear materials and coatings</li>
<li>Proficiency in statistical data analysis and the ability to communicate your results clearly to others</li>
<li>Experience in investigating the physics of failure through efficient selection of analytical techniques</li>
<li>Ability to identify root cause and recommended corrective action based on results from multiple data sources</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">To be successful in this role, your ability to establish and maintain interdepartmental relationships is critical. Roughly 60% of your effectiveness stems from exercising influence over the design team to help you implement solutions. We find individuals with the following personal skillset are best suited for this role:

Extraordinary problem solving abilities
Excellent written and verbal communication skills
Strong attention to detail
Ability to handle multiple projects at once
Ability to independently complete experiments and resolve problems
Flexibility and adaptability to approach new tasks
Dynamic and “can do” attitude with the dream to work with a great team towards cutting-edge products
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">This position requires 5 - 10+ years of experience in materials science/engineering, and/or reliability. A degree in Materials Engineering, or an equivalent field, is required - M.S. or PhD desired.</p>
</div></body></html>
