<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55806302">Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55806302</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join a team transforming the way apple delivers its cloud infrastructure. We are looking for a highly motivated developer to help enhance our tooling. The primary responsibilities will be building internal applications, integration with various existing tools, and ensuring quality development.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>At least 3 years of experience developing tools or building automated frameworks</li>
<li>Proficiency in at least two of Java/Scala/Python/Go/Swift/R</li>
<li>Proficiency in SQL</li>
<li>Experience managing MySQL DDL</li>
<li>Experience working with distributed data pipelines using system like Spark/Flume/Kafka</li>
<li>Proficiency with Django or Rails</li>
<li>Working knowledge of HTML5/JavaScript/CSS</li>
<li>Proficiency in scripting UNIX shells</li>
<li>Experience defining and consuming REST/SOAP APIs</li>
<li>Good understanding of code reviews</li>
<li>Proficiency working with GIT on a distributed team</li>
<li>Must be self directed, analytical and work well in a large cross functional environment</li>
<li>Deals well with Ambiguity and embraces change in a fast moving environment</li>
<li>Strong written and oral communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Fleet Planning and Delivery team is looking for an experienced Software Engineer to work to work on tools, automation, and testing infrastructure. You will join a team of people responsible for ensuring that our fleet management is as smooth as possible. We are looking for someone who can thrive in a small team while working collaboratively with other cross-functional teams. Work closely with various teams to understand the requirements for the tools. Design, build, and test systems to support new and existing use cases.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS in Computer Science or Electrical Engineering (or equivalent) </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Knowledge of data center management
Knowledge of integration with complex data sets</p>
</div></body></html>
