<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56897775">Systems QA Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56897775</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We're looking for a driven and dedicated senior Systems QA engineer to lead testing on new technologies. As a member of our fast-paced group, you will have the unique and rewarding opportunity to be part of a new project and shape upcoming products that will delight and inspire millions of Apple’s customers every day.
Quality is an important aspect of our innovative products, and as a System QA Engineer, you will have a significant impact on helping to deliver functional and stable products to millions of customers in a fast-paced environment. The ideal candidate will possess an energetic personality with excellent communication and interpersonal skills, attention to detail, patience, and a passion for product usability. 

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li> 3+ years of SQA or System Test experience, preferably on consumer-facing hardware/software products.</li>
<li>Experience with hardware and/or software development lifecycle processes.</li>
<li>Experience with testing consumer computer and/or mobile devices.</li>
<li>Ability to work with cross-functional and remote teams </li>
<li>Demonstrates QA skills with at least 2 complete product cycles, from concept to customer shipment.</li>
<li>Ability to communicate technical concepts to a non-technical audience</li>
<li>Ability to solve difficult problems with innovative and maintainable solutions</li>
<li>Must be detail oriented and strive for product excellence</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">-Reviewing and testing hardware and software features of one or more products.
-Identifying important and relevant customer scenarios, integrating test cases from those scenarios based on risks, and executing them.
-Work closely with development teams, to identify and understand key features and their underlying functionality.
-Working closely with other team members &amp; test teams to create and execute tests cases.
-Isolate and report defects effectively quantifying customer impact, and verify fixes through regression testing and other test methodologies.
-Analyzing data from test results; generate reports from that data.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS EE/CE/CS or equivalent (MS preferred)</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Scripting automation experience (ie, Python, Perl, etc.) 
Developing and executing testing using computer vision and robotics solutions.
Testing experience with machine learning
Strong data analysis &amp; tools experience (Excel or Numbers required; Matlab, LabView or similar tools preferred) 

</p>
</div></body></html>
