<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113134829">AppleCare Service Technician</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113134829</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple Internal Service Support is seeking an experienced Apple Certified hardware technician to join our team at our Austin Campus for the service and repair of Apple owned equipment.  The ideal candidate should be a hard working, self driven individual with no less than 2 years of Apple Service hardware experience with an advanced knowledge and understanding of Apple operating systems and iOS devices and hands on break/fix experience with current Apple Product.   Current ACMT and ACiT certifications preferred. A knowledge and understanding of GSX and AST is required.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ability to multi-task</li>
<li>Broad minded with meticulous attention to detail</li>
<li>Strong verbal and written communication skills</li>
<li>Advanced knowledge and understanding of Apple Operating systems and iOS</li>
<li>Ability to troubleshoot software and hardware issues on all Apple Products</li>
<li>Current Apple Certifications, ACMT, ACiT</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with current and vintage Apple Products</li>
<li>Strong analytical problem solving skills</li>
<li>Excellent customer focused people skills</li>
<li>Keen understanding of teamwork and focus on customer service</li>
<li>Understand the importance of personal and corporate privacy</li>
<li>Works well independently and in a team environment</li>
<li>Must have valid driver’s license</li>
<li>Willingness to perform in-campus onsite repairs</li>
<li>Ability to lift and transport up to 50 lbs.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will be providing break/fix service and support on all Apple owned product such as the iMac, Mac Pro, MacBook, MacBook Pro as well as the iOS devices iPhone and iPad including system installs and upgrades.  You must have the ability to work independently with minimal supervision with meticulous attention to detail.   You will be managing, tracking and maintaining seed stock inventory and the repair ticketing database. Your ultimate goal will be to diagnose, repair and return Apple Own Products for our internal community so they can continue with their primary job function of creating and supporting our amazing products</p>
</div></body></html>
