<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-86550930">Data Science &amp; Machine Learning Internship, Apple Maps </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 86550930</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking a data science and machine learning intern to join the Apple Maps Routing and Traffic team in 2018. Our group works on some of the most challenging and impactful big data problems in the industry today, making sense of petabytes of data to deliver critical navigation functionality for millions of users who depend on Apple Maps.

This internship opportunity is perfect for highly-motivated students who want to apply their coding skills and machine learning knowledge to a large and important application.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience with machine learning theory and practice, particularly neural networks and sequence-based models.</li>
<li>Experience using machine learning software, such as Python Sci-Kit, TensorFlow, Weka, MATLAB, or R.</li>
<li>Experience with Java or Python along with an understanding of CS fundamentals and object-oriented programming.</li>
<li>Experience with Hadoop or Spark is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a data science and machine learning intern, you will use your skills to help our organization develop novel solutions to improve the quality of traffic information, ETAs, routes, and navigation using large-scale streaming data. On a day-to-day basis, you will collaborate with experts in the fields of machine learning and traffic, apply your knowledge to solve interesting data-driven problems, and work hands-on to implement your ideas.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Currently pursuing a M.S. or Ph.D. in Computer Science, Math, Stats, Civil Engineering (Traffic with a data science focus), or related fields.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Students in Computer Science, Math, Stats, or related fields (or Civil Engineering / Traffic with a data science focus) are strongly encouraged to apply.</p>
</div></body></html>
