<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83590065">Analog Mixed-Signal (AMS) Design Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83590065</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Design and productize Analog/Mixed-Signal circuits</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate should have the following qualifications or experience:</li>
<li>•Typically requires at least 8 years of experience and should have demonstrated taking chips to production in the following areas:</li>
<li>•Good knowledge of data converter architectures and understanding design tradeoffs.</li>
<li>•Good knowledge of bandgaps, bias, opamps, switched-cap circuits, LDOs, low power oscillators, PLLs, feedback and compensation techniques.</li>
<li>•Design for ESD compliance.</li>
<li>•Good knowledge of mixed-signal design techniques.</li>
<li>•Good knowledge of high precision techniques in presence of device mismatch.</li>
<li>•Experience in C/Matlab/VerilogA modeling.</li>
<li>•Strong device physics knowledge as it applies to analog IC design.</li>
<li>•Hands-on experience in using spectrum analyzers, oscilloscopes, signal generators, etc. to validate analog designs.</li>
<li>•Experience in working with production test engineers to produce test plans and design for testability details</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Transistor-level feasibility study for various Analog/Mixed-Signal circuit blocks.
•Designing blocks and documenting design simulation and verification towards formal design reviews.
•Drive mask design to implement layout views of designs and drive layout reviews.
•Post-layout and top-level simulations to validate top-level integration.
•Defining production and bench-level test plans.
•Taking lab measurements to validate performance compliance with the spec.
•Driving and reviewing yield/lab test results to drive bug fixes.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS, Preferred in EE</p>
</div></body></html>
