<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56052893">Database Automation Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56052893</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Mar. 28, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Do you like the idea of running global services that are used by millions of passionate people all over the world? Do you enjoy working on challenges that no one has solved yet? Do you like changing the game? Imagine what you could do here!  At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there’s no telling what you could accomplish. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Understanding of the software development lifecycle  </li>
<li>4/5 years experience in key developer role with strong hands-on experience in SQL and PL/SQL development on Oracle/MySQL/PostGres</li>
<li>Proven track record of designing and implementing technical solutions for automation, efficiency , scalability and capacity planning.</li>
<li>Strong scripting/programming and data manipulation experience in Perl, Python or Unix bash/shell.</li>
<li>Good understanding of regular expressions and expertise with large scale multi-threaded development.</li>
<li>Experience in developing scripts for alerting, monitoring and reporting to maintain a stable production environment of large highly available, and/or high-transaction databases.</li>
<li>Experience in troubleshooting and problem solving on live production systems is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Develop robust automation solutions for the DBA team managing various RDBMS. Includes installations, patching, baselining, security, disaster recovery,  monitoring/alerting and capacity planning.

Responsible for the automation needs for the high availability and high performance databases.

Database developer works well under pressure and relies on extensive experience and team's input to proactively automate database tasks.

Will require knowledge of scripting in Linux and as well in procedural sqls ( SQL/PLSQL) 

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
