<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112960913">Privacy &amp; Information Security Counsel - data security, compliance</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112960913</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As Privacy &amp; Information Security Counsel you will have the opportunity to work with a dynamic and experienced team on privacy and information security issues impacting Apple’s business and products across the globe. You will work directly with business and engineering teams to design innovative privacy and security solutions for products and services as well as across the legal department on Apple activities and regulatory issues.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Outstanding academic credentials</li>
<li>5+ years privacy experience as an associate at a top-tier law firm or business</li>
<li>In-house experience a plus</li>
<li>Excellent organizational and communication skills</li>
<li>Exceptional written and verbal skills</li>
<li>Proven ability and commitment to work both independently and collaboratively with numerous people at all levels throughout the company</li>
<li>Sound business judgment, and flexibility/adaptability to manage multiple wide-ranging matters, conflicting deadlines, and new areas of expertise as business needs change</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability, in a positive, commercial and practical manner, to identify, prioritize and resolve issues quickly and effectively</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">At Apple we are about creating great products. Part of making products great is designing products that respect security and privacy. This role offers the opportunity to work directly with key members of the business, engineering and legal teams on a variety of cutting edge projects including:

privacy and security by design reviews and projects

assist with data security incident response

support privacy and security compliance and auditing frameworks

manage privacy and security related issues in business partnerships 

assist with drafting of policies and procedures surrounding privacy and security laws
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA and JD

Attorney with 5+ years of experience in privacy and information security law</p>
</div></body></html>
