<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113074434">Data Analytics and Business Intelligence Analyst </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113074434</li>
<li title="Sacramento, California, United States">Sacramento, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline"> 
The Information Systems &amp; Technology (IS&amp;T) team manages key business and technical infrastructure at Apple -- how we take an order online, the experience with technology in our retail stores, how much network capacity we need around the world, the processing of every credit card an iTunes customer uses, and closing the books. IS&amp;T does it all.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Required Experience and Skills</li>
<li>Desire and ability to thrive in a fast-paced, highly demanding, dynamic business and information technology environmentAbility to maintain composure and focus in stressful situations</li>
<li>Customer service orientation</li>
<li>High standard for attention to details and 100% accuracy</li>
<li>Excellent verbal and written skills</li>
<li>Superb time management and multi-tasking skills</li>
<li>Ability to meet and exceed goals and objectives with minimal direct supervision and only high-level direction</li>
<li>Excellent risk management and information security knowledge, skills, and abilities</li>
<li>Basic Linux and Mac OS system administration</li>
<li>Unix shells (bash and ksh)</li>
<li>SQL</li>
<li>Advanced skills with Excel</li>
<li>Advanced skills with Tableau</li>
<li>Advanced skills with R</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience working with a variety of data structures and formats</li>
<li>In-depth knowledge and skills to use and apply descriptive and inferential statistics including probability, hypothesis testing, estimation, associations, correlation, regression analysis, and forecasting</li>
<li>Analytic and business intelligence skills to identify meaningful patterns, analyze them, and then integrate and communicate them via data visualization and reporting techniques</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with data modeling using R or other similar software</li>
<li>Strong data visualization, reporting, and communications skills and abilities</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with map reduce using Hadoop</li>
<li>Familiarity with enterprise information technology</li>
<li>Effective communication; up, down and laterally</li>
<li>Preferred Experience and Skills</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience producing reports with Business Objects</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with Splunk</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with Oracle</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with Teradata</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with R</li>
<li>Knowledge and experience with map reduce using Hadoop or similar software</li>
<li>Expanded Roles and Responsibilities</li>
<li>The Data Analytics and Business Intelligence Analyst (Analyst) operates independently and is responsible for coordinating the storage, retrieval, presentation, and analysis of data for the IS&amp;T HelpLine and Network Operations Center. The Analyst will present data to peers, managers, directors, and VPs; and highlight data patterns that could be useful for making business decisions.</li>
<li>Effectively plans and leads projects and tasks to determine data needs, data sources, and data users</li>
<li>Coordinates with other data producing and data consumer groups</li>
<li>Coordinates data access with other data stewards and data users</li>
<li>Develops data requirements document and collaborates with developers and data miners to obtain the required data</li>
<li>Validates data quality by:</li>
<li>Filtering data</li>
<li>Analyzing and removing errors</li>
<li>Analyzing and removing inconsistencies</li>
<li>Ensures that the data is accurate and meets the stipulated requirements</li>
<li>Analyzes data using various methods including:</li>
<li>Data visualization</li>
<li>Basic descriptive statistical measures</li>
<li>Statistical dependency (association) and correlation</li>
<li>Trend analysis</li>
<li>Predictive analytics</li>
<li>Modeling</li>
<li>Develops data visualizations and reports on the data, trends, probabilities, forecasts, and other business intelligence based on data</li>
<li>Skillfully communicates the data, reports, and findings using a number of media including:</li>
<li>Oral presentations</li>
<li>Written reports, charts, and graphs</li>
<li>Web-based, interactive reports and data visualizations</li>
<li>Takes the initiative to develop and automate regular and ad-hoc reports</li>
<li>Researches, and if applicable, implements new technologies and methods in the areas of</li>
<li>Data analysis</li>
<li>Data visualization and presentation</li>
<li>Data glossaries and libraries</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The IS&amp;T HelpLine and Network Operations Center (NOC) provide technical support services to Apple’s employees, contractors, and vendors throughout the world, 24 hours a day, 365 days a year. We support Apple’s products and services from hardware to software. We also support Apple’s world-class information technology infrastructure from our data centers through our data and voice networks to each user’s Mac or IOS device…and everything in between.
 
We are currently looking for a highly motivated, technically savvy, business intelligence analyst who has excellent analytic and data visualization skills to join our HelpLine team. This is an extremely fast-paced and highly demanding environment. If you have what it takes, we would like to talk to you.

Work hours
Variable but typically Monday-Friday, 8 AM to 5:00 PM
Holiday and on-call work required at times

Responsibilities
Business intelligence
Data management, analysis, visualization, and communication
Business process management
Technical documentation
Project coordination and management

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's degree in a related field preferred.</p>
</div></body></html>
