<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-70907582">Senior Web Development Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 70907582</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 28, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Maps Evaluation Engineering team is looking for product focused senior front end engineer to build Maps Evaluation data visualization platform. The front end engineering position is a role suited for candidates who enjoy approaching a wide variety of problems with small teams to make an outsized impact on Apple products. The ideal candidate will have experience building large scale, custom designed,  web applications that have tight integration with back end web services. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in designing and implementing web applications with Javascript/HTML5/CSS and web services integration</li>
<li>Knowledge of best practices and methodologies for writing web application</li>
<li>Extensive experience with front end frameworks such as Angular, Polymer, React, or Backbone.</li>
<li>Understanding of design/UX principles and ability to participate in design discussions</li>
<li>Understanding of performance, data security, large scale deployment, continuous integration, unit testing</li>
<li>Ability to pick up, understand, and communicate complex concepts</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills and a strong desire to work with both technical and non-technical audiences</li>
<li>Ability to drive product feature and requirement gathering with external customers</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a developer on the Maps team, you have the opportunity to build various web services and tools supporting many different teams collect, verify, and troubleshoot a wide variety of algorithms. You will work with engineers, statisticians and test engineers to improve a core product that touches millions of users worldwide each day.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA / BS in Computer Science or equivalent work experience.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Nice to have:
Knowledge of the Adobe Creative Suite
Experience in designing and integrating web services (REST)
Experience with at least one major language suited to web services programming such as Java, Scala, Python, Node.js
Understanding of data modeling and storage with NoSQL platforms and/or relational data stores such as Postgres/MySQL</p>
</div></body></html>
