<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113179438">Antenna Design Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113179438</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Define and implement antenna system architecture to optimize the radiation performance for wireless portable devices.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Must have working experience of antenna design and tests, anechoic chambers, and RF test equipment. Hands-on is a must.</li>
<li>Must have strong problem solving skills and strong working knowledge of radiation performance. Antenna and wave propagation theoretical background is essential.</li>
<li>Experience with different wireless communication systems such as GSM/LTE/UMTS, 802.11, Bluetooth, etc.,</li>
<li>Experience with regulatory requirements and process for wireless consumer devices, including FCC, PTCRB, CTIA, ETSI, TIA/EIA, etc.</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills required, both written &amp; verbal.</li>
<li>Detail oriented - taking data  and making meaningful tables/graphs/averages.</li>
<li>Preferred Experience:</li>
<li>Experience with simulation tools such as CST, HFSS is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The candidate should be able to design antennas suitable for wireless handheld devices with excellent radiation performance, including TRP, TIS, SAR, and EMC. Work closely with other RF and antenna design engineers, mechanical and industrial designers, and EMC engineers to integrate the antenna design in our products. The candidate will be expected to performance radiation performance measurements, create test plans, execute them, publish test reports, provide feedback to the other design engineers, and lead some of the manufacturing of antenna.

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MSEE required, PhD is preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
