<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113191511">Market Research Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113191511</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for an extraordinary market researcher to join our team. The successful candidate will be highly experienced in consumer market research who works effectively with others and is a creative and resourceful problem solver.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in consumer market research and analysis in client and vendor roles</li>
<li>In-depth knowledge of consumer market research analysis methods and techniques</li>
<li>Second-to-none client service bent</li>
<li>Extremely detail oriented</li>
<li>Experience with using Keynote for reporting data</li>
<li>Knowledge of Apple products, markets, and consumer trends </li>
<li>Able to manage many projects in a fast-paced environment, often under tight timeframes </li>
<li>Highly proficient with SPSS, Excel, SQL</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Collaborate with research managers and clients to understand business objectives and develop research approaches that are best suited to yield actionable insights
Assist in the design of questionnaires, screeners, discussion guides, and other materials required in the process of conducting consumer research
Analyze data on customers and consumers and produce Keynote reports that clearly and concisely communicate key insights</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Highly proficient with Python, R
Strong design aesthetic as it relates to the visual communication of information
Advanced degree</p>
</div></body></html>
