<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-51868047">Senior Camera Hardware Systems Design Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 51868047</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 14, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The camera hardware team is responsible for design, development, and validation of all camera systems and modules in Apple products. The senior engineer in this role will take end-to-end responsibility for system modeling, system trade-offs, and data analysis of camera hardware and sensor systems that incorporate camera hardware. This multi-functional role requires highly analytical skills in system design parameters, in system concept development, system evaluation, data analysis, and reporting of conclusions. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years relevant experience.</li>
<li>Experience with lock-in pixels, high speed modulation/demodulations system and high speed / high power emitter.</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of imaging physics and system modeling.</li>
<li>Strong background in testing and characterization of high accuracy electro-optical system.</li>
<li>Proficiency in MATLAB for data analysis and simulations setups.</li>
<li>Excellent written and reporting skills for clear reporting of data analysis and conclusions.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Key contributor to end-to-end implementation of system simulations, system modeling and evaluation.
Reporting of simulation analysis based on high-level system description.
Engagement of cross-functional discussion with non-imaging teams and map their imaging needs to sensing implementations.
Engagement with cross-functional teams to discuss implications and trade-offs on camera HW and sensor system performance.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master's or higher in related engineering field</p>
</div></body></html>
