<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52464960">Senior ASIC Design Engineer - Fabric</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52464960</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 6, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. 
Apple is leading the charge in high performance mobile computing with state of the art SOC's announced with each of its revolutionary new product offerings.  At the core of all Apple mobile SOC's, is an on chip system interconnect bus that supplies the SOC agents with their requested load and store data from on chip and off chip memories.  With every generation the max bandwidth, lowest latency, lowest area, and lowest power requirements are more stringent and require complex planning in order to achieve on Apple's schedules.
Be part of the team creating the architecture and design for the on chip system interconnect bus for next generation Apple SOC's.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>This position requires thorough knowledge of the ASIC design flow, front end RTL coding and Design verification, synthesis, scripting and netlist generation. </li>
<li>The ideal candidate will have the following background</li>
<li>At least 10+ years experience in ASIC design flow</li>
<li>Expertise in at least one of the following disciplines:</li>
<li> CPU load store units or BIU unit design</li>
<li>L1, L2, or larger on chip or off chip cache design</li>
<li>Coherent memory system design</li>
<li>SOC system bus design</li>
<li>Memory controller design</li>
<li>Networking packet based bus protocols</li>
<li>Proven track record of complex high performance designs in high volume production for low power applications</li>
<li>Design for high performance, low area, and low power</li>
<li>Familiarity with CDC, DFT, UPF, other Asic flow checks, and backend timing closure at hihg frequencies is a plus</li>
<li>Strong communication skills are a pre-requisite as the candidate will interface with a lot of different people within and outside the company</li>
<li>Self starter and highly motivated</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a senior member of the SOC Design team you will be responsible for the following

1)   Microarchitecture and design of RTL code for high performance (low latency, high bandwidth, high frequency), low area, and low power

2)   Own all aspects of development design for large SOC blocks including: Internal and external IP integration, design of system bus and control bus logic for connectivity of IP blocks to main SOC infrastructure, ownership of the Integration Spec for the design project, integration and optimization of any memories and hard macros required for the block,  run synthesis, netlist generation, and timing closure for the block

3)   Work closely with Chip Architecture, memory system Design, Design verification, Physical Design, DFT, and power teams to achieve first tapeout success on designs

4)   Develop and maintain methodology/flows/checks for designs

5)   Work with multi-disciplinary groups to make sure designs are delivered on time and with highest quality by incorporating proper checks at every stage of the design process
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MSEE or related field</p>
</div></body></html>
