<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-88480115">Senior Software Architect, Apple Media Products</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 88480115</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for a highly motivated, entrepreneurial, and hands-on, senior software architect to join the Apple Media Products Server Architecture team.  You will be a key part of shaping the future architecture of Apple Media Products.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10+ years of experience in software development</li>
<li>6+ years of internet-scale application services development</li>
<li>A strong foundation in Computer Science fundamentals, such as: data structures and algorithms is required</li>
<li>Ability to develop new and innovative applications, as well as, debug and refactor existing code.</li>
<li>Strong experience with Java and JVM tuning is required</li>
<li>Experience working with scalable distributed systems in practice, like: Cassandra, Voldemort, Memcached, Redis or Hadoop</li>
<li>Experience with processing large datasets using Hadoop, Map Reduce and Spark</li>
<li>Experience with ORM technologies like Hibernate</li>
<li>Some experience with large-scale datacenter application deployments, including: monitoring and capacity planning</li>
<li>Demonstrated experience architecting, developing and deploying internet-scale, distributed and mission critical services is required</li>
<li>Strong software and system design skills are required</li>
<li>Ability to communicate effectively, both written and verbal, with technical and non-technical cross-functional teams</li>
<li>A desire to work in a fast-paced and challenging work environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for a self-starting, energetic individual with very strong leadership and technical capabilities. The ideal candidate should have at least 10 years of experience working on internet-scale services.  As part of the Apple Media Products engineering team, your responsibilities will include: working closely with other engineering team members and site reliability engineers.  The selected candidate will not be afraid to question assumptions and possesses excellent verbal, written and communication skills.  You will need to have both the technical chops and the communication skills to articulate your ideas, as well as, influence others.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Bachelors or Masters degree in Computer Science, Mathematics, or relevant industry experience preferred
</p>
</div></body></html>
