<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113158178">Regional Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113158178</li>
<li title="New York City, New York, United States">New York City, New York, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Participates with other managers to establish strategic plans and objectives. Makes final decisions on administrative or operational matters and ensures operations effective achievement of objectives.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square"><li>Works on complex issues where analysis of situations or data requires an in-depth knowledge of the company. Participates in corporate development of methods, techniques and evaluation criteria for projects, programs, and people. Ensures budgets and schedules meet corporate requirements. DISCRETION: Erroneous decisions will have a serious impact on the overall success of functional, division, or company operations. INTERACTION: Regularly interacts with executives and/or major customers. Interactions frequently involve special skills, such as negotiating with customers or management or attempting to influence senior level leaders regarding matters of significance to the organization. SUPERVISION: Directs and controls the activities of a broad functional area through several department managers within the company.  Has overall control of planning, staffing, budgeting, managing expense priorities, and recommending and implementing changes to methods.</li></ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Direct the growth and strategic direction of overall ASC operations covering multiple countries. Initiate programs to set and achieve business objectives. Accountable for recruitment, training and development of ASC management. Set performance targets for the ASC teams annually. Set parameters of the ASC’s and Apple shops business performance against objectives. Establish and maintain meaningful relationships with key stakeholders within resellers businesses to grow and develop long term business partnerships.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">High school diploma, college degree preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
