<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-37203360">CPU Power Analysis Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 37203360</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Dec. 3, 2014</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">
In this crucial role, the individual will be responsible for driving all aspects of power analysis and optimization for energy efficient CPU designs. The role will involve working with cross functional teams to analyze multiple use cases at various phases of the design cycle.


</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li> The ideal candidate will have 5+ years of hands on experience in CPU implementation or power analysis.</li>
<li> Familiar with CPU microarchitecture.</li>
<li> Experience with industry standard power analysis tools.</li>
<li> Familiar with techniques to reduce static and dynamic power using industry standard place and route tools.</li>
<li> Timing fundamentals and timing-power trade offs.</li>
<li> Understanding of device physics.</li>
<li> Familiar with power modeling for standard cells and other IPs.</li>
<li> Scripting proficiency with Perl, TCL or other scripting languages.</li>
<li> Good analytical skills to draw conclusions from large amounts of data.</li>
<li> Good communicator who can accurately describe issues and follow them through to completion.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">
• Create/maintain scripts and methodologies to generate power results and analyze them.
• Work with various teams to set power targets early in the project and drive to those.
• Work with the CPU microarchitecture team to analyze power impacts of features and drive changes to reduce power.
• Work with the implementation team to analyze the build recipes to reduce static and dynamic power.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">
BSEE/MSEE required</p>
</div></body></html>
