<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113052059">Technology Specialist - Travel and Meetings</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113052059</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are currently seeking a highly talented travel technology developer with mid-office expertise who will contribute to the advancement of Apple’s WW Travel and Meetings organization. This role will support oversight of the development and maintenance pipeline for the organization’s travel technology systems and will be a key contributor within the department, driving the development of innovative, cost effective, and automated processes of the global organization. 

The Technology Specialist will actively participate in process improvement team discussions, conduct research, and facilitate problem resolution for system issues. This individual will act as a subject matter expert (SME) at industry events, be able to work under pressure and be effective at supporting differing regional nuances and time zones for the global program. This role requires someone who has the ability to recommend innovative approaches, policies, and procedures to affect continual improvements in efficiency of operations and services performed by Apple’s WW Travel and Meetings organization.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Travel and/or Meetings and Event Industry Experience</li>
<li>Qik Developer or equivalent development language</li>
<li>Database experience (MySQL or equivalent), SQL queries and stored procedures</li>
<li>Web Services and related tools</li>
<li>Web Content Management System (Mura, Wordpress or equivalent)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Drive operational efficiency, redundancy, team skills
• Increase team velocity (from Idea, through development and testing to deployment)
• Help create a culture of innovation, appropriate risk taking, continuous improvement
• Assist with Business Partner Relationship Building and Customer engagement
• Assist managing key vendor relationships </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Bachelor's degree or equivalent required</p>
</div></body></html>
