<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112947248">Sr. Software Engineer, Systems</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112947248</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this position, you will use your skills as a software engineer to envision and specify the software stack of computerized electro-mechanical test equipment, automated sample handling systems and their integration with external systems, such as an MES. You will design specifications that will be delivered to third party equipment manufacturers and guide external resources through implementation. Once realized, you will work with your teammates to verify that the design was built to specification.  You will also design and develop the communication of test equipment with internal systems, using a variety of protocols and languages. You will work in a multidisciplinary team of engineers to develop complex systems used locally or globally for battery performance testing.

You will report to the battery data systems team in Cupertino, and work with equipment and battery manufacturers locally and globally.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Solid technical background with experience in the areas of electro-mechanical systems and data system integration</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple projects across different engineering disciplines </li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to work directly with suppliers to solve test problems</li>
<li>Ability to coach and provide solid guidance to lab personnel for consistent lab performance</li>
<li>Self-starter with innovation, integrity and attention to details</li>
<li>Relies on data to justify technical decisions</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Ability to clearly explain technical issues, justify technical decisions, and write technical specification documents</li>
<li>Fluent in written and oral Mandarin Chinese a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Collect requirements and write detailed software specifications covering GUI, controls and feedback loops, tool validation and diagnostics, data integration with backend systems, and data encryption for test equipment
•Design and develop the communication of test equipment with the MES system, and build out MES features as needed
•Install, manage, and provide end-user software support for instruments that collect test data from battery test equipment at Apple labs
•Assist in developing scripts for data transfer from Apple external labs to our servers
•Automate testing procedures e.g. marathon validation runs
•Test prototype equipment and automated handling system with pre-deployed software at the local engineering lab to ensure that it is stable and meets the requirements
•Review and approve third-party vendor implementations, and validate against Apple specifications, and operator procedures (SOPs)
•Manage software system updates
•Identify opportunities for continuous improvement of equipment and test processes
•Domestic and global travel may be required
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS in Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Control Systems Engineering or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
