<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57217716">Platform Architect -Graphics, Camera, Video</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57217716</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, you will be a member of a System-on-Chip team, working with various hardware and software engineering groups to shape the architecture of Apple's future devices. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have experience/skills in several of the following areas:</li>
<li>Knowledge of the inner workings and data flows of gaming / video / camera Apps.</li>
<li>C/C++ modeling of SOC and use cases for performance and power simulation.</li>
<li>GPU / Camera / Video IP memory access patterns and usage of system caches.</li>
<li>Worked on logic design of graphics, video, or camera hardware.</li>
<li>Writing specification documents, in collaboration with engineers across different disciplines.</li>
<li>Gathering and analyzing data to compare architectural design alternatives.</li>
<li>Investigating how Apps use the SOC, by running and profiling on the live silicon (e.g. smartphone).</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will have responsibilities for architecting Apple’s graphics, camera, and video system-on-chip subsystems. Your work will be highly visible and critical for delivering best performance and power efficiency in Apple’s future products.

Documenting the SOC performance and power requirements together with Camera, Graphics, and iOS teams.
C/C++ modeling of graphics, camera, and video data flows, and integration with other SOC models.
Running simulations of future camera, video, and gaming applications.
Careful analysis and presentation of the simulation results to enable data-driven design decisions.
Writing of architectural specification documents, in collaboration with cross-functional teams.
Work with both hardware and software design teams.
Silicon validation on prototype hardware.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS or PhD in CS, EE, or related field.</p>
</div></body></html>
