<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57498969">Senior Software Engineer, iTunes Editorial Tools</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57498969</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>- Minimum of 5 years experience in a professional programming position</li>
<li>- Experience with Cocoa (macOS or iOS) and ObjectiveC/Swift.</li>
<li>- Knowledge of Apple framework paradigms and commonly used patterns.</li>
<li>- Being able to drive a project from a simple idea to the finished product.</li>
<li>- Experience with remote data handling, REST, asynchronous programming.</li>
<li>- Will to focus on details and building the best user experience.</li>
<li>- Aptitude to independently learn new technologies.</li>
<li>- Experience in shipping shrink-wrapped applications for macOS or iOS is a plus.</li>
<li>- Experience in functional programming is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">iTunes Editorial Infrastructure Team is looking for a Senior Software Engineer to provide new tools in order to support its fast paced growth. We're looking for a Cocoa engineer to help us build the next generation macOS Cocoa tools that will drive out current and future media products. The ideal candidate should have experience building and shipping macOS (or iOS) applications. If you love to start with an empty canvas and build a great desktop application, crave building better user experiences and have the will to keep the users not only productive but delighted, this is the job for you!
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSCS or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
