<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112980878">Web Services Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112980878</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 11, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We build systems that help improve the productivity of iOS engineers. We build device/system log analysis systems, searchable knowledge bases, bug triaging bots, workflow productivity applications and many more. We work on various web based technologies to build scalable and large data systems. Our team has both the modern web app expertise and search/large data expertise. We are looking for full stack engineers with good problem solving skills who can excel in more than one open source web platforms like NodeJS, Python Django, Php Symphony. We collaborate with the product teams on many innovative hack week projects.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong analytical and problem solving skills</li>
<li>Strong Web framework experience- Ruby on Rails, PHP, Python, Java</li>
<li>Good programming / scripting skills</li>
<li>5+ years industry experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will join a dynamic team responsible for working on projects that help iOS Motion features while collaborating with various cross functional teams. You will be involved in design, development and execution of new test scenarios, bug reporting and troubleshooting as well as developing innovative automation tools.

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors Degree in Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Electrical Engineering, or equivalent experience.
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Great team player with good communication skills
Thrive in a collaborative environment and can clearly communicate while confidently driving multiple projects across many teams
Obsessively passionate and inquisitive, and seek to solve everyday problems in innovative ways
Laser-focused on the smallest details that are meaningful to our customers</p>
</div></body></html>
