<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113080593">Software Engineer/Data Infrastructure</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113080593</li>
<li title="Denver, Colorado, United States">Denver, Colorado, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>8+ years of experience in software engineering.</li>
<li>Hands-on experience in software development methodologies and working knowledge in one or more programming languages (Java, C/C++, Python, Go).</li>
<li>Demonstrated track record of creating and building instrumentation for processing/assessing/tracking network performance.</li>
<li>Impressive track record of being able to deliver on complex initiatives, solid project management skills and attention to detail.</li>
<li>Flexibility and comfort working on a dynamic, fast-growing effort with minimal documentation and process. </li>
<li>Quick learner. Aptitude to deal with ambiguity, and enthusiasm to help solve difficult issues.</li>
<li>Exceptional communication skills, for collaborating across many participating teams.</li>
<li>Nice to have:</li>
<li>Big data pipeline (Kafka, Spark) </li>
<li>Distributed database (ElasticSearch)</li>
<li>Familiarity with the Networking protocols (BGP, MPLS)</li>
<li>Knowledge of network monitoring protocols (Netflow, SNMP etc)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Implement network measurement and analytics system for analysis of network performance, failures, errors, health. The position requires building systems to ingest and analyze data from switchers/routers, designing models to summarize data, building complex queries and statistical algorithms to build insights and create dashboard using modern visualization tools. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master/PhD in Engineering or Computer Science.</p>
</div></body></html>
