<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113033138">Core Audio Software Tools Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113033138</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Audio Software Tools Engineer
The Interactive Media Group (IMG) provides the audio, video, and graphics foundation across all of Apple's innovative products, including iPhone, iPod, iPad, Apple TV, Apple Watch, and Mac, as well as professional and consumer applications from Final Cut and Logic to iLife and iWork.




</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Excellent software system design/programming skills in C++</li>
<li>Solid understanding and implementation skills in object-oriented methodologies</li>
<li>Solid understanding of realtime, multi-thread programming concepts and operating system concepts </li>
<li>Strong problem solving and debugging skills </li>
<li>Excellent knowledge of validation concepts such as test based development, unit testing, and white box API tests</li>
<li>Passion for creating superior user experience </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Core Audio team within IMG is working on advancing the audio software infrastructure on Apple’s platforms.  These platforms have a considerable level of complexity in the way that audio is routed through the system and how they integrate the various audio hardware components that are available. This position will involve developing a deep understanding of the systems that manage this.  The ideal candidate for this position will work with the team to contribute to the development of a comprehensive system that will be used to characterize and validate the audio software stack on these platforms.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS/PhD in CS, EE, or related</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Solid understanding of digital audio and digital signal processing is a plus
Experience with audio hardware architectures is a plus
Experience with databases is a plus</p>
</div></body></html>
