<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57239587">Technical Project Manager - Apple Online Support</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57239587</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Self-Service Engineering team is looking for an exceptional technical product manager to lead the design, implementation, delivery and maintenance of software projects for Apple's customer facing online support applications. In addition to overseeing the work of a team of engineers, this role requires working closely with several cross-functional teams to effectively coordinate the complex interdependencies of the applications in our portfolio. The ideal candidate will have a strong eye for detail on par with Apple’s high standards, coupled with a deep technical understanding of building scalable web applications and the ability to translate business process needs to functional and technical requirements.  The candidate must possess excellent leadership skills, be a proactive, solution-oriented individual with strong written and verbal communication skills. Exceptional project management skills, and a proven ability to influence and collaborate across the organization are key qualities required to be able to excel in this role.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>High ownership, self-sufficient, hands-on leader to drive quality across the project; in usability and experience from requirements, technical design reviews, testing and more - the position requires a hands-on, get-the-job-done attitude</li>
<li>Ability to reason logically and creatively, identifying problems, drawing valid conclusions from the data available, and develop effective solutions while applying creative thinking in the design and development of high performing web applications</li>
<li>Ability to understand business needs, articulate trade offs and debate solutions with both business and engineering teams</li>
<li>Excellent verbal and written communication skills</li>
<li>Excellent interpersonal skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Manage projects, setting priorities and measurable objectives, monitoring and reporting on the process, progress and results
• Review technical development team deliverables for accuracy and completeness
• Exercise sound management practices and support a productive environment
• Extract clear action plans from complex requirements and technical discussions
• Take ownership of challenging, fast-paced projects in a cross functional environment with changing priorities</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS degree in computer science or equivalent field with 7+ years experience</p>
</div></body></html>
