<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-99608141">Siri Senior DevOps/Build Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 99608141</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 15, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Siri is looking for a talented DevOps/Build &amp; Release engineer who is passionate about continuous integration and delivery. 
Join a fast moving team working hard to automate all aspects of a continuous delivery pipeline for Siri. 
This DevOps focused individual will be a key player in how software is built and delivered.


Join the Siri team at Apple!</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Expert knowledge and experience with Software Version Control systems: SVN, GIT (Git and GitHub knowledge is a plus) </li>
<li>Knowledge of Java Build Systems and Tools including: Maven, Ant, Gradle  </li>
<li>Knowledge of other Build Tools and Languages included: Java, C, C++, Ruby, Python</li>
<li>Experience working with server clusters consisting of hundreds or thousands of machines</li>
<li>Experience maintaining automated build systems such as Jenkins or TeamCity</li>
<li>A desire to write tools and applications to automate work rather then do everything by hand</li>
<li>Familiarity with Splunk for investigating or monitoring problems on systems</li>
<li>Ability to use and create web applications using REST, JSON, or similar protocols</li>
<li>Experience machine system configuration using tools such as: Puppet, Chef, Salt, Docker</li>
<li>Linux system administration experience: ssh, monitoring processes, attaching storage, cleaning disk space, tailing logs</li>
<li>Experience with Java test frameworks such as JUnit</li>
<li>Experience implementing Continuous Integration or Continuous Delivery processes in engineering teams</li>
<li>Experience managing and integrating test automation into various points in a deployment pipeline</li>
<li>Knowledge of Java Code Coverage Tools: Jacoco, Sonar, or Clover</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. You will contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. 
You will create groundbreaking technology for large-scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  You will also work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science, or Information Systems or 8 + years equivalent experience in an engineering role.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Knowledge of Apache Mesos, Hadoop, and Zookeeper
Experience using Docker
</p>
</div></body></html>
