<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113019760"> Product Design, Audio Products PD EPM</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113019760</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Audio Products Team is looking for a Product Design Engineering Project Manager to drive the design, development and validation of high quality Apple Audio Products. In this highly cross functional role the EPM will coordinate efforts across acoustic, mechanical, hardware and industrial design teams. Our EPMs are fearless organizers who work with highly skilled engineers to prioritize issues, identify and resolve potential risks to the schedule and quality of the product all while keeping in touch with the big picture. A successful EPM must be savvy enough to understand the roles and responsibilities of the key partners and identify stakeholders to drive key decisions efficiently.

This is a highly technical role requiring a solid ME or Mechanics background to understand technical details of cross-functional issues which will enable you to set the proper priorities and put risk mitigation plans in place.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>2 - 4+ years of related experience in project management (consumer electronics experience a plus)</li>
<li>Excellent written/oral communication, organization, presentation and leadership skills</li>
<li>Ability to comprehend, communicate and manage complex design tradeoffs</li>
<li>Self-motivated and proactive with demonstrated creative and critical thinking capabilities </li>
<li>Knowledge of product development and manufacturing processes</li>
<li>Understands and deals well with rapid development cycles; remains flexible and calm in the face of ambiguity</li>
<li>Ability to travel internationally to support builds</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Develop and manage hardware development project schedules with engineering teams and communicate project status to a wide spectrum of individual contributors to executive management
Support system definition and drive closure of architecture and technical opens in the early stages of a project
Identify risks, develop mitigation strategies and facilitate conflict resolution
Understand technical issues and drive them to closure by bringing together key stakeholders for decision making
Collaborate and facilitate communication across engineering managers, operations manager, marketing managers and our OEM partners to meet very aggressive cost, schedule, and quality goals
Interface between vendors and product engineering teams, setting and managing schedules and milestones
Synthesize large amounts of data into a clear story and communicate to stakeholders and organizations at all levels</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS ME degree or equivalent</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">One or more of the following a plus
Experience driving international OEM/ODM partners
Understanding of high volume production and test processes
A passion for audio and acoustics
Knowledge of mandarin</p>
</div></body></html>
