<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113132194">iTunes Disbursements Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113132194</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 16, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, one of the most influential technology leaders in the industry. Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact, where you will share in a commitment to excellence by partnering with world-class teammates, all with one unified vision—creating innovative products that delight customers. Finance is about “fueling innovation.” We do this by hiring quality individuals with integrity and personal accountability, who value teamwork, work product excellence and proactive thinking. If you share these values and want to be part of something big, contact us today.

We are seeking an experienced manager to lead the iTunes Disbursements team in Austin, TX. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience with disbursement, treasury and global banking processes  </li>
<li>Proven success in management by analyzing operational metrics and driving performance improvement</li>
<li>A track record demonstrating strategic thought leadership, innovation, and effectiveness at partnering with others</li>
<li>Strong communication, analytical, and time management skills</li>
<li>Highly proficient with computer systems, including spreadsheets, databases, and accounts payable systems</li>
<li>High level knowledge of GAAP, Sox, general ledger, finance and accounting processes  </li>
<li>Experience with payment screening solutions</li>
<li>Experience with SAP preferred</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Lead a team that ensures royalties are paid timely for content sold on the iTunes Store, iBooks Store and App Store
• Coordinate with multiple functions within the purchase to pay organization, the Treasury team and other iTunes business partners across the company
• Responsible for executing processes and driving global improvements</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Bachelor’s degree minimum in Business, Accounting, or Finance</p>
</div></body></html>
