<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-70900835">QA Analyst, Maps</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 70900835</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The QA Analyst will be a part of the Maps Data Review Team. This role is responsible for the GIS production data quality evaluation, comparative data analysis and trends analysis. Requires to collaborate closely with the data production, product and engineering teams. 

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3-5 years of experience in GIS field</li>
<li>Spacial data research &amp; analysis with the focus on basemap data</li>
<li>Familiar with geodatabase software (ArcGIS, QGIS)</li>
<li>Basic scripting skills (Python, UNIX)</li>
<li>QA experience is a plus but not required </li>
<li>Keen eye for detail, tenacity and drive to process large amounts of data, to see the trends emerge</li>
<li>Critical thinker with the ability to solve problems independently, demonstrate innovative approach</li>
<li>Proficiency with GIS tools, experience with GIS data digitization is a plus</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills, ability to summarize findings and provide recommendations for product specification and training improvement </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Executes data quality evaluation, documents findings and reports results of the area assigned.
Creates a summary of key drivers of rejected data, comments on trends, provides recommendations on specification training and clarification, based on observations.
Able to provide feedback and defend a QA decision to the production team. 
Demonstrates a deep domain knowledge, versatile in all Map data layers, and is a go-to expert on product specifications.
Participates in testing Quality Processes and Tools before deployment. Recommends improvements to automated testing based on findings. 


</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or equivalent, preferably in GIS or Geography</p>
</div></body></html>
