<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-46702013">App Store Engineering, Senior Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 46702013</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">App Store Engineering R&amp;D team is looking for talented software engineers to build and update App platform. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish. We are looking for a self-motivated, energetic individual with excellent communication skills who is willing to question assumptions, take end to end ownership of features and drive them to completion. The candidate should have experience developing large-scale server-side systems using object-oriented languages.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ideally 5+ years experience in designing, implementing and supporting highly scalable backend systems and web services.</li>
<li>In-depth Java programming experience.</li>
<li>Cassandra, Elasticsearch or Solr</li>
<li>Deep understanding of HTTP and REST APIs.</li>
<li>Experience with NoSQL &amp; big data technologies like Cassandra, ElasticSearch/Solr, Kafka, Hadoop</li>
<li>Multi-threaded programming</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Ability to thrive in a cross-functional team on high profile, critical projects</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Ability to work in a fast-paced dynamic environment 
Analyze, design, code, inspect, debug, and test features for the data platform.
Maintain and enhance existing applications in response to new feature requests.
Collaborate closely with members of other teams throughout the release cycle.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science, Mathematics, or EE, or relevant industry experience is required. MS in Computer Science or related technical field is desired.</p>
</div></body></html>
