<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57251243">Full Stack Developer - Technology Investigation</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57251243</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Technology Investigation team develops and ships core computer vision &amp; machine learning algorithms to production, driving revolutionary future Apple devices.  The Full Stack Developer role will be helping with rapid prototyping and helping build the tool and platforms for the data/visualization needs of the research algorithms.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Comfortable creating and using web based REST APIs</li>
<li>Expertise in Web development using Django (or other MVC frameworks), JavaScript/jQuery, CSS ,front-end JS Frameworks and HTML</li>
<li>Comfortable in working with document stores (MongoDB, CouchDB) and relational databases (MySQL, PostgreSQL),</li>
<li>Full-stack design experience</li>
<li>Comfortable working with Git</li>
<li>Values developing comprehensive unit tests </li>
<li>Knowledge of basic classical computer vision a big plus</li>
<li>Experience with large scale software projects - source code control, continuous integration, documentation</li>
<li>Work with a cross functional algorithm’s team to understand dataset requirements</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Technology Investigation team is looking for talented engineers who are passionate about creating products for millions of customers around the world. You’ll be working on cutting-edge technology and develop algorithms that enable a high-quality user experience across a range of tentpole use cases and applications. As a part of Technology Investigation team, you will closely collaborate with HW engineers (cameras, silicon, electrical engineering, product design) and other Technology Investigation software teams (computer graphics, video engineering, data generation/annotation, drivers/OS). You can make a difference by researching and prototyping novel algorithms beyond the state of the art and/or by optimizing the performance of real-time algorithms running on Apple silicon.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS in Computer Science or similar, alternatively a comparable industry career with a proven track record of successful projects.
</p>
</div></body></html>
