<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113141518">Senior Software Engineer (Quality Tools) - Technology Development Group</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113141518</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We're looking for a driven and dedicated lead quality software engineer for our ARKit team. As a member of our fast-paced group, you will have the unique and rewarding opportunity to contribute to upcoming products that will delight and inspire millions of Apple’s customers.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of experience developing automated quality evaluation software</li>
<li>Excellent C/C++ and Python programming skills</li>
<li>Excellent software design, problem solving and debugging skills</li>
<li>Experience in server, database and website administration on Unix-like systems</li>
<li>Excellent communication and teamwork skills</li>
<li>Basic computer vision, image processing, geometry and graphics skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Leverage your experience in order to help us deliver a next generation product. You will work in a cross-functional team which is developing innovative computer vision and machine learning algorithms. We research new and implement state of the art CV/ML algorithms, and you will play an important part in ensuring the quality of these groundbreaking technologies. 

Your job includes implementing automatic evaluation algorithms and visualizing evaluation results, administering server infrastructure for automatic evaluation, and implementing tools to collect and annotate data. You will provide technical leadership to engineers in the team and participate in planning and scoping of projects. You will collaborate closely with our Computer Vision R&amp;D engineers as well as our QA team to ensure that our algorithms meet highest quality standards.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master’s degree or higher in Computer Science or equivalent field, industry experience </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Objective-C, Swift, JavaScript programming skills  (preferred)
Familiarity with macOS, iOS operating systems (preferred)
Familiarity with Apache, CouchDB, CentOS, SSL, Open Directory, Pyramid Web Framework (preferred)
Familiarity with the CMake build system (preferred)
</p>
</div></body></html>
