<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113168092">RF/OTA Systems Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113168092</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The candidate should be able to work with Antenna designers and RF Engineers to verify that antennas is suitable for wireless portable devices with good radiation performance, including TRP, TIS, SAR, and EMC. Thus, the candidate should be extremely familiar with RF characteristics (at a system level) and requirements for modern wireless communication systems such as GSM/GPRS/EDGE, 802.11, Bluetooth etc. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Must have working experience of antenna design and tests, anechoic chambers, and RF test equipment. Hands-on is a must</li>
<li>Must have strong problem solving skills and strong working knowledge of radiation performance. Antenna and wave propagation theoretical background is essential. </li>
<li>Experience with different wireless communication systems such as GSM/GPRS/EDGE, 802.11, Bluetooth etc. including the corresponding system level specifications (e.g. ETSI 51.010, 51.05…) is essential.</li>
<li>Experience with regulatory requirements and process for wireless consumer devices, including FCC, PTCRB, CTIA, ETSI, TIA/EIA, etc. </li>
<li>Excellent communication skills required, both written &amp; verbal. </li>
<li>Detail oriented - taking data, using Excel, and making meaningful tables/graphs/averages.</li>
<li>Programming skills in C, C++ would be a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The candidate will be expected to create and execute detailed test plans for antenna passive and OTA performance, provide feedback to the design engineers for performance optimization, create test reports, and lead the radiated tests for type approval and certification. Also, the candidate will be required to create test plans to qualify and quantify different modulation schemes as required depending on the wireless communication system being designed.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Must have BSEE, MSEE preferred  </p>
</div></body></html>
