<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57478435">Financial Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57478435</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 16, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Retail Sales Finance group is looking for an analyst to develop, interpret and own the Accessories merchandising data and insights that drive our Apple Retail Accessories business. The Retail Finance Merchandising Analyst will interface directly with multiple worldwide internal teams, external vendors and senior management in order to create and drive metrics and reporting that adds to our vision of success.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Prior experience in Corporate Retail Analytics or Retail Finance environment required</li>
<li>Must be able to thrive in a fast-paced, challenging team-first environment</li>
<li>Must have experience that demonstrates understanding of the forecast process and the ability to deliver variance reporting and insight to the weekly worldwide forecast</li>
<li>Must demonstrate strong knowledge of retail practices, industry terms and key metrics</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will be an integral part of the WW Retail Sales Finance team. You will work hand in hand with our product and visual merchandising teams to deliver the right product in the right place at the right time to our enthusiastic retail customers. 
The analyst will be responsible for delivering key worldwide and geo level reporting and analysis. Specific responsibilities include:
Manage weekly merchandising reporting that is used by the entire product and visual merchandising teams
Develop new key metrics to increase the profitability of our accessory sales while helping to maintain the overall balance of product selection in our stores
Provide ad hoc analysis on all merchandising related items including pricing, margin, sales, space reporting, demo impact, visual merchandising decisions, etc
Challenge merchandising decisions while keeping the specific goals of the team in mind
Contribute to the weekly forecast process and variance reporting for all retail accessory revenue
Work closely with cross-functional teams to develop and produce reporting that measures and drives our merchandising objectives
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Finance or related field, MBA preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
