<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112932850">AppleCare Channel Operations Inventory Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112932850</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">AppleCare Channel Operations is looking for an Inventory Analyst to carry responsibilities for auditing and reconciling Apple owned channel inventory.  The AC Channel Operations team is committed to ensuring a first-in-class experience for AppleCare customers.

This role is located in Austin, Texas.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Significant experience with monitoring, auditing and remediation</li>
<li>Prior experience in inventory management or supply chain planning</li>
<li>Exceptional business communication and interpersonal skills, including the ability to interact effectively with individuals and groups at all levels of the organization</li>
<li>Skilled at engaging directly with external channel partners</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple tasks/projects simultaneously under minimal supervision</li>
<li>Strong attention to detail</li>
<li>Maintain a positive attitude in a high stress/fast paced work environment</li>
<li>Strong problem solving/analytical skills</li>
<li>Effective oral and written communication skills</li>
<li>SAP experience preferred</li>
<li>Proficient in Excel and/or Numbers</li>
<li>3-5 years of work experience</li>
<li>Must be a team player!</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsibilities include:

• Be a key member of an inventory audit and reconciliation team.
• Partner with materials, finance and field services to meet defined timelines.
• Provide data as required by management for periodic status reporting.
• Recognize and act on opportunities for automation, integration and process improvement.
• Operate with a high degree of initiative, creativity and leadership within division or department policy.
• Collaborate effectively with other departments at Apple and with our external channel partners.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• BA/BS degree required.</p>
</div></body></html>
