<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113203454">HANA Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113203454</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish. Would you like to work in a fast-paced environment where your technical abilities will be challenged on a day to day basis? 
If so, Apple's BI Engineering team is looking for highly motivated, detail oriented, technical savvy, energetic professionals who like to think outside the box and want to be part of one of the largest data processing and analytics team!
This role requires leading the design, development and deployment of data warehouse solutions for multiple business groups at Apple for Finance domain.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of experience in Data Warehouse/Business Intelligence space</li>
<li>Strong hands-on experience in Data warehouse development in SAP HANA</li>
<li>Experience in developing reporting solutions based on SAP data using SAP HANA</li>
<li>Have a good experience in core HANA data modeling </li>
<li>Have a good experience in HANA based data modeling</li>
<li>Performance tuning of data models and reports</li>
<li>Sharp troubleshooting skills to identify and fix issues quickly</li>
<li>Experience working on a Enterprise data warehouse environment </li>
<li>Data modeling experience in building Logical and Physical data model</li>
<li>Deploying solutions using version control management system</li>
<li>Experience in developing UI reporting solutions like Executive dashboards is a big plus</li>
<li>Leadership, critical thinking and excellent verbal and written communication skills</li>
<li>Strong problem-solving and analytical ability</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Key Responsibilities include: 

- Lead end to end solutions delivery of large scale reporting applications on EDW using on-site and off-shore resources
- Architect, Design and develop large scale and optimized Data Warehouses and BI solutions using SAP HANA
- Lead data modeling and database design &amp; development using HANA modeling techniques
- Lead Reporting and UI design and development using multiple industry standard reporting and dashboard tools
- Translate complex business requirements into scalable technical solutions meeting Data warehousing standards
- Provide subject matter expertise to support reporting needs for the multiple functional areas
- Conduct Design and code reviews
- Benchmark application performance periodically and fix performance issues</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS Degree in Computer Science or equivalent </p>
</div></body></html>
