<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112947738">Embedded Firmware/Software Engineering Program Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112947738</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking out a world-class Firmware/Software Program Manager to own and drive embedded FW/SW into all iPhones, iPads, Macs. We are searching for a candidate with a proven track record of planning and executing complex programs.  The ideal candidate will understand the who, what and how of system development, orchestrate a firmware/software development plan and schedule, then successfully manage execution of that plan. He/she will also need to collaborate with cross-functional teams, conduct and coordinate user studies and drive the analysis of resulting data.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of product development and/or project management experience</li>
<li>Understands and deals well with rapid development cycles; remains flexible and calm in the face of uncertainty</li>
<li>Excellent communication, organizational and leadership skills; ability to inspire team members</li>
<li>Self motivated and proactive with demonstrated creative and critical thinking capabilities</li>
<li>Well versed in agile project management models</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Technical knowledge of firmware and embedded systems, especially focused on consumer products.
Understanding of RTOS embedded system challenges
Support early definition and drive closure of architecture and technical opens.
Identify and highlight technical risk areas and mitigation strategies in partnership with Apple technologists.
Cross-functionally communicate the key developments and updates on projects.
Grasp complex technical topics and abstract key issues and risks into an actionable form.
Create schedule, identify critical path, and maintain throughout execution.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors or higher degree in Electrical Engineering/Computer Science or related technical field.</p>
</div></body></html>
