<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83847890">Content Planner</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83847890</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple Staffing, Training, &amp; Communications is responsible for training and enabling salespeople at Apple resellers globally, including mobile carriers, consumer electronics stores, and enterprise partners. Your work will be key in informing salespeople around the world about Apple products and helping them deliver a great customer experience.
We’re looking for a planner who can gather a broad range of inputs and business needs and synthesize them into a compelling, multimodal training and communications plan. You’ll also work closely with content creators to see the big picture, connect the dots, and imagine the possibilities.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Skills to work across a complex matrix of stakeholders</li>
<li>A track record of forming close partnerships with a variety of teams</li>
<li>Ability to translate business goals into actionable and measurable training and communications programs and communicate those results to leaders</li>
<li>Communications, training, and content-consumption expertise </li>
<li>Experience planning content across a variety of platforms</li>
<li>Strong storytelling skills and big-picture thinking</li>
<li>Superior presentation and written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Background in educational theory, instructional design, curriculum creation, or marketing a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Gather inputs on business needs and opportunities from global partners and business and marketing stakeholders, then synthesize inputs into a multimodal training and communications content plan
Form partnerships with other content development teams at Apple and with regional partners to find opportunities for collaboration and leverage
Effectively tell the story of the plan to partners and stakeholders to provide visibility and get buy-in
Use data to inform decisions about cadence, content types, content evolution, and more
Partner with the production lead to develop a resourcing and timeline plan to meet the content needs
Promote content to the audience, stakeholders, and regional publishing teams to ensure that it’s leveraged and consumed
Assess content leverage and trends, then work with regional partners to ensure clear communication and appropriate regional publishing and to identify issues and opportunities
Collaborate with content creators on the most effective ways to meet objectives</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree or equivalent work experience


Apple is an Equal Employment Opportunity Employer that is committed to inclusion and diversity. We also take affirmative action to offer employment and advancement opportunities to all applicants, including minorities, women, protected veterans, and individuals with disabilities.</p>
</div></body></html>
