<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83851191">iOS Frameworks Software Test Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83851191</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 14, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Be a part of the team that Designs, develops and debugs iOS apps to qualify new and cutting edge iOS technologies like HealthKit, HomeKit, Apple Pay, App Extensions in the next version of iOS!
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Objective-C, Swift or C/C++ programming skills</li>
<li>Ability to investigate and debug difficult problems</li>
<li>Experience developing with the iOS, tvOS, watchOS or macOS SDK is considered a plus</li>
<li>Experience with SDK/API testing is considered a plus</li>
<li>Automation and tools development considered a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The OS Program is looking for a software engineer with strong development skills. Our team’s focus is to ensure the iOS, tvOS and watchOS SDKs work as expected for the thousands of developers who create apps for our platforms.

Responsibilities in this position will include:
•Develop and maintain a set of test apps for new and exiting APIs that are released in the public iOS, tvOS, and watchOS SDKs. This includes developing the initial app to support a new API/framework. Additionally, this may include the development of accompanying web services, tools and test data sets needed to ensure the features works end-to-end for developers and customers.
•Design and develop automated tests to facilitate the ongoing testing of new and existing APIs/frameworks.
•Collaborate with different teams across the company in order to ensure the quality of the APIs/frameworks meet Apple standards.

This position requires a self-motivated individual with strong technical, problem solving and communication skills, and the willingness to work in a fast paced environment.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.Sc. in Computer Science or equivalent degree/experience.
</p>
</div></body></html>
