<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113004213">AppleCare Materials Planner/Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113004213</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">AppleCare is looking for a detail oriented, motivated, self-driven individual with strong background in Service/Repair supply chain. This person will own the planning and execution of  iPhone products for AppleCare. He/she will act as a focal point in communication, and execution supply plan to meet AppleCare’s overall goals. A successful candidate will require strong analytical skills, collaborative and proactive attitude, ability to think broad and to be able to work with senior managers and planners. This position requires strong knowledge and experience in procurement, supply planning, vendor communication, with the ability to collaborate cross-functionally to achieve outstanding customer service in a fast-paced environment.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Self-motivated team player</li>
<li>Ability for multi-tasking in dynamic fast-pace environment</li>
<li>Multi-discipline background, proven expertise in analytics, supply chain modeling</li>
<li>Experience in Operations, Demand Planning, Supply Planning, Forecasting, Inventory Optimizations.</li>
<li>Strong work ethic and a high degree of flexibility</li>
<li>Excellent written and oral communication skills</li>
<li>Knowledge of manufacturing, warehouse, logistic is a plus</li>
<li>Master’s degree in related fields plus 5-7 years of related experiences, or higher degree with 3-5 years of experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Manage key KPIs (Fill rate and backlog) for enterprise account
Develop allocation planning and execution models and perform ad-hoc analysis
Drive strategic design and optimization through cost analysis, optimize, simulation and scenario analysis
Collect data and build data collection rules for validation, create end-to-end processes
Create various statistical and data mining analysis
Provides forecast update recommendations back to vendor to better align with actuals
Coordinate issue resolutions, application enhancement requests between business and warehouses
Report and present weekly/monthly results to management
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master’s degree in related fields, or higher degree </p>
</div></body></html>
