<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56813343">Senior Software Engineer, Server and Cloud Integration</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56813343</li>
<li title="Santa Clara (FMK), California, United States">Santa Clara (FMK), California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">FileMaker, Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Apple Inc., the leading standalone desktop database company, is searching for a Senior Software Engineer to design and implement major features of new products. FileMaker has an established product line and large customer base. We are advancing the existing technologies and developing new and exciting technologies and products.  This position is located in Santa Clara, CA.

This position designs and implements major features of new products in Server and Cloud integration technologies with the guidance of Product Marketing.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years experience developing software using C, C++ and Java.</li>
<li>5+ years database and application server development experience</li>
<li>Strong object oriented design techniques, and reusable component design</li>
<li>Knowledge of Server architecture, performance &amp; scalability</li>
<li>Hands on experience with REST, SOAP and integration technologies</li>
<li>Hands on experience with ODBC/JDBC technologies and should be strong in SQL</li>
<li>Should have a strong knowledge on any of the relational database</li>
<li>Good knowledge and hands on experience on Cloud  infrastructure (AWS or Azure is preferable)</li>
<li>Strong analysis, problem solving, and troubleshooting skills</li>
<li>Good verbal and written communications skills</li>
<li>Preferred Experience</li>
<li>Database &amp; Application Server development, software architecture</li>
<li>Multi-tiered Server architecture research and development</li>
<li>Node.js, J2EE technologies and tools</li>
<li>Prior knowledge on integration (data or function) between distributed applications </li>
<li>Security frameworks, authentication, authorization and Encryption</li>
<li>Scripting languages</li>
<li>Experience on NoSQL and data migration</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Design major features of new products in Server  and Cloud integration Technologies
Implement innovative features on time with excellent quality

Create functional specifications and designs
Implement major features of new products
Create unit tests for features
Work with QA to ensure the top quality of the feature</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science or equivalent. MSCS or Ph.D. is preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
