<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57251169">Computer Vision Data Engineer - Technology Investigation</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57251169</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 28, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Technology Investigation team develops and ships core computer vision &amp; machine learning algorithms to production, driving revolutionary future Apple devices. Machine learning &amp; deep learning algorithms require lot of positive and negative samples as ground truth for training and testing. The real-world data team helps provide annotated real world datasets for ground truth.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in working with GAN’s to generate realistic data</li>
<li>Experience in working with deep learning algorithms for segmentation tasks</li>
<li>Exhibit breadth and depth of knowledge in machine learning and deep learning</li>
<li>Comfortable reading and implementing research papers to experiment with datasets </li>
<li>Experience with data augmentation techniques for building a huge corpus of data</li>
<li>Work with a cross functional algorithm’s team to understand dataset requirements</li>
<li>Background working with big image datasets preferred</li>
<li>Proficiency in Python/Matlab </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Technology Investigation team  is looking for talented engineers who are passionate about for millions of customers around the world. You’ll be working on cutting-edge technology and develop algorithms that enable a high-quality user experience across a range of tentpole use cases and applications. As a part of technology investigation team, you will closely collaborate with HW engineers (cameras, silicon, electrical engineering, product design) and other technology investigation software teams (computer graphics, video engineering, data generation/annotation, drivers/OS). You can make a difference by researching and prototyping novel algorithms beyond the state of the art and/or by optimizing the performance of real-time algorithms running on Apple silicon.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS in Computer Science specializing in Computer vision / Machine learning or similar, alternatively a comparable industry career with a proven track record of successful projects.
</p>
</div></body></html>
