<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113008178">CAD Engineer - Regressions</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113008178</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible and cross-functional role as a senior member of our hardware CAD team, you will be responsible for developing best in class methodologies and flows for Apple silicon mobile products.
You will develop and support large-scale, multi-site automated regression system.  This system will automate a large number of front-end and back-end design automation flows for modern System-on-Chip design.  It will enable faster design turnaround cycles, better testing coverage and drive design quality.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Typically requires 5+ years of industry experience in CAD and chip design. </li>
<li>Experience developing front-end RTL design, physical design or design verification regression/build environments</li>
<li>Expert-level knowledge and experience with large-scale, multi-site compute farms and queuing systems (e.g. LSF, SunGrid, NC)</li>
<li>Efficient programming capabilities in any of the following: Perl, Python, TCL or Makefile.</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with revision control systems (e.g. CVS, SubVersion, Perforce, GIT) and data management</li>
<li>Experience with build management and continuous integration / continuous release system such as Jenkins, TeamCity, Bamboo, BitBucket is a big plus</li>
<li>Proficiency with Unix-based environments, shell scripting and automation</li>
<li>Excellent communications skills, customer interfacing is a big plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Architect, develop, maintain and enhance large scale automated regression system
Optimize the regression system for maximum throughput, efficient license utilization, compute farm usage, reliability and predictability of results
Interface with multiple design and CAD teams to seek opportunities for further automation and regression testing to drive Quality-of-Results (QoR) improvements and efficiency.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS or BS Degree in technical discipline.
</p>
</div></body></html>
