<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113119212">Senior Renewable Energy Project Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113119212</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Global Energy Team is seeking a Senior Renewable Energy Project Manager to support our commitment to supply renewable energy to all our data centers, corporate offices and Apple Retail Stores.  The primary task of this team is to zero out the carbon emissions from energy used by all Apple facilities worldwide.

We seek someone who can immediately contribute in a dynamic and fast-paced work environment.  The candidate will be expected to take an active role in helping scale-up Apple’s commitment to renewable energy.  This work is detail oriented.  The ability to establish processes, multi-task and deal with change and ambiguity is vital.  You will have opportunities to propose new initiatives, as well as report results achieved, directly to key stakeholders across the Company.

This position is based in Cupertino, California.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>8 to 10 years of experience</li>
<li>Commercial expertise taking new solar and wind projects from origination through funding to COD in markets across the United States, Europe and Asia, often employing innovative approaches in markets with undefined or restricted regulatory frameworks;</li>
<li>Expertise structuring project ownership and equity investment deal terms; </li>
<li>A sound understanding of domestic and international renewable energy markets; </li>
<li>Renewable energy finance experience with in-depth knowledge of financial modeling;</li>
<li>Ability to lead multi-disciplinary project teams, including the ability to plan, coordinate and execute multiple complex projects concurrently;</li>
<li>Ability to develop highly collaborative relationships with internal and external stakeholders including: procurement, legal, finance, engineering, regulatory, public relations and project team consultants; </li>
<li>Project management, construction management and real estate development experience;</li>
<li>Excellent leadership, interpersonal and communication skills;</li>
<li>A strong technical background to help drive and manage technical aspects underlying project deals; </li>
<li>Ability to think critically and to solve complex problems with minimal supervision. </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Specific duties lead or supported by this position include:
Work in California and other states to evaluate and implement direct purchase of renewable energy through equity investments or long-term off take agreements. 
Work in international markets, particular Asian markets and other emerging markets, to identify and develop innovative solutions to creating a robust renewable energy program. Typically, these are markets and jurisdictions where no clear path for accessing renewables currently exists. Tools to achieve this include a combination of equity investments, long-term off take agreements and new distributed generation models, as well as working to coordinate policy and regulatory reform to better allow direct access to local renewable markets.
Assist strategy development leading to an increase in Apple-created renewable energy generation and a reduction in Apple’s energy use carbon footprint.
Provide technical assessments of complex and innovative engineering designs supporting solar PV, wind, run-of-river hydro, and biogas fuel cell projects, as well as distributed generation systems, micro-grid systems and energy storage technologies. 
Evaluate various emerging technologies, and where appropriate structuring investments in new projects utilizing emerging technologies.
Coordinate technical, financial, legal and environmental due diligence activities supporting Apple’s decision to invest in or partner with outside entities to develop renewable energy projects. 
Lead preparation of project documents including: asset purchase agreements to secure the development rights to projects; engineering, procurement and construction (EPC) contracts to build projects; long-term off take agreements to secure power and/or environmental attributes; and the joint venture or special purpose vehicle agreements and related shareholder agreements needed for equity investment projects. 
Support preparation of the energy supply agreements that govern the tariff purchase and delivery of electricity to Apple facilities.
Develop presentation materials and communicating results to management. 
Travel to domestic and international Apple renewable energy project sites and properties as needed. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in engineering or equivalent is required. An advanced degree in engineering or business administration is preferred.</p>
</div></body></html>
