<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113176557">Java Developer (For high throughput platform)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113176557</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 2, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Build and maintain highly scalable, low-latency, distributed Enterprise platforms for business critical applications.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Java, Multi-threading, Oracle PL/SQL and JSON/XML technologies</li>
<li>Web Services via SOA methodologies</li>
<li>Enterprise messaging using EAI and JMS</li>
<li>Relational database: Oracle</li>
<li>Performance tuned Java application</li>
<li>Designed schemas, coded PL/SQL modules and tuned them for performance</li>
<li>Familiar with Oracle data replication schemes</li>
<li>Worked in a Unix environment and wrote scripts.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Build and maintain highly scalable, low-latency, distributed Enterprise platforms. Build and maintain WebServices based upon service-oriented architecture (SOA) methodologies and leverage enterprise messaging using Enterprise Application Integration/Java Message Ser-vice (EAI/JMS).  Design and build highly scalable, multi-threaded ap-plications in Java, No SQL and JSON/XML technologies. Design da-tabase schemas, design and code Data Manipulation Language (DML) queries, analyze query performance and tune java and database appli-cations. Write UNIX scripts. Assist team members by providing design specs, reviewing code and providing review comments. Evaluate prod-ucts including open-source modules and incorporate them into projects as needed. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science or equivalent and 6+ years of progressive, post-baccalaureate experience in the job offered or related occupation. </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Functional knowledge of “Available to Promise” transactional systems is a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
