<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53827631">Systems Software Engineer, Distributed Systems</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53827631</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 30, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Systems Software Engineer within the Platform Architecture distributed systems team will be responsible for designing and implementing software for a variety of scalable, reliable, and secure distributed computing systems for Apple’s internal engineering teams.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong systems programming skills</li>
<li>Strong understanding of concurrency, parallelism, and distributed systems</li>
<li>Deep knowledge of concurrency control, data structures, algorithms, distributed system architectures, and networking</li>
<li>Experience with measuring, analyzing, and optimizing performance</li>
<li>Comfortable with all aspects of software development from architecture to deployment and maintenance</li>
<li>Experience running a large-scale production system</li>
<li>Experience with virtualization, containerization, and system image management (Docker, KVM, LXC)</li>
<li>Familiarity with distributed storage systems (HDFS, Amazon S3)</li>
<li>Fluency in C/C++, Go (golang), Python, shell scripting</li>
<li>Experience with Raft, SaltStack, Zookeeper</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Design, implement, and debug core components of internal distributed computing services
Research and implement key technologies, architectures, and standards
Work with other engineering teams to ensure that services meet scalability, availability, security, and performance goals
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS degree in Computer Science or equivalent, MS or Ph.D. preferred.
</p>
</div></body></html>
