<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113163072">SW Development - MCAD Training &amp; Support</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113163072</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s mCAD group is looking for a training and support engineer with excellent interpersonal skills, CAD and Data Management training and support experience to work with the world’s most creative engineers and designers.
As a trainer/support engineer within the mCAD group, you will be tasked with supporting Apple’s NX and Teamcenter users in their daily work, assure that problems are properly captured and solutions are provided in a timely and efficient manner. You will work with mCAD subject matter experts (SMEs) and solution architect in developing new NX/Teamcenter Integration initiatives to support Apple’s Product Designers business needs and introducing solutions and technologies for implementation.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Technical or engineering degree (Mechanical preferred), or equivalent technical training with 5+ years of relevant professional experience</li>
<li>Solid working knowledge of NX and Teamcenter Unified</li>
<li>Working knowledge with NX integration or any other integration with Teamcenter is highly</li>
<li>desirable</li>
<li>Excellent communication and interpersonal skills</li>
<li>Able to work in a very dynamic environment</li>
<li>Familiarity with Mac products and OS is desirable</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Provide mCAD training and Application support for a variety of mCAD environment tools.
- Design and Develop content for assigned modules of training programs with complete ownership
of the modules ensuring high quality
- Perform test engineering responsibilities for mCAD feature releases 
Collaborate with the mCAD team and their customers to develop solutions
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Technical degree in Mechanical Engineering / Computer Science or related discipline</p>
</div></body></html>
