<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57652401">Business Manager, iPhone</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57652401</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for a dynamic, highly motivated WW Product Marketing Business Manager to support iPhone.  The Business Manager partners with various groups, manages extremely confidential information, has direct exposure to senior business leaders and is in a position to influence key strategic decisions at Apple. 

This person needs to have outstanding verbal and written communication skills and be able to integrate wide arrays of data/information sources, build complex forecast and financial models to drive actionable business insights.  We are looking for someone with strong analytical capabilities, superior financial / quantitative horsepower, and a deep interest in Apple’s products, business and strategy. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum 3-7 years of relevant work experience</li>
<li>Highly motivated, works well under pressure, organized, and proactive in leading projects from end-to-end</li>
<li>Ease with quantitative and financial analysis in a product context; able to work comfortably with incomplete information and dealing with ambiguity</li>
<li>Strong business acumen, high intellectual curiosity, and deep interest in Apple’s product, business and strategy</li>
<li>Outstanding verbal and written business communication skills</li>
<li>Sharp attention to detail with the ability to maintain the highest level of accuracy, yet understand the big picture</li>
<li>Strong team player</li>
<li>Forecasting experience a plus</li>
<li>Superior Excel &amp; modeling skills </li>
<li>Ability to retrieve, analyze, and manipulate large datasets; experience with Tableau, R, Alteryx, SQL, and/or Business Objects a strong plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This is an exciting opportunity that entails the following responsibilities:
Collaborate closely with Product Marketing, Customer Analytics, Research, Finance, Sales, and Operations to find optimal intersections of information relevant to drive business decisions
Formulate, architect, and build demand forecast &amp; financial models based on a wide range of information available
Integrate various datasets to create, present, and defend forecasts, scenarios, and other business insights to senior leadership
Challenge &amp; validate customer demand signals based on a fundamental understanding of the business and sharp critical thinking
Build and maintain tools, presentations &amp; reports to highlight relevant insights and track their evolution
Work closely with the WWPM Finance and Pricing teams, and handle special projects and requests
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in Finance, Engineering, or other quantitative field
MBA; concentration in Finance is desirable</p>
</div></body></html>
