<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113118264">Thermal Management Tools and Analysis Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113118264</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for a talented and motivated Thermal Management Tools and Analysis Engineer to be a member of the team architecting our thermal control systems.  As a member of this group, you would create and own the software tools which enable a small group of individuals to apply their expertise to almost every product Apple designs.  You would also use these tools to run parameterized experiments in the lab, analyze, summarize and present the results. You would accomplish this by automating repetitive data collection tasks, automating the processing of collected data and maintaining user tools for data archive access.  This role requires a full spectrum of skills, and needs someone who can implement the right solution to any problem which comes along.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Documentation tools - LaTeX, XSLT </li>
<li>Network databases</li>
<li>Familiarity with relationships and tradeoffs between power, performance and thermal response</li>
<li>Object-oriented programming and design skills</li>
<li>Development experience with MacOS or iOS system frameworks</li>
<li>Development experience with architecting, coding or maintaining large software solutions</li>
<li>Experience with hardware bring-up, debug and analysis</li>
<li>2-3 years development experience with a combination of the following:</li>
<li>- High level languages - C, C++ or Objective-C</li>
<li>- Scripting languages - Bash, Perl, Python or PHP preferred</li>
<li>- Matlab</li>
<li>- Embedded micro-controllers</li>
<li>- Self-motivated, detail-oriented, excellent problem solving ability and critical thinking</li>
<li>- Excellent communication skills, both oral and written</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Understand parameterized test requirements and execute the tests
Analyze and present results
Maintaining and improving the following:
- a common environment for thermal data collection
- a database for automated archiving of data and meta-data
- applications for data retrieval, visualization and analysis
- device-specific scripting of thermal test sequences for various MacOS and iOS prototypes
Participating in engineering design discussions related to thermal and power control</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS ME/EE/CE or equivalent
</p>
</div></body></html>
