<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113033259">Sr Model Maker</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113033259</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">This position will utilize state of the art CAD/CAM and NX software, hardware and machine tools to create professional quality representations of Apple’s Industrial and Mechanical Product Designs.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>6+ years experience with 3-5 axis Computer Numerical Control programming skills to facilitate the manufacture of complex geometry utilizing vertical machining centers in a rapid prototyping environment.</li>
<li>Create Computer Aided Designs of holding fixtures to orient and restrain free-formed surfaced parts during manufacturing.</li>
<li>Create an intelligent process plan utilizing best practices that will yield a predictable end result very efficiently. Includes mentoring junior shop personnel and providing advice when necessary.</li>
<li>Interrogate complex Computer Aided Design geometry and provide feedback to the design teams on issues regarding potential production tooling issues or problems with the 3D database.</li>
<li>Acts independently to determine methods and procedures on new assignments.</li>
<li>Often acts as facilitator and team leader.</li>
<li>Journeyman level machine operation and setup in a very low volume/fast turn prototyping environment.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">These models are used to present new conceptual designs to the executive management team and validate our mechanical designs prior to committing to production tooling.
In this position you will provide support to the design teams to validate last minute design changes prior to production ramp or to restore production line down situations as soon as possible.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">2 year degree in Machining or Manufacturing preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
