<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112991989">Acoustic Integration Engineer - Audio Products</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112991989</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Audio Technologies team is looking for an Acoustic Integration Engineer who will be responsible for supporting Apple’s Audio Products portfolio.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have at least a Bachelor’s degree in Acoustics and some hands on experience in the headphone or loudspeaker industry. (e.g. – internships or work experience)  The following skills are required:</li>
<li>Strong understanding of acoustic fundamentals </li>
<li>Experience conducting acoustic measurements of headphones and earphones</li>
<li>Familiar with modern transducer and headphone architectures</li>
<li>Fluent in Matlab, Soundcheck and Solidworks</li>
<li>Strong troubleshooting, acoustic testing and data analysis skills</li>
<li>Strong individual contributor, motivated with a positive attitude</li>
<li>Effective communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">
As an Integration Engineer based in Cupertino, you will have responsibilities spanning all aspects of acoustic HW design:
Acoustic design responsibilities for new products concepts and prototypes
        Transducer specification/integration into product enclosures 
Working with cross functional teams and suppliers to deliver high quality results
Support development build activities at contract manufacturers as needed
Support broader acoustic team through prototyping, measurement and user studies
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS Acoustics or related field </p>
</div></body></html>
