<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83760731">Siri Senior Search Engineer, Internationalization</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83760731</li>
<li title="SF - Corporate, California, United States">SF - Corporate, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in revolutionizing how people use their computers and mobile devices. Create groundbreaking technology for algorithmic search, machine learning, natural language processing, and artificial intelligence. And work with the teams creating the most scalable big-data systems in existence. Join the Siri Search team at Apple.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience manipulating big-data</li>
<li>Applied background in Hadoop preferred</li>
<li>Applied background in Python, Java or Go language required </li>
<li>Experience with NLP and machine learning preferably with non-English content</li>
<li>Experience with search indexing, web crawling, ranking preferred</li>
<li>Fluency and experience working with text in one or more of the following languages: Japanese, Portuguese (Portuguese or Brazilian), Malay, Finnish, Thai, French, German, Spanish, Dutch, Korean, Hebrew, Arabic</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Siri Search team is looking for software engineers who will play a central role in improving the quality of data and results ranking for international users of Siri Search in various languages and parts of the world. Team members will: Perform data mining to support new search features; Evaluate search results and identify indexing, ranking and relevance problems; Scope, Design and Implement solutions to problems specific to international and non-English-speaking users; Implement systems for normalizing across scripts and input methods; Present results of analysis to team and leadership across Apple.

The role involves working with content in one or more of the following languages: Japanese, Portuguese (Portuguese or Brazilian), Malay, Finnish, Thai, French, German, Spanish, Dutch, Korean, Hebrew, Arabic.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Information Science, Linguistics </p>
</div></body></html>
