<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-78798065">Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 78798065</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>A successful track-record or demonstrated aptitude as a backend internet services software developer.</li>
<li>Experience or demonstrated aptitude for building, launching and operating very large-scale production internet services.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are designing, building, and supporting new, critical infrastructural systems and frameworks which provide and support services like structured and unstructured storage, caching, queueing, searching, and much more.  These form the platform upon which many iCloud and other backend systems at Apple are built.

Our team is responsible for the next generation platform that will power Apple’s infrastructural services. These services have huge scale and store hundreds of petabytes of data. The platform will support a variety of services based on open-source software, such as Apache Cassandra, SOLR, Zookeeper, Kafka, Redis, etc.
We are looking for a strong, self-driven developer to join as a member of this group.  This person will have a tremendous amount of individual responsibility and influence over the direction the backend of many critical Apple internet services take for years to come.   The ideal candidate is someone with ideas and passion for software delivered as a service to maximize reuse, efficiency, and simplicity.   This engineer’s work will impact hundreds of millions of users and be critical to the success of some of the most visible current and future Apple features.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in Computer Science or equivalent work experience.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">N/A</p>
</div></body></html>
