<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113132181">Payroll Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113132181</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, one of the most influential technology leaders in the industry. Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact, where you will share in a commitment to excellence by partnering with world-class teammates, all with one unified vision - creating innovative products that delight customers. Finance is about “fueling innovation”. We do this by hiring quality individuals with integrity and personal accountability, who value teamwork, work product excellence and proactive thinking. If you share these values and want to be part of something big, contact us today. 

The Payroll Team is seeking an experienced Payroll Analyst to provide timely, accurate, and comprehensive payment for the US, Canada and Mexico. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Overall understanding of payroll and post payroll process flows from the point of data capture through gross to net calculation </li>
<li>Processing and analyzing complex payments, non-cash fringe benefits/awards and related gross up, garnishments, tax withholding calculations and calculating workups for overpayments and retroactive pay</li>
<li>Experience developing and/or redesigning processes to maximize efficiency and effectiveness</li>
<li>Motivated self-starter who works well individually and in teams</li>
<li>Strong communication (written &amp; verbal) and interpersonal skills</li>
<li>Good organizational and planning skills with strong attention to detail</li>
<li>Proficiency with spreadsheet, process mapping, and word processing tools</li>
<li>Ability to identify key stakeholders and successfully influence without authority</li>
<li>Previous experience working with an integrated systems environment, such as SAP and ADP required</li>
<li>Experience with ADP Global View preferred</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Provides high quality customer service to both internal and external groups
• Analyzes and explains all components of Payroll
• Integrates and prepares payroll data from incoming documents relating to Compensation, HR, Benefits and Taxation
• Ensures all documentation is properly authorized and supported according to company policies, procedures, regulatory practices and legal requirements
• Performs reconciliations and detailed audits to ensure accurate processing
• Solves day-to-day operational problems of varied scope and complexity
• Assists other payroll analysts when needed</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Qualifications are generally met by someone who has a technical Bachelor’s degree</p>
</div></body></html>
