<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-49570600">Test Technician </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 49570600</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will have the opportunity to utilize your broad skills as a test technician, and apply them to next generation battery development for Apple products, pushing the limits of battery innovation. Responsibilities include following test procedures and ensuring the collection of quality data and results.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Typically requires at least 2+ years of test experience. Must have a previous track record of success conducting tests, be able to process and summarize data.</li>
<li>Experience with battery cycle life testing and equipment using Maccor, Arbin, etc.</li>
<li>Must possess a high level of attention to detail with handling of samples and test data.</li>
<li>Possess experience with electrical and mechanical lab measurement equipment (measurement gauges, volt and impedance meters, as well as automated test equipment, etc).</li>
<li>High degree of comfort in a lab setting, bringing a proactive attitude with a willingness to take ownership and drive results.</li>
<li>Experience with test implementation on wafer processing / capital equipment, medical device or test &amp; measurement equipment is considered a plus.</li>
<li>Experience with data analysis and s/w tools is preferred. </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Execution of testing following detailed test procedures, preparing and documenting test results.
• Running of complex test setups using high accuracy test equipment.
• Be capable of troubleshooting equipment and sample issues, maintain and troubleshooting test equipment as needed.
• Use various types of measurement equipment to test batteries and cells.
• Handling and providing sample materials with cross-functional team members. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">AS or BS Degree, or equivalent relevant work experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
