<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-58084674"> Full Stack Developer-3D Vision</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 58084674</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The 3D Vision team at Apple is looking for talented engineers who are passionate about creating world-class 3D content for millions of customers around the world. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Demonstrated experience designing and maintaining large scale </li>
<li>Expertise with at least one major language suited to web programming (such as Python, Ruby, Node, Java, Scala, or JavaScript)</li>
<li>Familiarity with at least one web application framework (such as Rails, Django, Flask, or Play)</li>
<li>Experience in modern web development using JavaScript, HTML5, and libraries such as Bootstrap, Angular, JQuery, or D3.</li>
<li>Strong understanding of data modeling and storage with NoSQL and relational DBs such as MongoDB, Postgres.</li>
<li>Fluent in OS X and *NIX command line environment.</li>
<li>Experience with Big Data processing</li>
<li>Experience with Spatial Data</li>
<li>Solid understanding of performance testing, improvement techniques and caching solutions.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for a full stack developer to work on the Flyover data processing pipeline. The ideal candidate will be a versatile and talented programmer who has experience developing exceptional software and system architecture. The position includes a broad set of tasks within data processing, spatial processing and web tools. The ideal candidate is an excellent communicator and has the ability to swiftly turn specification into finished software.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor or Master of Science degree in Computer Science or similar, alternatively a comparable long and productive coding career.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Meriting experience includes:
3D geometry
Computer graphics
Geometry processing
Image processing
Applied math
Data structures &amp; algorithms</p>
</div></body></html>
