<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113167115">MacOS/iOS Engineer - Video Applications (Cloud)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113167115</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Video Applications group develops leading media creation apps including Final Cut Pro X, iMovie, Motion, and Clips. The team is looking for a talented software engineer to help design and develop future features for these applications. The ideal candidate has a broad understanding of Cocoa API’s and in-depth experience integrating CloudKit and Core Data technologies into client applications.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years of software development experience</li>
<li>Strong Objective-C/Swift and Cocoa programming experience</li>
<li>Experience leveraging CloudKit and Core Data technologies in client applications</li>
<li>Well-versed in relational database concepts, data modeling, and web standards/protocols </li>
<li>Strong understanding of real-time, multi-threaded, object-oriented programming concepts</li>
<li>Passion for writing clean, well factored, and highly reliable code</li>
<li>Familiarity with audio and video editing applications a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This is an exciting opportunity to apply your experience in Cocoa application development to innovative media creation products that reach millions of users. The ideal candidate will have in-depth experience leveraging both Core Data and CloudKit technologies to efficiently store and synchronize data locally and in the cloud. As such the candidate should be fluent with Core Data &amp; CloudKit APIs, be able to design efficient managed object models and schemas, and be knowledgeable in best practices when working with these technologies. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor of Sciences degree in Computer Science or related field.</p>
</div></body></html>
