<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112979652">Software Developer (Network &amp; Data Center) </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112979652</li>
<li title="Sacramento, California, United States">Sacramento, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">A fast paced internal Software Development team is looking for an outstanding backend development engineer to design and implement features in applications that enable Network and DataCenter operation teams to work more efficiently. 

Joining this team will mean you will be working  on the key technology which support the major Apple applications, with all the scaleability and high-availability requirements that entails. 

(Note senior engineer positions also open in the same area)</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>1 to 2 years of development experience, preferably Network Management - Java/Go, Swift helpful. New graduates with Network Knowledge will be considered</li>
<li>Sprint Boot experience with Kafka, MongoDB in Spring Test. </li>
<li>Apache Storm or similar distributed realtime streaming computing platforms</li>
<li>REST API design and development experience. </li>
<li>Aware of the interplay between JavaScript and HTML and CSS, with the ability to quickly modify UI pages and queries. </li>
<li>Network Management protocol experience helpful - SNMP, NetConfig. Especially related to SDN Controller implementation</li>
<li>Ability to express ideas clearly within the team and across other groups.</li>
<li>Comfortable with Git source version control software, and test automation frameworks</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In addition to using expert technical knowledge to drive features and improvements, you must be comfortable with rapidly-evolving designs and requirements, and have excellent interpersonal skills. 
Success frequently depends on working with other teams, such as Network and DataCenter Operations. You must have a sense of customer-focused solutions that "just work," and must keep this in mind at every step of development. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Degree in computer science or related field, or equivalent work experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
