<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112924646">Analog IP Lab Characterization Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112924646</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will perform lab characterization and validation of embedded circuits; and you will Interface with many disciplines to launch the world’s premiere mobile computing chips.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>You will be part of a small team responsible for: </li>
<li>Bench test, debug, and characterization of embedded on-chip circuits (PLLs, DLLs, clocks, memory interfaces, and I/Os)</li>
<li>In-system PI/SI measurements for correlating with simulation models</li>
<li>Debug compliance test failures of standard interfaces (USB, MIPI, DisplayPort)</li>
<li>Setup, debug, and maintain lab system test environment</li>
<li>Development of bench top characterization tests exercising on-chip circuits through a combination of FPGA, JTAG, and analog interfaces </li>
<li>Development and execution of scripts to automate tests, extract and store results, and generate reports using database and analysis tools</li>
<li>Preparation of reports related to characterization and debug </li>
<li>Interface with chip design teams, system HW and SW design teams, Test engineering, and Product Engineering</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">5 or more years experience in test development, debug, and reporting that includes: Device tests and script development, Python preferred. Use of electronic measurement equipment. Use of data analysis platforms and databases. Testing/characterizing PLLs, DLLs, SERDES, and memory interfaces. Testing/characterizing control loops for various voltage regulator topologies (LDOs, bucks, multi-phase bucks). Lab work including soldering/instrumenting systems for test or debug. Malabo/DSP experience is a plus. Other skills should include: Initiative taking ownership of responsibilities, being productive, ability to meet aggressive deadlines. Strong written and verbal communication skills. Emphasis on quality of work: should self-check scripts, test patterns, and reports.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE / MSEE is required</p>
</div></body></html>
