<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53599665">Product Analyst - Siri Analytics</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53599665</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Product Analyst on the Siri Analytics team, you will be an ambassador of analytics to product and engineering teams with the ultimate purpose of improving the Siri experience for Apple customers. You will focus on a particular product within Siri and will be responsible for defining metrics, communicating product performance, and investigating research questions related to your product. We’re looking for people with a proven track record dealing with large, complex data and distilling it into meaningful insights and concrete actions. Intellectual curiosity and ability to ask good questions is key to this. The mission of the Siri Analytics team is to drive improvement of Siri through analysis and measurement.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Proficiency with relational databases</li>
<li>Expert SQL skills</li>
<li>Mastery of Excel</li>
<li>Experience with data analysis or data mining methodologies </li>
<li>Self-motivated, curious and proactive, with demonstrated creative and critical thinking capabilities and an innate drive to improve how things work</li>
<li>Excellent communications and presentation skills</li>
<li>5-10 year of experience in an analytics role</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Leverage an analytics background while working collaboratively with data science and engineering teams to provide insights and data-driven recommendations for Siri. Be passionate about asking and answering questions in large datasets, and communicate with a wide audience of engineers, managers and executives. Be expert in analyzing large, complex, multi-dimensional datasets with a variety of tools. Drive fundamental improvements to user experience through analytics.

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree. Master’s degree or MBA preferred. </p>
</div></body></html>
