<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83877138">Xcode Design Tools Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83877138</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 11, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Xcode team provides the tools to develop software for Apple's leading iOS, macOS, tvOS and watchOS platforms. Because our tools are our products, we have the unique opportunity to improve our development environment daily as we build software for our users. The Design Tools team is seeking a creative and motivated engineer to plan and build the next generation of user interface design tools.

As a member of our team, you will develop Xcode's Interface Builder by enhancing our canvas, expanding our inspectors, and improving performance, and adding support for the latest AppKit, UIKit, and WatchKit features.

We're looking for a developer with great fundamentals. If you have a thorough understanding of computer science principals like data structures, operating systems, compilers, and object oriented design, we can help you become an expert of developer tools.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Established history of self-direction </li>
<li>Critical opinions about the way software is engineered</li>
<li>Strong software engineering fundamentals</li>
<li>Fixation on constantly improving the status quo</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We’re passionate about the intersection of design tools and system frameworks. If you are too, we’d like you to join us in building powerful tools that are deeply integrated with AppKit, UIKit, and WatchKit</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree or equivalent experience in Computer Science or a related field.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">If possible, provide a portfolio of your work.</p>
</div></body></html>
