<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113094786">PCB DFM and Supplier Quality Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113094786</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>have at least 10 years experience the printed circuit including hands-on process engineering experience</li>
<li>have a strong knowledge of industry specifications, especially IPC and JEDEC specifications </li>
<li>understand the relationship between manufacturing processes and printed circuit defect conditions, especially latent defects</li>
<li>understand statistical process and quality control principles and be capable to apply statistical analysis methods to raw data sets</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This responsibilities of this role include:

- maintenance of printed circuit board design guidelines for all Apple products
- maintenance of printed circuit board technology roadmap
- maintenance of printed circuit board acceptability specifications
- establishment and maintenance of supplier site/material/technology qualification matrix
- action as the directly responsible individual all printed circuit board related quality issues and excursions  

In the course of fulfilling these responsibilities the person in this role will:

- provide guidance to product designers on available printed circuit board technologies and materials
- interact with and guide PCB layout designers to select layer structures, design rule sets and practices
- work with design tool engineers to define and validate appropriate scripting, design rule checks, etc 
- support design for cost investigations as the bridge between engineering and procurement
- audit and assess PCB vendor production lines, including manufacturing techniques and quality control systems
- review new technology qualification data and make disposition decisions
- review new product introduction first article data and make disposition decisions
- drive corrective actions for PCB vendor issues using step by step methodology</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">A BS or higher in materials science or chemical, mechanical or electrical engineering is strongly desired</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">- have a current knowledge of industry design rules capabilities and practices for different types of products 
- be familiar with PCB design and simulation tools 
- be willing and able to travel overseas up to 25% of the time, including trips on very short notice as well as for extended stays</p>
</div></body></html>
