<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113000988">Location Software Engineer in Test </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113000988</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join our Location, Motion and Connectivity team and drive innovation that matters! Create and seamlessly integrate technologies that enrich people’s lives and deliver the absolute best user-experience. If you're passionate about building technology that will make a difference, this is the job for you.


</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Knowledge of object oriented languages: e.g. C, C++, Objective-C</li>
<li>Knowledge of scripting languages: e.g. Python, Perl, shell scripting</li>
<li>Knowledge of automated build &amp; test systems</li>
<li>OS X or UNIX experience</li>
<li>Thrive in a collaborative environment and can clearly communicate while confidently driving multiple projects across many teams</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Location Framework QA team undertakes special projects for the Location &amp; Motion groups at Apple. These projects have ranged from developing data crowdsourcing systems to prototyping apps &amp; features for future OS releases.  Our team also contributes heavily to continuous integration and test automation systems.  In this position you will work closely with hardware and software developers and will be among the first to receive unreleased prototypes. Strong programming skills are a required as many teams will rely on your software.


</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors, Masters, or equivalent degree in Computer Science or Electrical Engineering.


</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Familiarity with version control systems: e.g. git, subversion, cvs.  Experience with iOS, OS X development a plus.  Some of knowledge of SQL and distributed systems.

</p>
</div></body></html>
