<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113146921">Localization Project Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113146921</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for an experienced localization project manager to join the AppleCare Localization team on site in Cupertino, CA.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 3+ years experience in a localization project management role. </li>
<li>Proficient knowledge of Translation Management Systems, Translation Memories, Term Databases, etc.</li>
<li>Experience with SDL WorldServer is strongly preferred. </li>
<li>Fluency in a non-English language and / or translation experience is preferred.</li>
<li>Technically savvy, with knowledge of software / content development and QA methods. </li>
<li>High attention to detail, efficient time-management and strong organizational skills.</li>
<li>Thorough understanding of localization best practices, processes and tools.</li>
<li>Ability to operate in fast-flowing, technically slanted meetings with a wide cross-section of stakeholders. </li>
<li>Strong ability to solve problems and dive in to localization-related challenges, skillfully leveraging learnings from your past experiences. </li>
<li>Experience juggling a high workload of concurrent projects, challenging schedules and conflicting priorities. </li>
<li>Skilled at influencing and motivating others; particularly when it comes to bringing localization to the mainstream in our business partners’ project planning and development processes. </li>
<li>Ability to perform in a dynamic and versatile environment while adjusting to changing business requirements.  </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The day-to-day job requirements change as needed in order to support the fluctuating needs of our business partners. 

Some of the tasks you will perform daily: 

- Work together with our Senior Localization Project Manager to support the localization needs of our Field Services department. 
- Analyze requirements and obtain supporting reference material; clearly communicate same to localization vendors. 
- Create and / or process translation projects in WorldServer, assign to vendor and monitor through the workflow all the way through to on-time delivery. 
- Manage schedule challenges, query cycles, and Linguistic QA, to ensure successful delivery to our clients. 
- Collaborate with relevant stakeholders(within AppleCare, across Apple, and externally) to resolve questions or conflicts related to terminology, language quality, technology and workflow. 
- Continual involvement and partnership with client projects; injecting yourself in their general and project-specific meetings, understanding their processes, roadmaps and challenges as pertains to localization. All this for the purpose of  making localization a core part of their projects rather than an after-thought. 
-Identify and implement process improvements when and where necessary at any point in the content creation / localization workflow. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/BA or equivalent experience in an area related to Localization or Project Management is preferred 
</p>
</div></body></html>
