<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-44313208">Technology Interface Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 44313208</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 10, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will be at the center of custom silicon design efforts with focus on interface with foundry technology teams and internal design teams.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Candidate should have 5+ years of experience in semiconductor process R&amp;D and manufacturing. </li>
<li>Experience with process qualification and yield enhancement is desired.</li>
<li>Deep knowledge of CMOS advanced technologies, device physics and industry competitive landscape is required.</li>
<li>Design experience (analog &amp; digital) in advanced CMOS process is desired.</li>
<li>Ideal candidates will have prior experience and success delivering new designs to production under a very aggressive schedule.                                                                        People management skills and managerial experience is highly desired.</li>
<li>Good data analysis, problem solving, and communication skills required.</li>
<li>Self-motivated and schedule oriented is a big plus.                                                             </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Manage technical interface with external foundry partners.
- Manage foundry partners for the development of new advanced processes.
- Coordinate process qualification of new processes with external foundry.
- Participate in technology development, device engineering, and ongoing sustaining engineering activities within the Technology group.
- Drive thorough investigation of root cause, and solutions to process/yield issues and its impact on product design.
- Drive design methodology working with design teams, including DFM and DFY activities.
- Manage and mitigate technology risks for the project.
- Engage parties in decision making and drive to timely closure and thorough follow-through.
- Monitor and assess research progress in Semiconductor technology through publications and conferences.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE / MSEE is required, PhD preferred,</p>
</div></body></html>
