<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113180462">Program Manager, Headcount Analysis and Planning</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113180462</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Engineering Headcount Team is looking for a resourceful, energetic, self driven, motivated and innovative individual to track and manage Headcount plans across various groups. Preferred candidate will be expected to track details associated with requisitions and offers in a FileMaker database with precision. The position entails working closely with Engineering, Finance and Recruiting and addressing headcount issues and process with all levels of management and calls for excellent communication skills.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in managing, organizing and maintaining large quantities of data</li>
<li>Detail oriented accuracy</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills (written and verbal)</li>
<li>Advanced levels in MS Excel and FileMaker Pro.</li>
<li>Unparalleled multi tasking abilities</li>
<li>Top notch critical thinking skill set</li>
<li>Ability to respond accurately in a time sensitive environment.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Handle highly sensitive and confidential material with tact and skill.
Track requisitions and offers in the FileMaker database.
Oversee HC Database ETL (extract, transform, load) process.
Reconcile and report on weekly headcount data into the FM database.
Continuously improve HC database efficiency through scripting and schema changes.
Secure agreements from various groups on transfers of employees etc.
Communicate regularly with high level executives in R&amp;D and Finance with HC reporting and planning.
Project manage the growth and expansion of HC Dashboard (web tool) with a team of contract software developers.
Transform business objectives from a vision into an action plan.
Manage contractor tracking and perform bi-annual reviews for the SVP.
Other miscellaneous ad hoc issues.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS degree and 3+ years of industry experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
