<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-70916092">Sr. Electrical Systems Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 70916092</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 7, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Engineering Team is looking for is looking for an energetic, creative, and self driven Senior Electrical Systems Engineer working on future Display hardware technologies.  The candidate will work in a collaborative, exciting environment to integrate new technologies into Apple’s products.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>- System integration experience of embedded systems with electronics, firmware, and software</li>
<li>- FPGA/CPLD implementation and algorithm review experience</li>
<li>- Mixed signal EE design experience at either the PCB or IC level</li>
<li>- Select EE components, guide schematic &amp; PCB layout teams, and analyze prototype performance</li>
<li>- Signal timing diagrams and power on/off sequencing</li>
<li>- Power converter circuit design and analysis</li>
<li>- Experience with simulation tools such as Matlab, Cadence, SPICE, or Ansoft</li>
<li>- Hands on lab experience for data analysis and debugging </li>
<li>- Familiarity with software code review and modification</li>
<li>- Familiarity with design for manufacturing</li>
<li>- Scripting or Automation is a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Demonstrate creativity in problem solving, ability to think out-of-box, and adapt quickly to new technical areas
- Promote innovation and new technology to further enhance Apple's display performance and user experience
- Create and give presentations before and after prototyping new ideas
- Analyze the trade-offs between performance, manufacturability and cost
- Communicate and demonstrate prototypes to Cross-Functional Teams
- Work with Display EE component and panel vendors to solve electrical &amp; optical related issues 
- Write detailed EE Specifications for System, IC, PCB, and Software design</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS with 5+ years, or BS with 8+ years of relevant EE Design experience
</p>
</div></body></html>
