<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112951760">Audio System QA Engineer - Apple (Beats By Dre)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112951760</li>
<li title="Culver City, California, United States">Culver City, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for an Audio System QA Engineer who is passionate about testing audio products. You will be involved in designing, developing, maintaining, and extending test frameworks across a range of Beats/Apple wireless audio products</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>2+ years of testing/QA engineering experience (Preferably in audio consumer end products)</li>
<li>Experience with recording, analyzing and debugging audio issues objectively and subjectively (issues like distortion, pops/clicks and other audio artifacts)</li>
<li>Experience with audio analyzer tools like Audio Precision (APx500) and Audacity is a big plus</li>
<li>Understanding of Audio quality metrics like MOS and PEAQ is a big plus</li>
<li>Understanding of FR curves, bluetooth profiles, sampling rate, bit rate and Bluetooth audio codecs (AAC, AAC-ELD, SBC, mSBC, CVSD) is a big plus</li>
<li>Experience testing Bluetooth and/or WiFi audio products is a big plus</li>
<li>Experience writing test plans and execution of tests over the development life cycle of the product</li>
<li>Understanding of regression testing, sanity, functional, end to end testing, interoperability</li>
<li>Experience testing active noise cancellation on a product is a plus  </li>
<li>Experience with filing bugs using bug tracking tools like JIRA is a plus </li>
<li>Experience with tools like Bluetooth sniffers (Ellisys or Frontline) and/or WiFi sniffer (Omnipeek or Wireshark) is a plus</li>
<li>Familiarity with hardware and software interaction of embedded systems</li>
<li>Understanding of system block diagrams and system level testing</li>
<li>Basic understanding of SDLC (system).</li>
<li>Automation experience using Python is a plus</li>
<li>Proven ability to learn quickly and adapt to new technologies</li>
<li>Ability to efficiently communicate findings and ideas to team members</li>
<li>Ability to effectively contribute in a fast-paced, cross-functional environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Developing and executing system level test plans for all audio features on multiple projects

Evaluating existing test tools/setups for improvement and building new audio test setups/fixtures.

Reviewing existing test coverage and proactively identifying areas for improvement 

Developing tests for new audio features and executing audio test plans covering all audio features through out the development life cycle of the product 

Validating bug fixes and performing regression testing on new FW and HW builds.

Collecting, analyzing and presenting test data to cross-functional teams and business stakeholders

Providing constructive feedback for testability and suitable solutions relying on data to justify technical decisions</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Prefer a B.S. in Electrical Engineering, Computer Engineering, or Computer Science.</p>
</div></body></html>
