<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83876256">Sales Training Instructional Designer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83876256</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">At Apple we are committed to delivering a best in class experience in all aspects of our business - delivery of sales training is no exception. The training course content delivered to our Channel partners enables our customers to receive a first class sales and service experience at the point of sale. Our goal is to develop creative course materials with focused learning objectives that are highly interactive and demo driven. The courses would be strictly developed in line with Apple’s global training course guidelines.

This role will establish content standards, content and learning path development processes, and quality assurance processes for content developed  around Apple’s entire ecosystem and delivered by the U.S. Channel Training team.  The role will work collaboratively with the Worldwide Instructional Design Team. In addition, the role will work closely with the Integrated Customer Experience People Programs team, our Apple Channel Sales team, and the Training Delivery team. 

The target audiences include partner salespeople selling Apple products or services in our Carrier and Consumer partners, as well as Apple employees working in our headquarters.

The ideal candidate must be able to work under tight deadlines in a fast-paced, dynamic environment that demands quality, creativity, scalability, and consistency.  This position also requires solid training design skills that map to the quality demands of the modern adult learner with measurable results. This Instructional Designer will be expected to set creative standards for a blended approach to delivery, including ILT, VILT, eLearning, podcasts, interactive video, just-in-time learning, gamification, and assessment tools. 

This Instructional Designer position will be expected to work as a project manager leading a collaborative development process while working closely with Training and Sales Management, Training Program Managers, and the worldwide Instructional Design Team. The ideal candidate will be highly motivated with excellent interpersonal, written and verbal communication skills. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years training design experience creating innovative, blended learning Sales Training solutions , through both instructor-led and self-paced training delivered through a variety of methods including classroom, web, video, and mobile devices</li>
<li>5 + years of working in a professional training environment showing process management for the training development lifecycle, from initial design through delivery and implementation (ADDIE model)</li>
<li>5+ years project management with proven ability to manage multiple, complex projects simultaneously</li>
<li>5 + years experience working in a Training organization or delivering training</li>
<li>MA in training design, related discipline or equivalent work experience</li>
<li>Knowledge of or experience in Carrier/Consumer sales environments and of different consultative sales processes</li>
<li>Ability to facilitate collaborative, cross-functional decision-making processes</li>
<li>Strong verbal and written presentation skills and excellent interpersonal skills.</li>
<li>Ability to apply needs assessment processes to determine effectiveness of regional training</li>
<li>Exceptional ability to listen and build rapport with a wide range of cultures and personalities</li>
<li>Strong understanding and experience with the Apple Ecosystem (SME)</li>
<li>Strong understanding and experience with Keynote and other Apple software</li>
<li>Self-starter and proven ability to work independently</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Establish content standards, define content development processes, and QA processes in conjunction with Apple standards and the WW team, or independently where geo-specific tailoring makes sense
Develop regional specific training content in partnership with WW, Sales, PM and Training Delivery teams
Lead collaborative (training design) projects and facilitate agreement; work effectively as a team member and individually under own management
Assess course materials for revision and continuous improvement purposes
Continuously enhance and develop their own Training Design skills

KPIs
Delivering content that meets agreed upon standards on-time and within budget
Quality of relationships with local and worldwide stake holders
Taking initiative to understand content gaps and develop content to meet the needs of the business
Engage in open feedback reviews and survey analysis to determine the overall quality and gauge if objectives of the training were achieved
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MA in Training Design, related discipline or equivalent work experience</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience with AdobeConnect a plus 
Graphic design, multimedia, and web development experience
Training related data analysis skills



Apple is an Equal Employment Opportunity Employer that is committed to inclusion and diversity. We also take affirmative action to offer employment and advancement opportunities to all applicants, including minorities, women, protected veterans, and individuals with disabilities. 
</p>
</div></body></html>
