<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-51918827">Product Quality Reliability Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 51918827</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join the fast paced Product Quality Engineering team.  You will partner closely with the Engineering, Program Management and Operations teams to manage our ongoing reliability testing.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>- Working knowledge and theory of quality methods, design of experiments, statistical process control methods and predictive modeling</li>
<li>- Exceptional statistical knowledge to derive sampling plans and projected failure rates</li>
<li>- Technical systems knowledge related to electronics and mechanical assembly</li>
<li>- Reliability and quality sampling methodologies</li>
<li>- Data-driven and results-oriented approach to problem solving</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Ensure ongoing reliability test readiness for product from ramp through end of life
- Own and drive key metrics 
- Develop and implement processes to enhance quality, capacity and efficiency
- Provide regular VP level communication of program status
- Manage ongoing reliability test execution
- Manage quality escalations
- Statistical data analysis to provide risk assessments
- Conduct reviews of Field/Factory Quality Data
- Support and visit ongoing reliability test labs as required</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS degree in Engineering
5+ years of industry experience in manufacturing or development of electronics
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience working with high volume international manufacturers and traveling to manufacturing sites
Third party production quality &amp; process management experience 
Exceptional ability to build relationships
Clear &amp; consistent communication
Project management experience
Enthusiastic and motivated
Experience performing reliability testing including Mechanical Stress Tests, Shock/Drop/Vibration Testing, Environmental Testing
Excellent written and verbal communication skills in English
Ability to travel internationally 20%.</p>
</div></body></html>
