<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113144055">Buzz Squeak Rattle Engineer - Noise and Vibration</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113144055</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">I know my workday will be fast-paced and challenging and that my communication, creativity, and problem-solving skills will help improve products loved by millions of customers around the world. I have an opening on my team for someone who shares my passion for building amazing products. Are you interested?

Apple’s Noise &amp; Vibration Team designs, validates, and solves problems in our hardware products to minimize audible noise and optimize sound quality. We are a diverse team of experienced engineers, sensitive listeners, and creative problem solvers. We work daily with multi-functional teams to discover innovative solutions to very complex engineering challenges. We are searching for a N&amp;V Buzz/Squeak/Rattle (BSR) Engineer to join our team of dedicated and passionate engineers.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li> You have considerable knowledge of acoustics and vibration principles, with 5+ years of experience in the noise/vibration field; understanding of forced excitation, both transient and steady-state, and how motion of mechanical systems turns into radiated noise.</li>
<li>You have acoustic and vibration measurement skills, are fluent in data analysis methodology, and have experience making measurements in anechoic/hemi-anechoic chambers.</li>
<li>An accomplished listener with excellent hearing over the audible frequency range.</li>
<li>You're a creative problem solver who thrives in a fast-paced multi-tasking environment.</li>
<li>Familiar with Matlab or other flexible data analysis software in addition to traditional N&amp;V analysis software. </li>
<li>Have worked with statistics and statistical analysis methods.</li>
<li>Experienced in using precision-grade instrumentation for ultra low-noise measurements.</li>
<li>Have a history of developing high-volume consumer electronics.</li>
<li>You have knowledge in electro-magnetic actuators</li>
<li> </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will author SOPs, test plans, and specifications.
You'll craft sound quality metrics to describe buzzes, squeaks, and rattles (among others); facilitate user studies and subjective evaluations to establish acceptability thresholds and discover key attributes driving user perception of noise; and set sound quality targets in lab and manufacturing environments.
You will perform validation testing to these targets, analyzing data sets and communicating results to both technical and non-technical team members.
You'll use your findings from vibration and acoustic testing to discover the root cause of offensive noises.
On occasion, you will travel to our partner facilities overseas.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Most of our engineers have advanced degrees in Acoustics or equivalent field, but if you’ve followed a different path to expertise in acoustics, vibration, noise control, or sound quality, that’s fine too.
</p>
</div></body></html>
