<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55752115">Senior Devops Software Engineer - Crypto Services</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55752115</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are seeking a talented and motivated software engineer to be a part of our small and nimble team to take us to the next level in automation. You will be challenged to innovate while balancing both security and automation requirements.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>-- Minimum Qualifications:</li>
<li>10+ years hands-on experience in engineering, DevOps, or as a software engineering staff member</li>
<li>5+ years working with Puppet, Chef, and/or other DevOps automation tools</li>
<li>Unix GURU and proficient with at least one shell and high level scripting language (bash, python, ruby, etc.)</li>
<li>Passionate about Continuous Build, Integration, Test, and Delivery systems</li>
<li>Expertise with continuous delivery systems using Svn/Git and Jenkins</li>
<li>Strong understanding of both front-end and back-end web technologies (HTTP, AJAX, XML, JSON, CSS etc)</li>
<li>Familiar with a variety of front-end &amp; back-end build tools &amp; systems (Maven, Gradle, Grunt, npm, etc.)</li>
<li>Expertise with building system capacity models, logging and monitoring infrastructure (Splunk, graphite/grafana, etc.)</li>
<li>Expertise with troubleshooting complex OS, database, network configuration, and applications server issues</li>
<li>Understanding of packet sniffer tools such as Wireshark, tcpdump, etc</li>
<li>Ability to influence architecture and design decisions; thread pools, caching policies, memory allocations, connection pooling, performance tuning etc.</li>
<li>Ability to evangelize DevOps best practices and mentor other engineers</li>
<li>-- Preferred Qualifications:</li>
<li>5+ years working with load balancers and databases (Oracle, MySQL, Cassandra, Elasticsearch, MongoDB) </li>
<li>Java and object oriented design &amp; development experience</li>
<li>Knowledge of applied security concepts (authentication, authorization, protocols)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Re-engineer manual business processes by building software that automates and simplifies getting started with our services
- Enhance the development pipeline and team processes with modern technology (containerization, orchestration, reproducible builds) toward a goal of continuous deployment
- Build tools and platforms that provide strong visibility into high-volume services and enable intelligent responses to changing conditions
- Own, manage and enhance the development tools including source/artifact repositories (svn/git) and build pipeline (Jenkins)

As part of our small team of engineers, you will be involved in the full life cycle of many features targeted for Apple's encryption, signing and PKI services.</p>
</div></body></html>
