<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113075837">Technical Product Manager- Pricing </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113075837</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 29, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join the Business Operations Pricing team and play a leading role in evolving the worldwide pricing, rights, and availability system to support the rapid growth of App Store, Apple Music, Movies, TV, and iBooks.

Here is a glimpse of the types of projects you will work on…

Features and Expansion: 
You will work on new features that will impact hundreds of millions of customers around the world. New pricing features allow us to introduce innovative business models, provide our customers with exciting new types of content and make our products and services more accessible. Examples from the past few years include expanding the App Store to more countries around the world, launching the new subscriptions platform for developers, and launching the new Apple Music service.

Tax and Scalability: 
We currently operate in over 150 countries. Tax legislation is constantly changing and becoming increasingly complex. A focus of this role will be redesigning the pricing system and working with cross-functional teams to manage the tax requirements in a scalable manner.

This role is predominantly technical product management, and will be responsible for translating pricing-related ideas and strategies into tangible products and features. You will work closely with business, operations, legal, compliance, and finance teams to understand and refine requirements. You will then document and collaborate with engineers and QA teams to design, test, and launch new features
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience gathering functional requirements and preparing engineering and QA specifications</li>
<li>Experience in working with engineering and QA teams to develop and launch features</li>
<li>Background in SQL and relational database systems</li>
<li>Broad knowledge and experience in financial concepts (margins, break-even, fx rates, tax rates etc.)</li>
<li>Willingness to take initiative and troubleshoot pricing system issues and a solid track record of responding quickly and decisively to production issues</li>
<li>Advanced quantitative and analytical skills with strong Excel and Keynote skills</li>
<li>Experience working with senior management and executive team</li>
<li>Willingness to work in a hands-on, high volume, fast-paced, and changing environment</li>
<li>At least 5 – 7 years of relevant experience in product/program management, consulting, or engineering </li>
<li>Bachelors or Masters in an Engineering discipline, Management Science, Industrial Engineering, or Computer Science OR an MBA degree with engineering/quantitative background </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Types of projects: launching new pricing system features, redesigning the pricing system to accommodate changing tax environment in a scalable manner, developing internal tools and optimizing processes
•Author detailed functional requirements specification documents for pricing engineering and QA
•Review all pricing-related system implementations, including user acceptance testing
•Ensure pricing system supports compliance with corporate pricing policies and arrangements with content providers
•Work with Compliance team on ensuring sound design and effective operations of pricing-related controls
•Maintain pricing documentation, including details of the systems
•Assess whether price change requests can be supported by the system
•Roll out new pricing features, including developing training materials and coordinating training effort
•Help the team with the broad range of challenges that arise in day-do-day operations, including analysis and system configuration 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors or Masters in Electrical Engineering, Industrial Engineering, Management Science, or Computer Science OR an MBA degree with engineering/quantitative background </p>
</div></body></html>
