<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55212965">Engineering Project Specialist Module</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55212965</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Engineering Program Management Team is looking for a resourceful, energetic Engineering Project Specialist (EPS) to manage and assist with Configuration Management, Supply Chain Management, Vendor and Logistics Management, Procurement, and Budget Tracking. 

Preferred candidate is a strategic problem solver who can lead and work with cross-functional teams to manage changes, perform risk analysis, and execute mitigation to support the engineering development builds.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum 5 years of experience in NPI Procurement and project management</li>
<li>Experience with BOM (preferably hands on experience with hardware products and AGILE)</li>
<li>Data savvy in build planning and budget management</li>
<li>Quick leaner with ability to follow direction and adapt to changes in order to promote efficiency and productivity</li>
<li>Meticulous attention to detail</li>
<li>Effective and collaborative communication skills (written and verbal)</li>
<li>Proficient in MS Excel</li>
<li>Unparalleled multi tasking abilities</li>
<li>Working experiences with oversea vendors including NPI projects, purchasing, logistics and Clear To Build</li>
<li>Top-notch critical thinking and problem solving skill capabilities</li>
<li>Ability to react to re-sets and changes in a fast paced environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsibilities include:

Work closely with program managers, global commodity managers and finance team to manage development budgets
Communicate project status to vendor regarding PO/invoice, material requirement, and delivery schedule
Manage Clear To Build based on engineering build matrix
Ensure on time delivery of vendor components or finish goods, monitor and optimize logistic flows
Create Purchase Requisitions, maintain invoice tracking and Goods Receipts
Create and manage BOMs (Bill of Materials), part numbers, and release related technical documentation
Create, manage and process Engineering Change Orders, Manufacturer Change Orders and Deviations
Work on multiple projects simultaneously

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS degree.</p>
</div></body></html>
