<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112928099">Apple News iOS Analytics Intern</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112928099</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple News team is looking for an iOS developer with a passion for data analytics to build the next-generation analytics and experimentation platform for News.

Apple is currently seeking enthusiastic interns who can work full-time for a minimum of 12-weeks between Fall 2017 and Summer 2018.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Track record of shipping exceptional iOS software.</li>
<li>Deep understanding of Cocoa design patterns.</li>
<li>Experience writing multi-threaded, asynchronous code.</li>
<li>Proficiency in data science, including statistical analyses and A/B testing.</li>
<li>Experience designing, conducting, analyzing, and interpreting experiments.</li>
<li>Understanding of strategies for maintaining privacy of user data, such as differential privacy.</li>
<li>Prior experience with big data tools such as Hadoop is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In this position, you will work closely with a team of world-class iOS engineers and data scientists to take News’s analytics and experimentation platform to the next level. You will be responsible for instrumenting the News client and making sure that data makes it safely and anonymously to News’s servers. Critically, you will ensure that all data collection happens with the utmost respect for customer privacy.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor of Science in Computer Science or related engineering discipline.  Advanced degree highly desired.
</p>
</div></body></html>
