<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-58118026">Sensor System Development  Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 58118026</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here.  At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly.  Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong knowledge of software development in C</li>
<li>Experience with sensor components such as cameras, laser scanners and GPS/IMU positioning systems</li>
<li>Knowledge of computer vision, sensor fusion and image processing</li>
<li>Knowledge of electrical design fundamentals</li>
<li>Experience with Linux development environment</li>
<li>Creative, pragmatic, critical thinking and troubleshooting skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The 3D Vision team at Apple is looking for a talented engineer to work with sensor system design and processing of collected sensor data for aerial, ground and portable sensor platforms. The work is a unique combination of software development and hands-on hardware component integration, involving direct interaction with multiple other teams such as field operations, infrastructure, computer vision and machine learning. As a member of this fast-paced and result oriented team, you will participate in all phases of product development; product definition, design, implementation, debugging and testing.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master of Science in Computer Science, Electrical Engineering, Physics or equivalent.</p>
</div></body></html>
