<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-86025680">Automation Manager - Wireless Technologies Tools and Apps Team</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 86025680</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Wireless Automation team is looking for an experienced software engineering manager to lead the Tools and Apps team. Come help us build the next generation of automation tools. This team is responsible for creating iOS/macOS/watchOS/tvOS based tools for the Wireless Technologies organization. These tools are used both internally and by third parties to help Apple deliver the best experiences in a variety of wireless technologies such as: HomeKit, ApplePay, Bluetooth, WiFi, Cellular, and Location.  We are looking for an experienced Engineering Manager that has demonstrated ability in building teams, developing processes and building and maintaining automation solutions.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Three or more years of experience managing a software development team</li>
<li>Proficient with Objective-C and well versed in concepts such as CoreData, GCD, UIKit</li>
<li>Strong leadership skills to lead and motivate a team of engineers with various levels of experience</li>
<li>Able to communicate effectively with engineers, managers, executives, and third parties</li>
<li>Highly motivated and independent with a strong track record of accountability</li>
<li>Enjoys software design, technical challenges, and problem solving</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Manage a team of software engineers to deliver several critical automation solutions used by Apple and third parties to certify various wireless technologies
Drive multiple parallel projects and their respective timelines while ensuring Apple’s high level of quality across each project
Work cross functionally with project stakeholders to create clear roadmaps for products with rapidly changing requirements and goals
Regularly update senior management on progress and risks with an emphasis on being able to succinctly summarize complex issues 
Work cross functionally with various other technology and product teams to ensure alignment of objectives and timelines
Forecast and align with the automation needs of the organization based on product roadmaps
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in Computer Science or equivalent
</p>
</div></body></html>
