<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52245549">Siri DevOps/Build Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52245549</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 15, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Our team is looking for a talented DevOps engineer who is passionate about building systems and continuous delivery to deploy new Siri functionality to internal users and customers as soon as possible. You will play a key role in designing and building tools and systems that Siri, and other teams at Apple, will use to implement and monitor automated development pipelines.

Join the Siri team!</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience with Software Version Control systems: GIT, SVN, (GitHub knowledge or Administration is a plus) </li>
<li>Experience with languages including: Java and Python</li>
<li>Maintained or Architected large project builds using Gradle or Maven</li>
<li>Ability to administer build systems such as Artifactory, Jenkins, TeamCity Bamboo</li>
<li>A desire to write tools and applications to automate work rather then do everything by hand</li>
<li>Experience using configuration tools such as: Puppet, Chef, Salt, Docker </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. You will contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. You will create groundbreaking technology for large-scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  You will also work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking.  </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science or Information Systems or 5 + years equivalent experience in an engineering role.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">- Experience implementing Java server applications using tools such as: Jersey, Jetty, ZooKeeper, JDBC, JMS, JMX and cloud deployment tools 
- Linux system administration experience: ssh, monitoring processes, attaching storage, cleaning disk space, tailing logs, etc. 
- Experience using Docker or other container systems 
- Experience working with server clusters consisting of hundreds or thousands of machines using tools such as: AWS, OpenStack, Mesos etc.
</p>
</div></body></html>
