<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113057066">Record to Report Global Process Lead</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113057066</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 25, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, one of the most influential technology leader in the industry.  Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact on a company that is known for its impressive lineup of products, including iPhone, iPad, Mac, iTunes and Apple Watch.  At Apple, you can share in a commitment to excellence by partnering with world-class managers, all with one unified vision, to create innovative products that delight our customers.   Finance is about supporting that innovative culture, accomplished by hiring quality individuals with integrity, personal accountability, teamwork, commitment to excellence, and proactive thinking.  If you exemplify our values and want to be part of something big, contact us today.

We are seeking a Global Process Lead (GPL) to lead the reporting analytics for the Record to Report organization (R2R). This is a new position providing an excellent opportunity for the successful candidate to make a difference. The ideal candidate will have both technical expertise in data/report design and experience in R2R process areas.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Skilled user of Business Intelligence Tools: Business Objects, Advanced Excel (VBA, Macro), Tableau &amp; SQL.</li>
<li>Knowledge of Database development and database administration, including experience working with Teradata, Enterprise Data Warehouse etc</li>
<li>Ability to analyze and operate on large data sets.</li>
<li>Basic scripting language and data visualization experience</li>
<li>Can manipulate and condense large volumes of data into succinct and powerful visualizations (graphs, charts, diagrams, dashboards, pivot tables, etc) </li>
<li>History of driving process improvements, system automation and world class reporting </li>
<li>Experience with SAP preferred </li>
<li>Strong knowledge of GAAP, SOX and R2R accounting processes a major plus </li>
<li>Proven analytical skills with the ability to collect, organize, analyze, and disseminate significant amounts of information with attention to detail and accuracy</li>
<li>Ability to develop prototypes and mock ups</li>
<li>High attention to detail, organization, team-orientation and an ability to work under tight deadlines </li>
<li>Strong business acumen; ability to engage with all levels of the organization for process improvement and reporting</li>
<li>Ability to deal with ambiguity, work independently, be a self-starter</li>
<li>Very strong communication, presentation, and interpersonal skills</li>
<li>Five years of relevant experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Develop an R2R reporting roadmap which identifies and closes key reporting gaps for the organization
• Liaise with a central reporting development team highlighting key reporting deliverables
• Become the key analytical point person for the regional R2R teams for report requirements and design
• Develop, manage and deliver specific global R2R reporting and SLAs
• Work with other regional leads and SMEs to pursue answers to questions raised by data analysis
• Influence requirements for improvements to reporting tools (bug fixes / enhancement requests), with an eye for eliminating manual data extraction and processing
• Manage the relationship with key stakeholders and reporting teams to propose solutions, and facilitate prioritisation of work
• Work with GFSS Reporting &amp; Analytics team to ensure data sets are aligned with requirements
• Acquire data from primary or secondary data sources and maintain databases/data analysis systems
• Design and develop management and operational reports to meet business requirements
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Bachelor's degree in related field</p>
</div></body></html>
