<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83848940">AR Specialist - US &amp; Canada Resellers</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83848940</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact on a company that is known for its impressive lineup of products, including Mac, iPod, iPad, iPhone, Apple Watch and Apple Music. At Apple, you’ll share in a commitment to excellence by partnering with world-class managers, all with one unified vision-creating innovative products that delight customers. Finance is about “fueling innovation.” We do this by hiring quality individuals with integrity, personal accountability, teamwork, excellence, and proactive thinking. If you exemplify our values and want to be part of something big, contact us today. 

Apple is seeking an AR Specialist to manage relationships and AR efforts with resellers in the US and Canada.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>4-7 years of relevant AR experience preferred</li>
<li>SAP including FSCM module &amp; advanced Excel experience highly desirable</li>
<li>Substantial understanding of the accounts receivable function is required, with an ability to apply knowledge and skills to complete a wide range of tasks including reconciliation and post audit requests </li>
<li>Ability to perform detailed reconciliations/analysis to resolve outstanding issues promptly</li>
<li>Proven track record of meeting collections goals while maintaining positive relationships with customers &amp; internal business partners</li>
<li>Excellent verbal and written communication skills </li>
<li>Ability to communicate issues quickly and concisely to management</li>
<li>Ability to work in a fast-paced, deadline oriented environment</li>
<li>Experience in corporate collections &amp; reconciliations</li>
<li>Solid understanding of billing, logistical, sales &amp; sales support operations</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Respond to inquiries from customers, internal and external, via email and phone, and follow-up when necessary
• Ability to work cross functionally within the team and with other departments within Apple
• Resolve outstanding invoice and reconciliation issues on past due accounts
• Proactively manage portfolio by identifying potential issues before they roll past due, utilizing resources and tools available
• Responsible for reconciling accounts with large volume of transactions
• Manage accounts within credit limit, escalating internally and externally as needed
• Release orders based on credit availability and risk
• Maintain SAP by entering, updating, and retrieving data, as well as formatting and generating reports from SAP into Excel
• Prepare outstanding accounts statements and gather reference documentation to identify issues
• Provide administrative support in the collections process
• Consistently meet quarterly metrics on portfolio</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• BS/BA in Finance, Accounting or related field</p>
</div></body></html>
