<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113163078">Camera Test Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113163078</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is responsible for all research, design, development, test and qualification of camera hardware for Apple products. The team is looking for a Camera Test Engineer with responsibilities for the camera test technology development and production test implementation.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum 2+ years of relevant experience</li>
<li>Good fundamental EE skills</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of camera module operation</li>
<li>Good Matlab programming skills on digital image processing and data analysis</li>
<li>Experience with prototyping solutions, camera testing methodology and production-level testing environments</li>
<li>Familiar with CMOS image sensor and digital imaging pipeline and algorithm (AE, AWB, etc.)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Responsibilities:
Duties include developing production-ready test methodology and software (including image quality, electrical and optical testing) for camera system/module/component performance evaluation including CMOS sensor pixel, lens quality, actuator system, and illumination technologies.

The applicant should be familiar with megapixel CMOS image sensor technology, photographic lens selection and qualification, imager interfacing and tuning, implementation of camera systems in mobile products. He/she should also have a strong knowledge of image sensor operation and control, and be familiar with digital imaging pipeline and algorithms. In addition, the applicant needs to understand how to implement high precision and high-volume camera module test.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS Electrical Engineering, Computer Engineering, Color Science, Imaging Science, Physics, or equivalent</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">~25% travel to both Apple and suppliers' facilities will be required for testing development and production bring up.</p>
</div></body></html>
