<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52781584">Senior Automation QA Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52781584</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 17, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Technology Investigation team is looking for a Senior Automation Quality  Engineer to enhance our testing capabilities for new and exciting technologies. As a member of our fast-paced group, you will have the unique and rewarding opportunity to be part of and shape upcoming products that will delight and inspire millions of Apple’s customers every day. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Excellent knowledge of software development lifecycle, test methodologies and tools and, passion for quality processes.</li>
<li>Experience or demonstrated ability in working in an automated testing pipeline (integration + system + functional + use case validation) driven by a Continuous Integration framework.</li>
<li>Ability to define/design/develop/maintain test automation frameworks.</li>
<li>Experience with Continuous Integration tools (e.g. Jenkins).</li>
<li>Experience in C/C++/Obj-C and scripting languages (e.g. Python).</li>
<li>Strong organizational and communication skills.</li>
<li>5+ years of relevant experience.</li>
<li>Experience with macOS, iOS and Xcode.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, the Senior Automation QA Engineer will design and maintain automation frameworks used in the testing of  computer vision algorithms and  applications. This   involves close collaboration in a cross-functional team of Software Development &amp; QA engineers, architects, project managers and other Apple QA teams. Responsibilities include defining and implementing the automation framework, monitoring CI performance &amp; test results analysis, maintaining databases for test cases and test results, use case validation, evaluating and reporting current quality of existing technologies and new features, developing and maintaining test tools.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in CS/CE or equivalent experience is expected</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Demonstrated ability in increasing functional test coverage (UI, API).
Demonstrated ability in enhancing test frameworks (scalability, reliability).
Experience in test automation frameworks that involve HW &amp; SW subsystem.
</p>
</div></body></html>
