<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-48785862">SRAM Circuit Designer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 48785862</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, you will be working on high performance custom digital circuits and will work with the team to implement advanced circuit techniques to improve circuit performance, optimize dynamic/static power and support full bring up through productization. In this highly visible role, you will be at the heart of a processor design effort, interfacing with all disciplines, making a critical impact delivering products to market quickly.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 5+ years circuit design experience in the CPU environment.</li>
<li>Knowledge of high performance low power circuit design.</li>
<li>Experience developing caches/SRAM design for low voltage and low power operating conditions.</li>
<li>Knowledge of Verilog and/or VHDL, and experience with simulators and waveform debugging tools.</li>
<li>Knowledge of industry standards circuit and design tools.</li>
<li>Solid understanding of device physics and process.</li>
<li>Ability to conduct experiments during silicon debug, gather &amp; analyze data; and utilize scripting to support efficient handling of ATE data.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Responsibilities:
As a SRAM Circuit Designer for custom digital team, you will perform the following:
• Design and implement high performance low power custom digital circuits for SRAM design.
• Responsible for working with logic/architecture team to formulate design specifications. • Define architecture/topologies optimizing for power, timing, area and yield.
• Work with layout team to supervise the design.
• Perform backend and front-end verification.
• Write RTL, integrate into next level of architecture and validate.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE / MSEE is required.</p>
</div></body></html>
