<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-99729438">Sr. Financial Analyst - Operations Finance</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 99729438</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking a highly motivated Senior Financial Analyst to join the Operation Finance team.  The successful candidate will be responsible for:

(1) Maximizing profitability and recovery on returned and E&amp;O inventory
(2) regional finished goods inventory scrap/E&amp;O consolidation and analysis 
(3) business partnering with Operations, Sales, SDM, AppleCare, Regional Finance Managers and Logistics 
(4) ownership of the monthly forecast review
(5) participating in global cross-functional initiatives

This role is highly visible and requires strong communication, analytical, and decision making skills. 

The successful candidate is a proven analyst with enthusiasm to drive the business, who embraces change, offers new perspectives, and constantly looks for new and improved ways to achieve results.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 5 years experience in the field of financial analysis with demonstrated increasing responsibilities</li>
<li>Excellent analytical &amp; financial modeling background</li>
<li>Excellent verbal and written communication skills</li>
<li>Proven ability to perform to strict deadlines</li>
<li>High degree of proficiency with Excel and Keynote</li>
<li>Experience with SAP, GRID, Essbase, and Filemaker are a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">PRIMARY RESPONSIBILITIES

Refurbishment, Finished Goods Scrap/E&amp;O, Planning &amp; Analysis
Coordinate and review regional finance input including consolidation of information

Analyze the data using relevant key metrics in order to challenge, support and explain the business

Participate and drive results on WW initiatives

Drive standardization and best practices across regions

Business Partnering
Facilitate flow of information between the business partners
Perform financial analysis to support all lines of business including product-level margin analysis which is used for decision support

Monthly Forecast and Close Preparation
Prepare and present the Monthly Forecast Review package 
Support monthly management cost reporting
Support close activities including forecast to actuals and calculation of required accruals and reserves
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in accounting, finance or related field
</p>
</div></body></html>
