<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54030286">Advanced Algorithm Engineer-Color, 3D Vision</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54030286</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Mar. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here.  At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly.  Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.The algorithm engineer will work in a dynamic R&amp;D  oriented team developing and implementing methods for automatic enhancement, equalization and color balancing of very large scale imagery.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>To succeed within this role, you should have strong expertise and experience within the following areas:</li>
<li>Strong knowledge in C/C++</li>
<li>Data structures and algorithms</li>
<li>Image formation and color theory</li>
<li>Automatic white balance</li>
<li>Image processing</li>
<li>Image enhancement techniques</li>
<li>3D Geometry</li>
<li>Computer graphics</li>
<li>Performance optimization</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The 3D Vision team at Apple is looking for talented engineers who are passionate about creating world-class 3D content for millions of customers around the world. You’ll be working on cutting-edge technology as well as researching and developing new algorithms that enable high-quality production of massive 3D models for display on mobile devices. Responsibilities include developing new methods for image enhancement, automatic white balance, auto exposure and general image processing.

A background in photography and a general interest in the aesthetics of images and color is meriting.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline"> PhD or Master of Science degree in Computer Science or similar, alternatively a comparable industry career with a proven track record of successful project
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Meriting experience include: mesh processing, computational geometry, structure from motion, applied mathematics.</p>
</div></body></html>
