<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54600784">iOS Cellular Power Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54600784</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Feb. 10, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Do you have excellent understanding of cellular protocols? Do you enjoy solving challenging problems? Do you feel comfortable collaborating with many cross-functional teams? If this describes you, we would love to hear from you!
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Excellent understanding of one or more of cellular protocols (GSM, WCDMA, CDMA, LTE, etc.)</li>
<li>Excellent coding skills, preferably in C/C++/Objective C (or similar languages)</li>
<li>Excellent debugging skills in software and hardware to solve challenging problems</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills, both oral and written.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We're looking for a motivated engineer with excellent programming, problem solving and communication skills. In this role, you will working on power optimizations of cellular data path and develop logging infrastructure to model cellular energy on iOS device. You would also be responsible for using large data analytics to analyze cellular usage in the field to inform design decisions and identify power improvement opportunities. To be successful in this role, you must have a solid foundation in software design/architecture coupled with good understanding of cellular and network protocols.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S., M.S., or Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering, Computer Science, or equivalent</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Preferred skills and experience: • Experience with development on Mobile systems  • Experience working with many cross-functional teams • Good understanding of cellular protocol stack and networking concepts • Good understanding of operating system concepts</p>
</div></body></html>
