<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113192402">QA Automation Engineer - Global Pricing Systems</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113192402</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The iTunes Store is looking for a talented software QA automation engineer with a strong analytical background to test, develop, and maintain an automation framework for iTunes pricing systems. Candidates should be skilled in automation and gray box testing with a desire to understand the bigger picture. Ideal candidates should be highly motivated self-starters with strong problem solving skills, attention to detail, the ability to ask the right questions and communicate effectively across the organization, and be able to produce a multifaceted testing approach. The tester must be able to discuss and analyze specific features and code changes with developers and produce a refined approach based on incoming changes and previous verifiable functionality and have the ability to integrate into automation test suites.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Create &amp; maintain automated tests and framework</li>
<li>Test and debug new and existing back-end iTunes Store features utilizing SQL and command line log expertise</li>
<li>Analyze business requirements to create testing methodologies that ensure pricing logic adheres to requirements</li>
<li>Interact directly with developers to evaluate testing needs</li>
<li>Work cross-functionally with other teams to ensure projects deploy seamlessly</li>
<li>Become proficient in understanding "the bigger picture" and how different software engineering components are linked together</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Solid experience as a Tools Development QA Engineer, Test Automation Engineer, Software QA Engineer, or Software Engineer
Strong experience in expanding automation tests, defining test strategies, and improving frontend or backend test coverage
5+ years of experience in utilizing automated testing frameworks, in-house or open-sources
5+ years of experience in object oriented programming, for test development, such as Java
5+ years of experience coding in Ruby or Python
5+ years of experience in shell scripting
Strong understanding of databases and solid SQL programming.
Strong analytical and problem solving skills with a meticulous attention to detail
Detailed oriented with exceptional verbal and written skills
Team-player with experience working on cross-functional teams
Self starter, self-motivated, independent, and proactive</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS/MS in Computer Science, Math, Statistics, or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
