<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112924970">AppleCare Support Business Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112924970</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Exceptional analytic problem solving skills </li>
<li>Demonstrated experience with quantitative analysis</li>
<li>Experience working in positions of ambiguity and muddy data </li>
<li>Experience working with and realizing the limitations of small samples and comfort working with large volumes of data</li>
<li>Strong business acumen and the ability to translate data into actionable business insight</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Advanced presentation skills</li>
<li>Ability to be flexible and multitask in a highly dynamic environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The AppleCare Support Analyst is tasked with using data to gain insight to help improve efficiencies within the support business both saving Apple money and leading to a higher quality support experience for the customer. The position will evaluate processes and decisions that the business might undertake, and evaluate current processes to help run the business more in line with our desired result.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS/MBA in mathematics, economics, statistics, engineering, operations research, or related quantitative social science would be ideal. </p>
</div></body></html>
