<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56998038">iCloud Software Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56998038</li>
<li title="Seattle, Washington, United States">Seattle, Washington, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience designing, implementing and supporting highly scalable applications and web services</li>
<li>Experience with SQL and NoSQL database technologies</li>
<li>Multithreaded or event-driven programming</li>
<li>Excellent analytical and problem solving skills</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Ability to thrive in a cross-functional team on high profile, critical projects</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Consider joining a small team writing the software which forms the foundation for some of our most exciting iCloud products and services. We are looking for an extremely capable engineer who has a strong background in web services development, and who has built high-performance, scalable and extensible systems. In this highly visible position, the successful candidate will collaborate with cross-functional engineering teams to define and implement some of the core backend platform frameworks and systems that will power next generation Apple web services.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's or Master's degree in Computer Science or equivalent industry experience</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Preferred Experience:
Java, C, C++
NoSQL databases such as Cassandra, HBase
Linux
</p>
</div></body></html>
