<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56730436">Engineering Project Specialist (EPS) - H/W Technology</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56730436</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Engineering Program Management team is looking for a resourceful, energetic Engineering Project Specialist (EPS) who will be responsible for managing key areas of Hardware Technology programs with exposure to large cross-functional teams.  The preferred candidate is a fearless organizer who can simplify complex environments through efficient coordination of tools and methods.  Responsibilities include managing and improving the critical processes that enable seamless execution of our silicon projects.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Exceptional communication skills (written and verbal).</li>
<li>Experience managing, organizing, and maintaining large quantities of data.</li>
<li>Computer programming experience.</li>
<li>Comfortable with building web pages and automation.</li>
<li>Passion for getting things done quickly and efficiently.</li>
<li>Detail-oriented accuracy.</li>
<li>Creative and open-minded.</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal skills and ability to work with a cross-functional team.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Coordinate project specifications and closure of technical definitions
•Interact with engineering teams to collect and present data
•Drive reviews to ensure consistent high quality on a variety of topics
•Manage schedules and action items
•Organize complex systems in a simplified view
•Identify and track key metrics
•Maintain and improve existing data visualization tools
•Utilize scripting and automation for better efficiency
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•BA/BS degree or 3+ years of industry experience</p>
</div></body></html>
