<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113110538">Data Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113110538</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple IS&amp;T, Global Business Intelligence (GBI) is responsible for hosting enterprise data warehouse. GBI is looking for “data engineers" to develop and support big data solutions on a variety of platforms.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ability to understand data model, understanding business process that generates the data.</li>
<li>The experience should involve “working independently” solving “variety of business problems."</li>
<li>Good communication skills.</li>
<li>Deep knowledge and hands-on experience with SQL is an absolute must.</li>
<li>Experience on how to improve SQL performance.</li>
<li>Good working experience with Java, Python.</li>
<li>Experience on Hadoop platforms with good knowledge of Hive, Tez, Spark and Map Reduce is important. </li>
<li>Hands-on professional with 5+ years of experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Data engineers at GBI are required to understand the business process, the relationship between various data elements, aspects of ETL, and logic behind a business solution. Various engineering solutions need the understanding of Hadoop platform capabilities and limitations. The solutions to be developed are to be on Hive on Map-Reduce, Tez or Spark. Day to day work involves analyzing various data products for the functional change, performance improvement, solutions that includes changing data structures and restating the data.  The candidate is considered a right fit if the person can demonstrate a fair amount of appreciation for working independently, yet enabling all team members by paying attention to overall details driving the application, delivering quality product modules on time.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS CS/CE or equivalent. (Engineering degree in computer science preferred).</p>
</div></body></html>
