<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112860389">Apple Payments Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112860389</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Payments Analyst will provide reporting and analytics on Apple’s global credit card volumes and fees.  This role will gain a complete understanding of the complex credit and debit card rules, regulations and fee structures.  Working directly with Apple’s acquiring partners, as well as the payment networks,  such as Visa, MasterCard, American Express, China Union Pay, and Discover, the analyst will help improve Apple’s payment operations.  The role will also support the payment managers with iTunes, Online and Stores to advance payment methods and international expansion.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Must be able to act independently and be self-motivated</li>
<li>Exhibit the highest standards of accuracy and strong organizational skills</li>
<li>Proven analytical and problem solving skills with attention to details</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to build effective business partnerships</li>
<li>Intermediate to advanced experience with Excel, Business Objects and SAP</li>
<li>Experience with Tableau a plus</li>
<li>Excellent data and statistical analysis skills</li>
<li>Superb listening, verbal, and written communication skills (including presentations</li>
<li>Experience in the Payments Industry desired with 2-4 years of finance and reporting experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Perform reporting and analytics on Apple’s global card sales, transactions and fees 
Manage the data integrity of Business Objects file inputs, internal tables, and reporting output
Analyze trends and proactively identify opportunities to use reporting to better support business management and/or improve efficiency of tools
Develop ad hoc reporting upon request
Maintain and enhance management and operational reports based on business requirements
Perform complex analysis and advise management and our business partners on business decisions and negotiations
Manage third party reporting relationships
Work with Apple’s acquiring partners on reporting and fees
Use data analytics to assist in the exploration of new global payment initiatives and expansion
Assist in contract and fee negotiations with our vendors by providing data driven models
Partner with internal customer in Stores, Online and iTunes on quarterly business reviews and provide suggestions on process improvement and fee reductions
Become the subject matter expert on credit card industry rules and regulations and association fee structures
Effectively communicate with all levels of management on regulation changes and fee impacts

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s Degree or higher in Finance, Accounting, or relevant field</p>
</div></body></html>
