<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57498409">Software Engineer, iTunes Store Engineering</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57498409</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 3 years experience in a professional programming position with Java or similar languages.</li>
<li>In-depth knowledge of database systems and domain modeling techniques.</li>
<li>Understanding of dependency and maintenance systems such as Spring, Guice, Maven, and Git.</li>
<li>Have passion for technology, value life-long learning, and enjoy finding the right tool for the job.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">iTunes seeks a self starting, energetic individual who is not afraid to question assumptions, is passionate about technology, and is capable of mastering full-stack development.  Our team focuses on sophisticated tools and services that bridge the worlds of automation and human task management.  Excellent understanding of workflow and data modeling techniques, performance, and the balance between synchronous and asynchronous processing is a must.  The candidate should have several years experience developing large-scale web-based applications. Experience with business rule, expert system, or machine learning systems is a plus.  We're looking for an individual who likes a challenge, tackles problems with imaginative solutions, works well in collaborative teams, and can produce high quality software under tight deadline constraints.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSCS or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
