<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113180106">Commute Operations Manager, Commute Alternatives Program</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113180106</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The commute alternatives program’s (CAP) flagship program is a fleet of 120+ vehicles operating a variety of commute, last mile, intra-campus, and on demand services.  The operations manager primary duty is to ensure the vehicles are operated with the highest levels of safety, training and maintenance. Apple’s Cupertino shuttle operations span from Marin to Gilroy and Elk Grove to Santa Cruz, with over 100 stops and 300+ trips per day.  Operations manage is responsible for ensuring the on-time performance, safety and efficiency of this vast operation.  Position will Interact with local and regional transit agencies to ensure compliance and all activities are coordinated appropriately.  

Apple’s CAP aligns with broader recruitment, retention, sustainability, wellness and real estate priorities.  Apple’s CAP supports real estate goals by enabling densification of buildings, reducing demands on parking and reducing peak hour single-occupant vehicle trips.  Apple’s CAP supports the recruitment and retention of top tier talent by bridging the commute gap between dense urban settings and Cupertino.  Apple’s CAP encourages active commutes for all employees, which ensures employees arrive alert and recharged.  The benefits of the CAP are felt throughout the company on a daily basis.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3 to 10 years of experience in a safety or transportation operations role</li>
<li>Survey and data analysis experience, especially related to complex routing and scheduling</li>
<li>Coordination across multifunctional teams</li>
<li>Manage and prioritize multiple projects with a constant focus on deadlines</li>
<li>Excellent verbal and written skills, ability to multi task</li>
<li>Extensive knowledge of various vehicle types with a specialization in motor-coaches and alternative fuel vehicles</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Manage commute program portfolio of strategic transportation suppliers to the highest levels of safety,  compliance and on time performance
Collaborate with suppliers safety and account management to ensure staff of 120+ drivers understand the CAP is a public-facing representation of Apple and requires appropriate attention to detail and excellence
Develop holistic, and expansive, safety monitoring program for all commute operations that includes periodic auditing and 3rd party verification
Manage day-to-day operations, while optimizing vehicle schedules, routes, and stops throughout the system
Ensure legal compliance to federal transportation law, regional air quality law and site-level hazard analysis
Charter coordination and procurement for Cupertino events team, admins and meetings group
Administer, along with procurement, transportation supplier contracts, RFP’s, renewals, extensions
Primary customers are coach and shuttle riders, operations manager should have an intimate understanding of what their priorities and requirements are and shape system performance accordingly
Develop best practices for monitoring safety and operations of various contracts
Develop compliance monitoring documentation and maintain historical records
Develop and maintain technology solutions to improve programmatic efficiency and data collection
Overflow parking service operations
Other duties as assigned</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or equivalent degree
Transportation Safety Institute Certification (or equivalent)</p>
</div></body></html>
