<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54386884">Product Design Engineer - Soft Goods</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54386884</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jan. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">
Apple is looking for a highly motivated product design engineer to join the Soft Goods Product Design group. You will be part of a cross-functional design team responsible for conceiving, designing and producing exciting new products. You will work closely with many different groups, including Industrial Design, Hardware Engineering, Operations, Packaging, Safety, Thermal, EMC, and Software. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>•Strong 3D and 2D CAD skills (NX, Solidworks or ProE/Creo preferred)</li>
<li>•Experience in production part design utilizing a variety of engineering materials (metals, sheet metal, plastics)</li>
<li>•Strong engineering fundamentals (beam bending, free body diagrams, GD&amp;T, etc...)</li>
<li>•Strong presentation skills (Keynote or Powerpoint)</li>
<li>•Experience using spreadsheets to analyze engineering data</li>
<li>•Organized self starter </li>
<li>Preferred Experience:</li>
<li>•Knowledge of soft goods materials (synthetics, leather, adhesives)</li>
<li>•Knowledge of softgoods assembly process (cut and stitch and cut and stick</li>
<li>•Strong understanding of thermodynamics and heat transfer</li>
<li>•High volume mass production experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will be part of a team that takes products from concept to mass production.  This role will require travel to our global supply base.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•BS in Mechanical Engineering required, MS Preferred.</p>
</div></body></html>
