<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113155825">Senior Software Engineer, iTunes Editorial Engineering</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113155825</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 5 years experience in a professional programming position</li>
<li>Experience in building data pipelines and analysis tools using Java and Scala</li>
<li>Experience building complex workflow based applications</li>
<li>Knowledge of SQL language and relational database systems</li>
<li>Aptitude to independently learn new technologies.</li>
<li>Ability to build complex human workflows in a scalable fashion</li>
<li>Ability to design, develop and deploy large scale applications</li>
<li>Have a belief in automation and tooling as a critical part of the software lifecycle</li>
<li>Be able to drive a project from a simple idea to an implementation</li>
<li>Be a leader who possesses both strong programming skills and a creative, user-focused mindset</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">iTunes Editorial Infrastructure Team is looking for a Senior Software Engineer to provide new tools in order to support its fast paced growth. Join our exciting team that has been leading the online music industry by constantly developing innovative features since its launch in April 2003. We are looking for a self starting, energetic individual who is not afraid to question assumptions and who has excellent written and oral skills. The candidate should have experience. We look for good team players who are able to tackle problems under tight deadline constraints and deliver imaginative solutions.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSCS or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
