<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112954300">Big Data Architect</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112954300</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Are you the kind of person that  is motivated by the challenge of a dynamic, changing Technology space? Can you utilize and exploit progressive systems and processes to satisfy the most stringent needs of  Data computing Platform at Apple? Are you a good partner with your teammates; driven to execute, team and individual commitments that align with business vision?  Does the idea of a high visibility and high impact role in a large  complex organization excite you? Then, this role is for you.
 
Apple IS&amp;T is looking for a Big Data Architect, a passionate power contributor who will provide Data Store Technology vision, effective collaboration, facilitation and coaching skills to the application development teams and Data Engineering team members, supporting some of the most critical Business Functions at Apple. We run the Directory Services , which is the gateway to Apple’s business, Global Business Intelligence, that fuels apple’s business decisions, Apple Pay and Apple online store, to name a few of the critical applications. The incumbent will be responsible  for  contributing to the  key data architecture and persistence design input into the Technology Strategy and Roadmap for future solutions. On a daily basis this person will work with application development teams to provide guidance on projects associated with new solution introduction and/or solution enhancements. When required this role will research and recommend new technologies, techniques and patterns along with providing sample Data store Engine programming/standards and best practices for their usage.  
 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 8-12 years' experience in diverse data environments. Extensive Database and Data Analysis technology skills and experience. Requires substantial experience with the Hadoop ecosystem and other NoSQL  technologies. </li>
<li>Experience with MongoDB, Couchbase, Cassandra, Solr Cloud, Elasticsearch, Vertica, Kafka and Neo4J technologies is a plus</li>
<li>Experience in using statistical analytics and predictive modeling tools and collaborating with and supporting analysts and data scientists.</li>
<li>Expert level of understanding of Data Modeling, Data Access Design, Query execution internals across different technologies, Indexing techniques, Text and Image search, Recommendation Systems, is a plus.</li>
<li>Extensive experience in addressing both operational and near real time needs as well as in addressing more traditional longer-latency data needs</li>
<li>Expert level of understanding of Hadoop ecosystem components: Hive, Oozie, Spark, Alluxio, Tez, Kerberos,  their internal working, interactions, Debugging techniques, is a must. </li>
<li>Expert level knowledge of 2 of the following languages is desired; C++, Java, Go</li>
<li>Excellent written, verbal, and diagrammatic communication skills</li>
<li> </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Designing complex enterprise data solutions with comprehensive understanding of  Technology, Operational and Analytical Data Architecture, Security, Performance, Scalability, and Reliability.  
Performing a key management and thought leadership role in the areas of advanced data techniques, including data modeling, Data Solution design and implementation, data access, data integration, data visualization, text mining, data discovery and statistical methods.
Cloud enablement and Diagnostic automation to modernize the operational practice and scale our operational work force for all the mentioned technologies.
Interacting with application development, enterprise architecture, business intelligence, data science, technology services, and vendors on a regular basis
Keeping abreast of the technology advancements in the industry and look for opportunities to introduce newer technologies and solutions to apple,  when appropriate.
Contributing to predictive /analytical modeling architectures, modeling standards, reporting, and data analysis methodologies. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's degree in engineering, computer science or related field; Master's degree preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
