<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57445324">Natural Language Processing Data Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57445324</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 8, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Natural Language Processing Group is responsible for a wide range of text-driven technologies, including auto-correction, spellchecking, predictive typing, Chinese &amp; Japanese input, tokenization, tagging and other solutions that are at the intersection of machine learning and NLP. Our multi-faceted team delivers intelligent and highly performant technologies driven by natural language text data. We are looking for a passionate engineer to harness the potential of our big data to develop better machine learning models and user experiences on all Apple platforms.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Extensive experience in designing performant and scalable distributed systems with the Hadoop ecosystem</li>
<li>Proficiency in writing high performance/memory efficient code</li>
<li>Java, Python, and Linux fluency</li>
<li>5+ years experience in software development</li>
<li>Strong communication skills &amp; collaborative mindset</li>
<li>Experience in NLP, speech recognition or machine learning is a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Natural Language Processing group is looking for a data engineer to design scalable and performant distributed text processing pipelines. You will be a key member of a team that is responsible for delivering the natural language intelligence behind keyboard input on Apple’s platforms, and will work closely with software engineers and machine learning experts to extract insights from data. The ideal candidate will be technically proficient, passionate about distributed systems and technologies and self-motivated, and will have a strong focus on details and quality.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science or an equivalent field</p>
</div></body></html>
