<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112976832">Telemetry Reliability Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112976832</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Platform Telemetry team is looking for a software and systems engineer dedicated to reliability and scalability of big data services.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Expertise in managing and troubleshooting large, distributed systems and maintaining them as production services</li>
<li>Experience building or using automation software (e.g., Jenkins, Gatling, Rundeck, Puppet)</li>
<li>Experience administering data pipeline software (e.g., Apache Storm, Apache Spark, Apache Kafka, Apache Flume)</li>
<li>Experience with large-scale, column- or key-oriented data storage (e.g., Apache Hbase, Apache Cassandra)</li>
<li>Experience in developing with one or more applications programming languages (e.g., Java, Go)</li>
<li>Familiarity with time-series or event databases (e.g., OpenTSDB, InfluxDB, Graphite)</li>
<li>Familiarity with UNIX shell scripting language (e.g., Bash)</li>
<li>Familiarity with Linux-based operating systems</li>
<li>Independent, motivated, and self-driven</li>
<li>Strong written and verbal communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Telemetry Reliability Engineers wants to revolutionize the way we think about the analytics and monitoring services that support iCloud, iTunes, and many other at Apple.  They enjoy diving deep into challenges in high-scale production environments.  They design and implement architectures that deliver answers to some of our most critical questions.  The Engineers engage regularly with other teams across Apple to drive availability and scalability in the systems they run.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS in Computer Science or equivalent professional experience</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">N/A</p>
</div></body></html>
