<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57631489">Sensor Test - Validation Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57631489</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is responsible for all research, design, development, calibration, test, and qualification sensing devices for Apple products. This team is seeking for an exceptional HW Sensor and Image Sensor Production/Test Engineer with responsibilities for the evaluation, qualification, calibration, testing and benchmarking.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years experience</li>
<li>Good fundamental EE skills</li>
<li>Exceptional hardware/software problem solving skill</li>
<li>Strong communication skills, professional, self-motivated and takes ownership of work</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of Sensing Hardware / Optical / Mechanical Principal a plus</li>
<li>Familiarity with mechanical design a plus</li>
<li>Good SW development skills with proficiency in: C/C++ programing and various algorithm prototyping and development skill</li>
<li>Expertise on OpenCV, OpenCL, OpenGL also a plus</li>
<li>Board level firmware development experience preferred</li>
<li>Experience with prototyping the solutions, bench testing methodology and testing environments for image sensing hardware preferred</li>
<li>Familiarity with processing large sized test results (statistical analysis)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Responsibilities:
Developing/performing Lab and Mass Production (MP) intent type testing HW and SW for various sensing device characterization, calibration and test.
Authoring the test plan documentation
Design, and develop the software suite for evaluating, calibrating and testing hardware and image sensing modules for large volume MP
Design, develop and provide the test/calibration infrastructure for MP 
Performing large scale data analysis
Deliver executive level presentation</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS Electrical Engineering or equivalent</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Frequent travel to both Apple and suppliers' facilities will be required for production bring up.</p>
</div></body></html>
