<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-33362460">Sr. Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 33362460</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 17, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are seeking an energetic and self-driven senior level server-side software engineer who will play a central role in the delivery of secure scalable services.  As a member of our fast-paced group, you will have the unique and rewarding opportunity to shape upcoming products that will delight and inspire millions of Apple’s customers every day.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of industry experience</li>
<li>Advanced programming skills in Java, Python a plus</li>
<li>Strong experience building scalable backend services</li>
<li>Experience with cloud-based infrastructure and platform services</li>
<li>Proficiency with large scale data processing technologies such as Cassandra, Solr, and Kafka</li>
<li>Knowledge of common web services protocols (HTTPS/JSON/REST)</li>
<li>Experience building stable and scalable server-side systems using distributed processing algorithms</li>
<li>Experience with ETL, data warehousing environments</li>
<li>Experience building practical, secure systems for handling sensitive data</li>
<li>Experience with data science or machine learning tools like Spark a plus</li>
<li>Web frontend experience a plus</li>
<li>Aptitude to independently learn new technologies</li>
<li>Ability to express ideas clearly within the team and across departments</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In addition to using technical knowledge to drive features and improvements, you must be comfortable with rapidly evolving requirements, and have excellent interpersonal skills.  Success depends on working with cross-functional teams.
Responsibilities:  Designing, developing and deploying a scalable data pipeline. Designing and building stable and scalable production systems to support machine learning and data science. Turning these systems into a service offering for other teams.  Maintaining an intense focus on secure and polished software. Participate in the continual improvement of engineering tools and processes.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS degree in Computer Science or related field, or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
