<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113160763">Site Reliability Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113160763</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Come help us build the next generation cloud platform to support internet services across Apple. Our server engineering team develops and deploys software which forms the foundation for some of our most exciting services, including iCloud, Maps, iTunes, and more.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Understanding of distributed systems</li>
<li>Have a good grasp of Linux systems, networking and security</li>
<li>Have a thorough understanding of cloud based architectures</li>
<li>Working experience with Java is highly desired (or Python or other languages)</li>
<li>Experience with orchestration systems</li>
<li>Experience with REST API, databases and/or key-value systems</li>
<li>Experience in CI build tools such as Gradle and Jenkins a plus</li>
<li>Experience implementing and administering logging, telemetry and monitoring tools</li>
<li>Know how in maintaining and debugging systems in Java runtime environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">PIE Coordination SRE team provides reliable distributed coordination service for PIE services and other services at Apple. We are seeking an experienced Site Reliability Engineer to join a small, highly skilled team. The person should be able to build and deploy software, analyze logs and telemetry data for issues. Apply good software development methodology in writing automation code. While working experience with Java is highly desired, what is more important is the ability to quickly become proficient in any language, and solid grasp of the fundamentals of Unix systems, service-oriented architectures, and cloud services.
Provide on-call support for critical services.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in computer science or equivalent experience</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">N/A</p>
</div></body></html>
