<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113028785">Front End Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113028785</li>
<li title="Sacramento, California, United States">Sacramento, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 21, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As a member of the Network Services software development team, the Front End Engineer will get to build tools to organize, visualize, and analyze network related metrics and data from our global IP network deployment. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>2+ years of Javascript experience</li>
<li>Knowledge of modern JS frameworks (React, AngularJS, Backbone) or visualization tools (D3.js or others).</li>
<li>Competent JavaScript programmer who doesn’t need to rely on libraries to accomplish innovative interactions.</li>
<li>Understanding of all major browsers and the special considerations required for all various quirks. </li>
<li>Aware of the interplay between JavaScript and HTML &amp; CSS, and can dynamically create, modify, and style element on a page with ease. </li>
<li>Able to communicate technical issues with non-technical users.</li>
<li>Ability to multi-task and manage tasks with varying priorities.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Come help us build the next generation of network management and monitoring systems at Apple.  Our global networks support services like iTunes, iCloud, Siri, and Maps, as well as everything from Retail Store Genius bars to production lines around the world.  The software and systems you build will ensure that every packet makes its destination, and that network operations engineers can sleep at night.  We support both open source and home-grown technologies to provide everything from basic inventory collection to sophisticated event correlation and traffic analysis, to network configuration management. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Technical degree or equivalent industry experience.
</p>
</div></body></html>
