<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-99787698">Software Engineer (Java, Scala, backend development)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 99787698</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 27, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Worldwide Marketing Communications department (Marcom) is seeking an experienced and highly motivated Software Engineer with experience in back end web application development. This role is critical in the evolution of Apple’s brand by working with the team taking  <a class="bridgeLink" target="_blank" href="http://apple.com">apple.com</a> to the next phase of its evolution.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 5 years of professional software development experience and 5 with backend development teams working on complex development projects</li>
<li>In-depth knowledge and experience designing and developing complex, scalable web-based tools using Scala and / or Java</li>
<li>Demonstrated background developing innovative backend solutions for dynamic web sites - how they scale, how they work with other services, and how they may break</li>
<li>Dedicated problem-solver who can work in a fast paced environment where multiple releases are a fact of life</li>
<li>Ability to size technical efforts accurately</li>
<li>A focus on quality, with experience writing unit tests and collaborating with quality engineering to develop test plans</li>
<li>Experience collaborating with other team members in multiple teams diagnosing and debugging complex systems, and participating in investigating build, deployment and operational issues</li>
<li>Knowledge of Linux stack, and comfort with Bash commands</li>
<li>Experience with web application security and incorporating security into the software development lifecycle</li>
<li>Familiar with database architecture, scalability, performance, and tuning</li>
<li>In depth knowledge of source version control software (Subversion, Git)</li>
<li>Experience collaborating with other technical teams on DevOps responsibilities for application deployment, performance, monitoring, reliability and scalability</li>
<li>Preferred experience with Docker, configuration management systems such as Ansible, Mesos or similar grid computing technologies, CI build tools such as Jenkins, and logging and monitoring tools like Splunk</li>
<li>Willingness to take the initiative to solve problems</li>
<li>Proven capabilities to work under pressure and tight deadlines to solve critical issues</li>
<li>Able to work equally well with people in creative and technical positions</li>
<li>Strong oral and written communicator, with good interpersonal skills; able to forge trusting relationships within a diverse team and across organizations</li>
<li>In addition to a strong technical background, the ideal candidate must possess outstanding interpersonal skills. The position requires excellence in communication, both written and verbal, including the ability to work well with stakeholders from a wide range of backgrounds with varying levels of technical knowledge</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This role is critical in the evolution of Apple’s brand by working with the team taking  <a class="bridgeLink" target="_blank" href="http://apple.com">apple.com</a> to the next phase of its evolution.

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors Degree preferred, but not required.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">5+ years experience developing in Java, Scala experience preferred
Experience with of HTML5, JavaScript and CSS
Knowledge of SQL and database schema design</p>
</div></body></html>
