<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112888992">GDCS Senior Electrical Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112888992</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 10, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Do you have a passion for designing innovative data center solutions that run at a massive global scale? Are you able to collaborate and balance between a strategic vision and pragmatic deliveries across multiple projects? As a key member of our global data center team you will have an opportunity to design the most innovative and efficient data centers in the industry. This position will support our global data center growth by developing bases of design, overseeing multiple design teams, performing design reviews, specifying equipment and operational requirements and seeing our innovative designs come to life during commissioning and operation. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Detailed knowledge of electrical power systems and equipment from grid to chip</li>
<li>Experience with reliability and availability studies</li>
<li>Selective coordination and available fault current study experience</li>
<li>Knowledge of total cost of ownership evaluations</li>
<li>Fluent and effective communication skills</li>
<li>High voltage substation protection and design experience</li>
<li>Generator control and protection experience</li>
<li>Experience with low voltage EPMS and BMS systems</li>
<li>Power conversion equipment experience</li>
<li>Familiarity with fire alarm and low voltage systems</li>
<li>Ability to review and critique electrical system designs for availability, quality</li>
<li>control, constructability and cost</li>
<li>Ability to coach, mentor and develop junior engineers</li>
<li>Must be able to establish and maintain close working relationships with</li>
<li>management, colleagues, team members, internal and external stakeholders</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This individual must have the following skills:
• Solid knowledge of data center facilities and operation
• Ability to manage equipment upgrades and modifications in data center production environments
• Develop training programs and provide training and guidance to employees
• Effective project leadership abilities to plan, organize, and motivate others to achieve objectives within challenging timelines and situations of uncertainty
• Comfortable with metrics and reporting
• Strong familiarity with project management processes and methodology requirements
• Liaise with leaders and provide support and accurate information to multiple levels of management
• Excellent planning, analytical, organization and problem solving skills and the ability to work independently as well as part of a strong team
• Ability to gracefully adjust to meet changing circumstances such as reorganizations, reassignment of project priority, changes in strategic direction, and customer needs
• The successful candidate must be able to operate independently with conviction and drive teams to the right levels of quality in delivery under pressure
• The successful candidate will be able to handle ambiguity in problem definition, have a good handle on business value and have the initiative to shape problems and projects so that they deliver maximum impact</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Electrical Engineering Degree
• 10+ Years of experience as a power systems design engineer
• PE or EIT license preferred
• Large data center design and project management experience
• Proven ability to design large power, protection and control systems</p>
</div></body></html>
