<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57473567">Software Engineer, Platform Engineering</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57473567</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 16, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for an energetic Java engineer to develop the deployment and application management automation system used by various teams at Apple including the iTunes Store, iCloud, and Maps.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ideally 5+ years of application development experience</li>
<li>Proficient with Java, JSP, HTML</li>
<li>Demonstrable experience with J2EE technologies for Web Tier and Business Logic Tier</li>
<li>Should be comfortable working with Object Oriented programming techniques</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with Application/Web Servers such as Tomcat, JBoss, or Glassfish</li>
<li>Familiarity with JDBC, Java serialization API’s and JMS preferred</li>
<li>Familiarity with JavaScript and AJAX preferred</li>
<li>Comfortable working in Unix environments such as MacOS, Linux etc</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for an energetic Java engineer to develop the data center management tool used by various teams at Apple including the iTunes Store, iCloud, and Maps.  Work involves adding new features and new development to existing tools.

Job Responsibilities:
- Analyze, design, code, inspect, debug, and test new software solutions in the internal tools area with emphasis on Java/J2EE development.
- Maintain and enhance existing applications in response to new feature requests
- Assist in resolving customer problems
- Collaborate closely with members of other teams throughout the release cycle
- Occasional after hours support and troubleshooting</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or higher in a technical field (Computer Science, Electrical Engineering, Mathematics, etc.) or equivalent work experience.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">- Competency and motivation to tackle complex problems in a fast-paced environment without compromising the quality of the work
- Ability to multi-task and manage tasks with varying priorities
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills and high attention to detail
- Prior experience designing tools around build system concepts a plus</p>
</div></body></html>
