<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113191167">User Studies Operations Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113191167</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for a User Study Operations Engineer to coordinate, execute, and monitor human-centered studies that will inform the research, verification, and validation of various sensor technologies.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum 2+ years of operations or project management experience (or equivalent) preferred</li>
<li>Knowledge of engineering development lifecycle and ability to rapidly acquire familiarity with emergent technologies and software algorithms</li>
<li>Design high throughput study methods given stakeholder’s data needs</li>
<li>Ability to manage study processes to maximize productivity without sacrificing quality requirements</li>
<li>Ability to write technical documents including study instructions, operating procedures and training documents for study moderators</li>
<li>Effectively collaborate, communicate and influence cross-functional teams </li>
<li>Must possess strong problem-solving, critical thinking, and time management skills</li>
<li>Meticulous attention to detail, extremely organized and demonstrated sense of urgency</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple projects and priorities in a fast-paced, changing environment with minimal supervision</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The User Study Operations Engineer will work closely with product development teams in Human Interface Devices and Video Engineering.  

Role responsibilities:

Manage and communicate study definition, progress towards study goals with study stakeholders
Coordinate fearlessly with hardware, software, algorithm, and project management teams to identify and resolve potential risks to the schedule and data quality
Work closely with protocol designers to define study requirements and to optimize data collection at scale while promoting an excellent user study experience
Establish relationships with researchers and manage confidential information with discretion
Author documents (plans, manuals) that integrate cross-functional study requirements, screeners, consent forms, and any additional materials required for data collection
Oversee the planning, kick-off, ongoing logistics, and upgrading of study protocol and materials, with an eye to quickly identifying and resolving critical obstacles
Train study personnel on data collection modalities and best practices
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Degrees in Mechanical, Industrial, and/or Operation Management Engineering, or in social sciences or human research-related discipline is required.  Minimum 2+ years of experience in project management/operations or relevant experience is preferred. 
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Passionate about user experience and innovative technologies.</p>
</div></body></html>
