<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113184136">Global Finance Projects UAT Coordinator</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113184136</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 29, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, the most influential technology leader in the industry.  Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact on a company known for its impressive lineup of products, including Mac, iPod, iPhone, iPad, iTunes and Apple Watch.  At Apple, you can share in a commitment to excellence by partnering with world-class managers, all with one unified vision to create innovative products that delight our customers.  Finance is about supporting that innovative culture. We accomplish this by hiring quality individuals with integrity, personal accountability, teamwork, commitment to excellence, and proactive thinking. If you exemplify our values and want to be part of something big, contact us today.   

The Global Finance Projects team is looking for an energetic, innovative and highly organized person to support the User Acceptance Test (UAT) efforts for Finance system projects.  Because UAT is critical in establishing and validating the overall readiness of the business to adopt to system implementations, the testing you execute and support will be an integral part of Global Finance Projects (GFP).

This position is based in Austin, TX.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>2-5 years related industry experience in technical or system implementation user support, Quality Assurance or UAT efforts</li>
<li>Outstanding technical, organizational, interpersonal and English communication skills</li>
<li>Strong written English skills</li>
<li>A high level of independence as demonstrated through mature problem solving skills and delivery of high quality work</li>
<li>Strong customer service focus</li>
<li>Ability to interact with team members at all levels of the company</li>
<li>Comfort working within a global community</li>
<li>Flexibility to change course based on business needs and environmental conditions</li>
<li>Ability to function in a fast-paced environment and prioritize multiple projects under tight deadlines</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Consistently employ Global Finance Projects UAT support model and strategy
• Work with project managers to determine appropriate Level of UAT Support required for Global Finance Projects
• Follow roles and responsibilities based on Level of Support
• Determine best strategic approach for UATs
• Drive UAT Readiness in partnership with GFP Project Managers and IS&amp;T to confirm all resources are identified and prepared for testing (data, systems, testers, technical support)
• Lead project teams in scenario identification, script writing and test execution planning
• Lead project teams in UAT logistics determination (travel, timing, co-location)
• Monitor and report out on test progress and issue triage using Radar (issue tracker) and in house Dashboard tool
• Organize cross-functional partners to support UAT transaction needs
• Enforce consistent and scalable test plans across multiple projects
• Drive UATs to completion within specified timelines using data analysis and communication skills to uncover issues, determine ownership, identify solutions and mitigate risk</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Bachelor's degree in relevant field or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
