<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113164997">Client Engineer - Endpoint Data Backup</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113164997</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Client &amp; Collaboration Services department work to ensure Apple’s employees are productive, efficient and secure. As a member of the Client Engineering team, you’ll work with various parts of Apple’s business to develop and deploy enhancements to our Corporate Backup service, ensuring we offer world class endpoint data backup to our employees.  Beyond that, you’ll bring your best influencing skills to bear so that others join your vision for the most customer-centric results possible. Everyone at Apple depends on our team’s technical skills, focus on security, and attention to detail.

We are looking for a client engineer with end-user and sys admin experience to contribute to our successful Corporate Backup service.  This person will administer, monitor and maintain our endpoint cloud backup solution, keeping customer experience, performance and security prioritized. Constant interaction with our vendor is necessary to highlight our feature requests, influence the future direction of the product and gain speedy resolution to any defects discovered in production. 

The ideal candidate possesses a strong customer experience ethic, has top-notch people skills, displays creativity and appreciates fully the core strengths that make Apple’s products easy to use.
 

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years in a technical operations or system administration capacity</li>
<li>2+ years in a large enterprise working on endpoint data protection (security and backup)</li>
<li>Strong experience with global technology implementations (Cloud and on-prem) </li>
<li>Demonstrated experience with technical admin and troubleshooting</li>
<li>Expert with macOS and iOS</li>
<li>Clear and articulate communicator</li>
<li>Obsessed with customer experience</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability operating as part of a high performance team, delivering objectives under tough deadlines and comfortable in an ever-changing, global environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The responsibilities of the team are varied. Your role will include, but not be limited to:
Supporting our Corporate Backup environment (cloud, on-prem and clients)
Managing our ticket queue for support escalations and ensuring SLAs are adhered to
Working with the vendor on a weekly basis
SME and escalation point for global support teams
Supporting our eDiscovery and Legal teams
Advocating our Corporate Backup service and driving its adoption throughout the company
Participating in a variety of technical projects throughout the year</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree or equivalent work experience</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Managing and working with vendors
UNIX/Linux sys admin
Experience with change management controls
Data analysis and presentation
</p>
</div></body></html>
