<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56786013">HID Sensor Algorithm Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56786013</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Be part of the engineering team creating next-generation touch interfaces for iPhone, Apple Watch and more. We are looking for a signal processing or imaging engineer with working knowledge of probabilistic modeling, statistics and state machines. Must have strong programming skills in functional and mathematical modeling languages, preferably familiar with embedded programming. Any user interface design or graphics programming skills will broaden your role and effectiveness in this position.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Algorithm development in areas such as gesture or handwriting recognition</li>
<li>C/C++ coding and a mathematical modeling language (e.g. Matlab/mathematica)</li>
<li>Adaptive filters, machine learning, computer vision or robotics</li>
<li>User studies and data analysis (a plus)</li>
<li>User interface design, graphics programming, or linguistic modeling (a plus)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Responsibilities: 

This is a key position at a focal point for HW/SW/UI integration. Starting from early in the product lifecycle, this engineer will analyze HW issues for user impact and potential mitigations, modify and tune current algorithms for new form factors and design and implement new user facing features.

Additional responsibilities include: 
- Investigating new technologies, prototyping concepts, evaluating user impact, and delivering products
- Data collection and analysis
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">
BS in CS/CE/EECS/Math; MS or PhD is preferred.  </p>
</div></body></html>
