<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-46158842">Mechanical Design Engineer (Haptic Engineering)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 46158842</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Feb. 1, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Design haptic solutions that shape next-generation Haptic Technologies in Apple products.

The Haptic Engineering team develops cutting-edge Haptic solutions and technologies that are central to Apple’s products, including the iPhone and Apple Watch. The key goal of the Haptic Engineering team is to enable the world’s best user-experience. New challenges arise everyday that require the sharp problem-solving skills of talented and smart individuals. The team features a highly cross-functional and hands-on environment that fosters engineering excellence, creativity, and innovation. 

Product Design / Mechanical Design Engineer to lead the design, development, and validation of next-generation Haptic Technologies.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3D CAD experience required, NX preferred</li>
<li>Experience in 2D drafting, GD&amp;T, and tolerance analysis</li>
<li>Strong engineering fundamentals (solid mechanics, kinematics, dynamics)</li>
<li>Master of problem solving: including use of the scientific method, root cause analysis, and DOE creation</li>
<li>Applied knowledge in electrical circuits, material science, and basic chemistry</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication and leadership skills</li>
<li>Team Oriented: must be able to thrive in collaborative cross-functional environments </li>
<li>Preferred Qualifications:</li>
<li> 4+ years of hands-on, detailed product design experience in consumer electronics products</li>
<li> Design experience with haptic technologies and/or electro-mechanical actuators</li>
<li> Proficiency with data analysis tools (JMP, MATLAB, Excel, etc)</li>
<li> Expert knowledge of electromechanics and dynamics  </li>
<li> High volume mass production experience (DFM)</li>
<li> Experience in modeling complex, dynamic, cross-disciplinary systems</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">End-to-end mechanical design and integration of a haptic actuator from concept to production
Brainstorming design concepts and executing concepts in all phases of a development cycle
Prototype bring-up, debug and characterization
Defining mechanical component outlines and assembly schemes
Generating innovative design including detailed written specifications, drawings, and tolerance analysis
Participating in the development of new manufacturing and assembly processes with external vendors (includes periodic international travel)
Managing and tracking multiple priorities within schedule requirements
Conducting design reviews and driving design documentation release process
Analysis of static and dynamic structures to quantify fundamental device performance
Design validation and characterization from prototype to final product testing
Driving failure analyses and design of experiments to reach design solutions and corrective actions
Communicating cross-functionally and throughout management structure (written, verbal, and presentation)
Collaboration with industrial design, manufacturing, operations, electrical, and other engineering groups
Driving design towards Apple's cosmetic requirements
IP generation</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S. in Mechanical Engineering, M.S. preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
