<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-50452901">Analog Mixed-Signal Micro Architect</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 50452901</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Architect low-power high-performance AMS solutions.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate should have architecture, design, and production expertise in the following areas:</li>
<li>High-speed wireline transceiver architectures and circuits.</li>
<li>High-speed memory interface architectures and circuit.</li>
<li>High-speed data converter architectures and circuits.</li>
<li>Ultra-low-power analog circuits.</li>
<li>Digitally-assisted analog circuits.</li>
<li>The ideal candidate should be skilled in the following areas:</li>
<li>Matlab/Simulink/VerilogA modeling.</li>
<li>Data converter architectures and design tradeoffs.</li>
<li>Low-power and high-precision analog techniques.</li>
<li>Architect circuit solutions that achieve challenging noise, linearity, power consumption, and silicon area requirements.</li>
<li>AMS design flows and chip assembly techniques.</li>
<li>Working with design, layout, and production test engineers.</li>
<li>Excellent communication.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, the key responsibilities are the following:

Top-down architectural analysis of AMS systems. Understand general concepts of high-performance analog design and compare various topologies that best fit the specifications. Enhance system performance using digitally-assisted analog techniques and optimum partitioning of analog and digital circuits. Develop signal processing and calibration algorithms for mixed-signal systems. Transistor-level feasibility study for various AMS circuits. Define design specifications and verification plans. Define production and bench-level test plans.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Requires MSEE with min. 6+ years of experience in related areas of expertise or PhD + 3 years of experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
