<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112944075">Developer Publications Engineering Project Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112944075</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 29, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">If you enjoy managing projects of all sizes, and are passionate about providing the best learning experience for Apple developers, then we have a great position for you! The Developer Publications team is looking for an experienced Engineering Project Manager to work with engineers across the company who are developing new technologies, along with an amazing staff of content writers, designers, and editors, to deliver world class array of teaching materials, such as API Reference, Sample Code, Playgrounds, to millions of developers around the world. In this role, you till manage projects of all sizes, levels of complexity, and secrecy, and play a critical role in their success. As such, the successful candidate is a great communicator, extremely detail-oriented, proactive, focused, highly motivated, thinks out of the box, and can help teams identify and resolve problem in a constructive and scalable way.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Attention to detail</li>
<li>Self-motivated and proactive</li>
<li>Critical thinking and creative problem solving</li>
<li>Software release experience, managing complex, cross-functional projects</li>
<li>Ability to devise and organize project plans, schedules, tracking </li>
<li>Concise verbal and written communication skills</li>
<li>Experience with Programming Languages, such as Ruby, Swift, and JavaScript, is a plus</li>
<li>Experience with Source Management Systems, such as Git and SVN, is helpful</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a project manager, your responsibilities include:

Build project plans and schedules and track to them

Track and prioritize tasks across multiple product releases and efforts simultaneously

Drive program meetings and events

Communicate effectively at all levels, from informal drop-ins to formal announcements, often being the face of Developer Publications inside Apple

Use tracking tools such as Numbers, OmniPlan, OmniGraffle, web databases, and may create web tools for managing and tracking purposes</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors Degree in Computer Science or equivalent experience

</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience using project management tools such as OmniPlan, MS Project

Thorough understanding of macOS and iOS technologies</p>
</div></body></html>
