<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113037309">Software Engineer in Test - Health Software</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113037309</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 15, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Want to help make a deep impact on the lives of hundreds of millions of people all over the world? Are you passionate about shipping code? Come join a team of enthusiastic, hard working, diverse and highly talented people developing life changing software! The Health Software team is looking for an experienced software or QA engineer who is proactive, detail oriented, and can multi-task effectively. You will be a member of the Health Software team working on QA for HealthKit, app development for tools, and automation frameworks with the additional benefit of learning about the health industry and product development at Apple and more!</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong computer science fundamentals including data structures and algorithms</li>
<li>Proficient in Objective-C and/or Swift.</li>
<li>Experience developing iOS and watchOS applications.</li>
<li>Proficient in scripting with Python/Perl/Shell etc.</li>
<li>Solid understanding of and ability to communicate QA practices in order to help maintain a culture of testing.</li>
<li>Thrive in a collaborative environment and can clearly communicate technical problems to software teams and management.</li>
<li>Passionate and inquisitive, seek to solve everyday problems in innovative ways</li>
<li>2-3 years in a software development or quality engineering role.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Software Engineer in Test you will be working on validating software for the HealthKit Team. You will be expected to develop test plans and iOS and watchOS reference applications to enable testing of new and existing APIs in the HealthKit software stack. In addition, you will be working to identify and build tools to test HealthKit’s integration with other projects, such as transport layers and SQLite.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S. in Computer Science, Computer Engineering or equivalent experience. 
</p>
</div></body></html>
