<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-49219730">WiSE - Sr. Wireless Firmware Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 49219730</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join our Wireless Software Engineering team and drive innovation that matters! 

We create and seamlessly integrate technologies that enrich people’s lives and deliver the absolute best user-experience.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10+ years of embedded software development experience with commercial SOC products for very high volume consumer electronics products</li>
<li>Expert level C/C++ programming skills, familiarity with compilers, build and source code control tools</li>
<li>Experience with memory constrained Real Time Operating Systems (RTOS) and concurrent programming</li>
<li>Deep understanding of wireless communication software/firmware architecture</li>
<li>Experience with wireless communication principles and protocols: 3GPP, 802.11 or Bluetooth</li>
<li>Good understanding of SoC architecture, DMA, bus, GPIO etc.</li>
<li>Proficiency debugging embedded software systems. Familiarity with UARTs JTAG, and oscilloscopes</li>
<li>Thrive in a collaborative environment and can clearly communicate while confidently driving multiple projects across many teams</li>
<li>Obsessively passionate and inquisitive, and seek to solve everyday problems in innovative ways</li>
<li>Laser-focused on the smallest details that are meaningful to our customers</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are seeking an energetic and self-driven senior level firmware engineer or architect, who will play a central role in the embedded firmware effort within a wireless software group responsible for designing and productizing state-of-the-art wireless products for Apple.

Responsibilities:
▪Define, design, implement and debug the firmware architecture for cutting edge mobile wireless products
▪Implement wireless communication protocol on host driver and on-chip firmware
▪Design and implement wireless communication MAC/PHY algorithm
▪Closely work with Silicon team to partition HW/SW and define HW/SW interface
▪Define methodologies and best practices
▪Execute technical leadership and mentor junior member in the team</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s or Master’s degree in Computer Science or Software Engineering or equivalent
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Hands-on datapath experience a plus.
</p>
</div></body></html>
