<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-41559038">Display System Architect - Platform Architecture</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 41559038</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will lead the architecture of SoC display subsystem, including memory fabric interface, data pipe flow controls, memory compression, display interfaces, and etc.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 10+ years of in chip architecture, display subsystem architecture, design experience with a complete understanding of the technology</li>
<li>SoC display subsystem architecture and micro-architecture knowledge</li>
<li>Thorough understanding of SoC display sub-system architecture, interface, performance and energy tradeoffs Broad understanding of display technology</li>
<li>Demonstrated expertise in memory sub-system, memory interface, and DMA</li>
<li>Demonstrated architectural modeling ability</li>
<li>Strong communication skills with cross-functional teams</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The ideal candidate will be responsible for all aspects of SoC display subsystem architecture:
• Work closely with SoC and fabric architects, software, and system engineers to architect SoC display subsystem
• Architect display subsystems, including display pipe control, memory, and interfaces
• Provide detailed architectural guidance at all levels of design throughout the design process from concept through production
• Make recommendation on key design tradeoffs across architecture and performance
• Author and maintain the display subsystem architecture specifications
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MSEE/CE required
</p>
</div></body></html>
