<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113045094">Technical Product Manager – Media</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113045094</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We’re looking for a Technical Product Manager with a passion for media to join our Partner Data and Analytics team in Cupertino. You’ll work with peers from a diverse set of product and engineering teams to design and build innovative reporting systems that exceed industry standards and provide our partners with clear, accurate, and actionable insights. 

In this role, you’ll combine your passion for media (music, film / TV, and books) with data to chart a strategic course. In this role, you’ll lead similarly passionate people at all levels and be part of the team responsible for building the reporting and data systems used globally by our partners across a wide range of content types, including apps, music, film, and books.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>A deep understanding of media, either in music or film / TV, and past experience working with data and reporting systems in the digital space is a must</li>
<li>A proven ability to deliver automated, scalable analytics and reporting systems in a fast-paced and cross-functional environment while managing multiple projects and responsibilities</li>
<li>A demonstrated ability to query large datasets using SQL, Hive, Python, or similar languages and to distill your findings into easy-to-understand analyses</li>
<li>A nagging intellectual curiosity and an extreme attention to detail that drives you to self-audit your work and understand complex systems</li>
<li>An ability to clearly and effectively communicate and manage relationships with a diverse group of internal and external stakeholders</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Drive the vision, strategy, and overall success for the data tools and analytics used by our media partners, conceptualizing a compelling data product roadmap and delivering clear specifications
Collaborate with peers from product, analytics, engineering, and operations to solve complex and challenging problems with data and to deliver new and innovative partner-facing data products, features, and enhancements
Design and maintain innovative and scalable systems to turn large amounts of data into clear, accurate, and easy-to-use reports
Work closely with a development team to implement new features and enhancements to these systems, turning your designs into code that lasts
Meet directly with our partners to identify ways to improve our reporting and anticipate needs by understanding industry trends</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree</p>
</div></body></html>
