<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-51983745">DRAM Product Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 51983745</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this position you will ensure the successful integration of DRAM memories with Apple's SoC devices.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Requires 5+ years in DRAM development</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills and teamwork abilities</li>
<li>Knowledge in DRAM cell architectures</li>
<li>Knowledge in DRAM memory organization and periphery design for low DRAM power</li>
<li>Experience with memory interface verification with understanding DDR-PHY and Memory Controller</li>
<li>Experience with LPDDR IO (DDR/DDR2/DDR3/DDR4) characterization and qualification</li>
<li>Knowledge in memory test patterns</li>
<li>Knowledge in DRAM reliability</li>
<li>Knowledge with state of the art packaging technology (POP, TSV, etc.) and their relationship to DRAM signal/power integrity</li>
<li>Previous experience in Failure Analysis of DRAM devices</li>
<li>Excellent hardware and software debug skill</li>
<li>Experience working with the major DRAM memory vendors</li>
<li>Strong background in computer architecture</li>
<li>Programming experience in C/C++</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Working with design, verification, and integration engineers to ensure memory controller requirements are well defined and cover the scope of DRAM based corner cases
Collaborating with the DRAM vendors for Apple’s main memory solution
Ensuring the timing, voltage and power of the DRAM silicon meets Apple's requirements
Define DRAM corner silicon and ensure all AC/DC characteristics represent corner cases
Drive the validation and qualification of DRAM with the memory vendors
Debugging RMA material with apparent DRAM related defects
Collaborating with the DRAM vendors to improve DRAM FAB/Assembly related defects
Drive the roadmaps and specs of memory vendors for next technology node devices
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">PhD, MS, or BS Degree in technical discipline</p>
</div></body></html>
