<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-44985824">Wireless SOC Test Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 44985824</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Seeking engineers wanting a challenging Test Engineering position in wireless communication. Individuals will work with RFIC circuit designers and system integration engineers to do: Bench testing, debugging, and characterizing RF Wireless SoC performance.  Individuals will then automate mentioned tasks especially for tasks that are done repeatedly or require a high amount of setup.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>•Strong wireless PHY/MAC experience including objected oriented programming experience such as Python </li>
<li>•Expertise in test and script development (eg. Python but at a minimum Unix scripting knowledge is a requirement. )</li>
<li>•Working knowledge of RF test equipment (network analyzer, spectrum analyzer, vector signal analyzer, vector signal generator, etc.).</li>
<li>•Candidates should be comfortable in a lab environment and have a minimum of 5+ years experience</li>
<li>•Expect candidates to be proficient with basic metrics for determining quality of digital communication signals measured. </li>
<li>•Having experience with Channel Emulation, RF parametric testing and loadpull testing are highly desirable.  </li>
<li>•Good written and verbal communication skills.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Designing, automating and executing directed PHY/MAC testing scripts, which control and setup RF test equipment.  
•Designing, automating and executing scripts that plot, parse and analyze large data sets of data
•Generating RF design/verification/test reports by interfacing with RF and systems and integration teams to design such reports.
•Work collaboratively with team members </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•MS or PhD EE or EECS</p>
</div></body></html>
