<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112873054">Information Security Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112873054</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking an exceptional Information Security Engineer to support our vulnerability management program across all our assets. This is a technical hands-on role in a dynamic and fast-paced environment. You’ll be working with various application and system owners to report vulnerabilities, to drive remediations, and also to improve our current processes. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ability to track and manage numerous parallel activities</li>
<li>Passionate about keeping our customers data safe</li>
<li>Strong communication skills</li>
<li>Highly collaborative</li>
<li>Driven to automate and improve continuously</li>
<li>Familiarity with common security vulnerabilities and the ability to judge their severity and impact to the business</li>
<li>High standard of ethics</li>
<li>Excellent knowledge of large-scale security solutions integration</li>
<li>Good knowledge of integrating very large data sets, analyze these datas and present relevant metrics</li>
<li>Knowledge of the security research community is a strong plus</li>
<li>Strong understanding of network topology IPV6</li>
<li>Very good understanding of vulnerability scanning tools</li>
<li>Skills and Experience with either Python, Perl, Shell Scripting</li>
<li>Experience in configuring CI processes using Jenkins</li>
<li>Experience with SQL and Linux</li>
<li>Experience in implementing code quality scanning and reporting using tools like Jenkins, Sonar, Appscan or Fortify</li>
<li>Experience on Web Services</li>
<li>Experience implementing solutions in the cloud</li>
<li>Experience with big data</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will join a team that passionately stays up to date on emerging security vulnerabilities and threats, keeps a cool head in crisis, and advocates every single day for improving the security of Apple products and services. Successful candidates will need to have a good technical background, superb communication skills, and a strong interest in network, system, and web security. The role also requires a strong ability to work with incomplete information and to adapt to changing priorities. Specific responsibilities include: 
* Strategize vulnerability management for the application and business team
* Author clear, authoritative responses to vulnerability queries 
* Provide guidance to engineering teams regarding the impact of security issues 
* Work closely with project management to drive issues to closure 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science, Information Technology, or related field and 5 years experience in information technology or related field within the last 10 years OR 7 years experience in information technology </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">5+ years’ experience Information Security Engineering experience
7+ years’ Unix/Linux systems engineering background
</p>
</div></body></html>
