<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-86230414">WW Business Analytics Manager </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 86230414</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Our mission in the Business Analytics team within the WW Sales and Operations organization is is to enable rapid business decision making through building an agile data strategy and infrastructure, and delivering world class reporting and analytics. We are looking for a senior leader to join our team and do the best work of their lives here at Apple.

The ideal candidate for this role has a combination of business acumen in the supply chain and operations domain and technical knowledge of business intelligence and advanced analytics capabilities. This role will be responsible for delivering a comprehensive data strategy and running an efficient and scalable reporting and analytics function that supports a broad range of functions as well as senior executives across the company.  You will enable the launch and growth of Apple’s products across all routes to market. This role is highly visible, interacting with executives and teams throughout Apple.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>- Innovative and strategic approach to reporting and business analytics</li>
<li>- Strong business mindset - ability to grasp business needs, translate into technical needs; ability to communicate complex technical concepts to business leaders</li>
<li>- Extensive experience in overseeing business analysis, reporting, and data analytics / data science functions</li>
<li>- Strong familiarity with multiple platforms, tools, methodologies in the data management, reporting and analytics space</li>
<li>- Ability to manage a complex portfolio of programs, manage capital and opex budgets and headcount</li>
<li>- Ability to define and build robust management systems that enable business visibility and decision making</li>
<li>- Experience driving reporting improvements and technology implementations in support of business analytics</li>
<li>- Ability to comprehensively understand data elements, sources and relationships in business and technical terms</li>
<li>- Strong track record of building and leading a high-performing team</li>
<li>- Demonstrated teamwork as well as leadership and influence skills</li>
<li>- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal - able to present complex analytics and technical topics to an executive audience</li>
<li>- Excellent prioritization skills</li>
<li>- Ability to operate comfortably and effectively in a fast paced, highly-matrixed, rapidly changing environment</li>
<li>- Excellent time management skills with the ability to manage work to tight deadlines and handle the pressure of product launches and executive requests</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Lead a global BI center of excellence that drives the business strategy around reporting and analytics capabilities required to support operational management and executive decision making
- Partner with the WW and regional IS&amp;T and business analytics teams to enable both short term quick wins and long term scalable solutions
- Manage and execute a complex portfolio of programs that enable scalable self-service BI solutions 
- Engage with the business and with business process reengineering efforts to define end to end process and data flows
- Drive a global strategy that aligns regional business analytics teams to a common process and framework
- Build and maintain strong partnerships with key leaders across the company in order to successfully lead specific business tracks
- Lead a team of program managers, architects, analysts and analytics professionals that are focused on providing the infrastructure and information needed to manage Apple’s business
- Supports the business in operational reporting, dashboards, data analysis and advanced analytics
- Lead governance and business ownership of master data, hierarchies, key measures, KPIs, etc.
- Partner with other Apple organizations on data governance, reporting standards, data quality, reporting tools, hierarchy management and KPI’s.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or equivalent, MS preferred
15+ years of relevant experience
</p>
</div></body></html>
