<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113140552">Technical Project Manager, Software Applications</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113140552</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 13, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Technology team in Apple’s Worldwide Marketing Communications group is responsible for a number of areas including systems infrastructure, internal tools, and applications delivered to customers on  <a class="bridgeLink" target="_blank" href="http://www.apple.com">www.apple.com</a>, used by Apple business partners across the globe, as well as customers in retail stores. The Technical Project Manager, Applications, oversees multiple projects from the technology project portfolio, regularly reporting status on how each project is tracking relative to scope, schedule and resources. The position typically oversees more than one project, with the project manager needing to be able to adjust priorities as frequently as necessary. A key part of the job is bridging the gap between non-technical business users who provide the core requirements and technical implementers, with the ability to clearly set expectations and communicate status to both groups.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>You can adjust your interpersonal approach to individuals and situations as needed to effectively work with others.</li>
<li>You can effectively communicate with global stakeholders with varied marketing and technical strengths</li>
<li>You are persistent and can discover and eliminate complexity and ambiguity in projects to ensure clarity and establish goals and expectations for services requested.</li>
<li>You understand complex technical projects and can quickly learn about new technologies and solutions to manage their implementation.</li>
<li>You have a demonstrated ability to develop broad perspective on an organization and can use that knowledge to develop new strategies and options for new projects.</li>
<li>You can maintain momentum on a project and will diligently follow every detail through to its completion.</li>
<li>You can juggle multiple projects within a fast paced environment and change priorities rapidly as required by the business.</li>
<li>General project management skills as needed for technical projects: status, project plan, and risk and issues management.</li>
<li>Solid understanding of project management methodologies, with proven experience in putting project management processes in place. Demonstrated ability to deliver projects by adapting techniques to best fit circumstances. </li>
<li>Deep understanding of waterfall and Agile development methodology.</li>
<li>Able to analyze and document detailed functional requirements to create technical level-of-effort estimates. </li>
<li>Proven success as a key member of a matrixed, cross-functional team. Able to work equally well with people in creative and technical positions.</li>
<li>Able to apply sound judgment while working independently within tight timelines.</li>
<li>Outstanding attention to detail and commitment to excellence.</li>
<li>Excellent oral and written communicator, with great interpersonal skills. Able to forge trusting relationships within a diverse team. </li>
<li>Fanatical about creating order from disorder. Understands the “right” level of process to apply to different projects.</li>
<li>Solid technical background, experience managing technical projects, and/or hands-on technical experience.</li>
<li>Familiarity with systems administration, deployment of new hardware, and the issues associated with both activities.</li>
<li>Deeply familiar with software development methodologies.</li>
<li>Familiarity with Mac OS, multi-tiered web application stack, Unix (and flavors), networking basics, Java and front-end technology.</li>
<li>Knowledge of databases (MySQL in particular), ability to write simple SQL queries, debug issues at any level of the application stack, and unilaterally troubleshooting problems a huge plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Gather project requirements to develop tactical and detail oriented project plans, objectives and schedules that support department needs.
Extensive collaboration with IT infrastructure, network, and security organizations to track specific details of tactical work for the Marcom organization
Lead cross-functional teams to define the scope, business objectives and required project results.
Document detailed project findings for technical evaluation.
Develop project schedules and budgets. Estimate, negotiate and obtain resources to meet project requirements. Maintain, adjust and update program and project plans as needed.
Quickly grasp the essence of multiple new technical concepts and lead the team through assessment and documentation of goals, risks, dependencies, and timelines focusing on these concepts.
Marshal resources from a matrix functional group to get things done, and use resources effectively and efficiently.
Clearly assign responsibility for tasks and decisions. Manage and monitor project schedules, progress and costs.  
Consolidate, communicate and manage all issues and risks affecting the program or project.
Communicate program and project status to global participants and stakeholders accurately and on time.
Provide roll-up information to track projects in an overall project portfolio.
Work cross-functionally with other teams to ensure successful completion of programs and projects.
Manage rollout, release, post launch support, and issue triage during and beyond warranty period as necessary.
Deliver comprehensive summary of post project metrics, areas of potential improvement, and apply learnings to future efforts.


</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Requires a Bachelors Degree with 5+ years project management experience demonstrating increasing levels of project management responsibilities in a complex enterprise environment. PMP and/or CSM is a plus.
Undergraduate degree in Computer Science or Engineering is a strong plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
