<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112866167">Product Quality Engineer - Mac</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112866167</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 10, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join the fast paced Product Quality Engineering team. You will partner closely with the Engineering, Program Management and Operations teams throughout the product life cycle to enable success.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>• Working knowledge and theory of Quality Methods, Design of Experiments, statistical process control methods</li>
<li>• Project management experience</li>
<li>• Excellent written and verbal communication skills in English</li>
<li>• Technical systems knowledge related to electronics and mechanical assembly</li>
<li>• Broad software knowledge (OS &amp; test related)</li>
<li>• Reliability methods and quality sampling methodologies</li>
<li>• Third party production quality &amp; process management experience </li>
<li>• Experience working with customers </li>
<li>• Exceptional ability to build relationships</li>
<li>• Clear &amp; consistent communication</li>
<li>• Data-driven and results-oriented approach to problem solving</li>
<li>• Enthusiastic and motivated</li>
<li>• 5+ years of industry experience in manufacturing or development of electronics</li>
<li>• Experience working with high volume international manufacturers and traveling to manufacturing sites</li>
<li>• Ability to travel internationally 40%.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Ensure product quality readiness for all phases of the introduction cycle, including driving contract manufacturer preparation for pre-production builds
• Own and drive key quality metrics 
• Provide regular VP level communication of program quality
• Generate Product Quality Plan (PQP)
• Drive Final Quality Assurance (FQA) development, documentation, optimization &amp; execution during new product development
• Drive FQA issues to resolution during new product development with the cross-functional team
• Manage quality escalations during mass production bring up
• Support and attend new product development builds as required</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS degree in Engineering</p>
</div></body></html>
