<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53619239">RF/Wireless Design Validation Test Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53619239</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Seeking engineers wanting a challenging RF/Wireless Design Validation Test (DVT) Engineering position. Individuals will work with RFIC circuit designers and system integration engineers to do: RF bench testing, debugging, and characterizing RF Wireless SoC performance.  Individuals will either automate mentioned tasks and/or help specify test procedures especially for tasks that are done repeatedly or require extensive setup.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have the following qualifications:</li>
<li>Strong Wireless RF background and familiarity with RF systems fundamentals</li>
<li>Working knowledge of RF parametric testing such as IP3, NF, ACPR, phase noise, etc.</li>
<li>Knowledge of loadpull testing is desirable.  </li>
<li>Characterized/Debugged RF PCB and chip issues within a test and script development •Strong working knowledge of RF test equipment (network analyzer, spectrum analyzer, vector signal analyzer, vector signal generator, etc.).</li>
<li>Unix scripting knowledge is a requirement. (Highly desirable is objected oriented programming experience such as Python is highly desirable)</li>
<li>Candidates should be comfortable in a lab environment and have a minimum of 5+ years experience</li>
<li>Expect candidates to be proficient with basic metrics for determining quality of digital communication signals measured.</li>
<li>Good written and verbal communication skills.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will work with RFIC circuit designers on:

•Characterizing and debugging RF PCB and chip issues such as external matching networks to optimize Tx/Rx radio performance
•Designing, and executing and/or automating directed RF and/or PHY/MAC testing scripts, which control and setup RF test equipment and RF chips
•Designing, executing and/or automating scripts that plot, parse and analyze large data sets of data
•Generating RF design/verification/test reports by interfacing with RF and systems and integration teams to design such reports.
•Work collaboratively with team members.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE or MSEE</p>
</div></body></html>
