<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54884129"> Maps Routing Software Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54884129</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is hiring outstanding software engineers to deliver the next generation of routing services for Apple Maps. If you are passionate about building the world's best routing platform at massive scale, this opportunity is for you. You will develop cutting-edge routing algorithms to constantly improve the routing experience and help millions of people every day with their driving, walking and public transit.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Industry experience in C++ and Linux</li>
<li>Outstanding understanding of graph algorithms and data structures</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving and analytical skills</li>
<li>Good interpersonal and communication skills</li>
<li>Inquisitive and highly-motivated self-starter</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple Maps provides driving, walking, and public transit routes to millions of users every day.  As part of the routing team, your responsibilities will include:

Designing routing features that will be used by millions worldwide 
Improve routing calculations using your algorithm knowledge
Implementing new features and resolving complex issues 
Working on high performance code using C++
Participating in design and code reviews 
Working with other engineers and QA to deliver high  quality routes to our customers
Influencing the future product direction</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS or PhD in computer science or a related field, or equivalent experience </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">For this role, the following skills would be a plus, but are not necessary. 

Data Science or Machine Learning background
Maps or GIS experience</p>
</div></body></html>
