<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112975833">Machine Learning Software Engineer - Client </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112975833</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We’re looking for a talented software engineer to help us build and deploy systems for learning from the activities of the crowd while preserving individual privacy.

In this role, you’ll implement novel machine learning algorithms, and integrate them into efficient client frameworks. These systems help us understand and improve Apple’s user experience, and are an important part of our strategic focus on privacy. You’ll work in a small and dynamic team and collaborate in algorithm development, pushing the frontier of differential privacy and other forms of data privacy.

This position requires a broad set of software engineering skills, with particular focus on efficient implementations. You should have experience creating at least one significant application or framework with local storage and network communication. An understanding of data privacy and a deep respect for users are also key.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years practical background in software engineering and client development</li>
<li>Proven track record delivering shipping software</li>
<li>Fluency in Objective-C, Swift, or another C-based language</li>
<li>Experience with iOS client APIs</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Produce high quality code with excellent reliability and performance
Explore novel architectural solutions and communicate ideas clearly
Collaborate in cross-functional teams to prototype new concepts and deliver end-to-end systems</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S. in Computer Science</p>
</div></body></html>
