<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113047327">Optical Sensor Engineer - Exploratory Design Group</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113047327</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 18, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">This is a hands-on role, working on an optical science team within a highly multi-disciplinary group to demonstrate new optical sensor concepts. You will exercise both your technical breadth and your deep understanding of optical devices and systems.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 5+ total years of experience with optical and/or device physics, some industrial experience developing products based on new technology, and most of the following:</li>
<li>Excellent grasp of optical physics fundamentals.</li>
<li>Hands-on experience implementing and testing optical devices and systems.</li>
<li>Experience constructing and validating models of optical devices, based on first principles and empirical data.</li>
<li>Solid understanding of optical systems, laser and non-laser optical sources, and optical measurement techniques.</li>
<li>Understanding of the impact of coherence on optical systems.</li>
<li>Proficiency at C, Matlab, Python or similar programming.</li>
<li>Experience with sequential and/or non-sequential ray-tracing, optical waveguide design, optical mode-solvers, or simulation of diffraction effects.</li>
<li>Excellent communication and presentation skills.</li>
<li>Ability to work well in a team environment.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As an Optical Sensor Engineer, you will:

•Work with the team to invent, implement and validate optical sensor concepts.
•Design, simulate, and specify optical devices and sub-systems to meet project requirements.
•Work with external vendors to fabricate custom devices.
•Characterize performance of optical devices, sub-systems and systems relative to project requirements.
•Identify causal relationships between observed performance and design parameters.
•Interpret empirical data and reconcile it with first-principles analytical and/or numerical simulations.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Masters degree or PhD in Physics, Applied Physics, Optics, EE, or related field is required.
</p>
</div></body></html>
