<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-51405755">Siri Speech Data Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 51405755</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jan. 4, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking.  Join the Siri Speech team at Apple.

The Siri Speech team is looking for exceptional data engineers passionate about customer experience, who love working with data to analyze trends. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Exceptional programming skills - expertise in programming languages such as C/C++ and Java as well as scripting languages such as: Python, Perl, Ruby, and bash</li>
<li>Strong analytical skills and a passion for data and data quality</li>
<li>Experience in the development and maintenance of tools for analyzing and processing large amounts of data</li>
<li>Outstanding communication and presentation skills</li>
<li>Proficiency in illustrating data analysis with graphs and statistics</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Siri Speech team is looking for exceptional data engineers who are eager to improve the Siri experience and have a significant impact on a product used by millions of customers all over the world. 

You will be a part of a small, collaborative team of talented researchers and engineers and be responsible for data analysis, test set preparation and tools development.  You should thrive in a fast paced environment with rapidly changing priorities, and collaborate well with engineering teams at all levels of the software stack to to succeed.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S or M.S  in Computer Science, or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
