<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113122553">Info Systems Engineer, IS&amp;T Collaboration Services</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113122553</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 31, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Client &amp; Collaboration Services team ensures Apple’s employees are productive, efficient and secure. As part of the Collaboration Services team you will be responsible for identifying and implementing cutting-edge products while managing flawless operation of existing systems.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in designing and managing systems with high performance, scalability and availability</li>
<li>Experience implementing 3rd party solutions with a strong focus on performance, security, reliability and internal tool integrations. Experience with SAML is desired. </li>
<li>Experience with managing, deploying and securing content co-editing collaboration solutions is required</li>
<li>Experience with AWS-hosted applications, with solid knowledge of data encryption</li>
<li>Experience with Oracle RDBMS, Cassandra, Git, Jenkins and Scrum development process</li>
<li>Accomplished automation/scripting experience with Bash, Perl, Python, or other.</li>
<li>Efficiently troubleshoot/prioritize issues and reinforce a culture of root cause analysis.</li>
<li>Responsible for configuration, management, and support of infrastructure with careful regard to availability, connectivity, performance, and security.</li>
<li>Coordinate vendor escalations by acting as a bridge to the vendor’s support and engineering resources.</li>
<li>Continuously move forward by researching new and emerging technologies.</li>
<li>Proactive follow through on commitments. Excellent communication, organizational and presentation skills; attention to detail.</li>
<li>Keep technical skills and product knowledge sharp via ongoing training and personal study. Coach junior staff and assist in training new developers to organize our growing team</li>
<li>Curiosity and a willingness to learn and talk about emerging technologies</li>
<li>Ability to manage conflicting project demands and thrive in a fast-paced environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will be responsible for designing the architecture of collaboration systems as well as managing the day-to-day development activities of a group of junior developers and contractors. Beyond that, you’ll bring your best influencing skills to bear so that others join your vision for the most customer-centric results possible.  You will be responsible for evaluating and integrating collaboration tools as well as developing a strategy/roadmap for collaboration tools.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS Computer Science or Equivalent</p>
</div></body></html>
