<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113139979">Senior Producer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113139979</li>
<li title="Culver City, California, United States">Culver City, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Beats by Dr. Dre is seeking a Senior Producer role to manage all aspects of day to day production projects, bringing the creative vision to life. They will lead the production process and be the brand’s liaison to our trusted partners communicating production logistics, as well as technical and artistic details with the goal of creative excellence and brand integrity. The Senior Producer will partner with the creative and brand leads to ensure smooth and efficient production executions. They will be a vocal leader during production projects, acting as the point person for budgets and schedules as they pertain to creative. This person will also play a key role in developing our team by mentoring junior producers with their career trajectory. It is also their responsibility to communicate the status of their current projects with the Head of Production. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of producer experience in the Production field - preferrably Advertising Agency or Brand</li>
<li>5+ years of experience producing global launch campaigns, tv commercials, video content, photoshoots, digital / social content from conception through completion</li>
<li>Strong knowledge in various production approaches: Live Action, Editorial, Animation, VFX </li>
<li>Strong relationships in the creative production community</li>
<li>Expertise in scoping deliverables — cost, schedule, and resourcing </li>
<li>Experience creating project processes and workflows</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple projects to on-time delivery</li>
<li>Passion for contributing to great creative work</li>
<li>Excellent collaboration and communication skills</li>
<li>Experience in fostering cross-team collaboration to ensure all business needs are aligned and accounted for</li>
<li>Proficient in Keynote, Excel, and Word</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Manage all aspects of Production project assigned: Creative Development, Prep, Scheduling, Partner Curation, Bidding, Shoots, Post
Production, VFX, Animation, Music, Finishing, and Final Deliverables
Accurately scope projects and create corresponding project plans that include cost, timeline, resourcing and workflows
Curate potential partners and provide production / creative recommendations
Manage and reconcile project budgets
Stay up to date on new production workflows and innovative technologies
Informed on new talent in the creative production communities
Cultivate growth through mentorship</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA or BS degree preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
