<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112877316">Financial Analyst - WW Sales Finance</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112877316</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for an outgoing professional with high analytical capacity, creativity, and strong interpersonal skills to support the Worldwide Sales Organization. The position requires the ability to complete complex financial and demand analysis, work cross functionally and with local teams in region, develop and execute business strategies, and recommend and present business updates to senior management.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Advanced spreadsheet and modeling skills </li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to conduct complex, data driven analysis. </li>
<li>Strong verbal and written communication skills with the ability to articulate results of analysis in easy to understand business terms</li>
<li>Thrive in a fast-pace, demanding environment</li>
<li>Must be able to think strategically on critical business issues, while simultaneously possessing the ability to act tactically to execute against them</li>
<li>Proven experience developing processes and/or improving existing processes, with desire to influence change across our team and Apple as an organization</li>
<li>Deep understanding of financial principles and theories</li>
<li>Some accounting experience is recommended</li>
<li>Ability to navigate through a large organization</li>
<li>Strong prioritization skills with ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously</li>
<li>5-8 years sales/finance/business development related work experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The ideal candidate is one who has been a top performer in his or her career with a proven track record of accomplishments. The candidate will be joining WW Sales Finance with the expectations of being a key contributor in a fast-paced, growth environment. The candidate should feel comfortable dealing with complex &amp; ambiguous situations.
Responsibilities Include: 
Business Partnership: work closely with local finance teams on demand trends and key sales initiatives, with supply chain on demand assumptions and supply profile to navigate the business forward and provide executive updates
Demand Forecasting: own the WW Sales forecast for multiple lines of business taking into consideration a dynamic global environment
Demand Generation Playbook: own, communicate, approve and manage the playbook used to drive incremental demand for your specific lines of business. 
Product Transition Playbook: drive execution and pricing strategy on end of life products through the channel
Contra-Revenue: roll up and own the spend associated with sales actions to the corporate FP&amp;A team
Influence various teams and be comfortable being the central point of contact for a product across teams and geographies. </p>
</div></body></html>
