<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113135171">Sensing HW Engineer (Optics)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113135171</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Design, develop, and launch next-generation Sensing Technologies. 
The Sensing Systems team integrates Optical, MEMS, magnetic and capacitive sensors across a variety of Apple products such as iPhones, iPads, MacBooks. Bring devices to life and enable them interact with users and the environment in ways never imagined before. Join us in crafting solutions the world doesn't know of yet. The Optical sensing team is looking for a someone who has an illumination optics background and is a self-driven go-getter.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong optics background (such as lenses, diffusers, thin films)</li>
<li>Proficiency in Python and JMP tools for data collection and analysis</li>
<li>Working knowledge of sensor opto-electronics (photodiode front-ends)</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills and solid teamwork and leadership </li>
<li>skills </li>
<li>Familiar with optical lab equipment such as spectrometers, spectrophotometers, monochromators, optical filters, etc</li>
<li>Proficiency in MATLAB and simulation tools such as Zemax, Code V or LightTools modeling tools required</li>
<li>Hands-on experience in system- or module-level design preferred</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">System- or module-level prototyping, integration, characterization and validation of optical sensors
Analyze data to draw conclusions to enhance product design and manufacturability
Failure mode analysis, root-cause diagnosis, and system-level problem solving
Business travel to support product development
Collaborate with cross-functional teams (including mechanical, firmware, process and test engineering teams) to deliver state-of-the-art sensing solutions 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S., M.S. or PhD in Optics, Physics or Electrical Engineering. Industry experience preferred. </p>
</div></body></html>
