<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57251200">Computer Vision Algorithm Engineer - Technology Investigation</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57251200</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Technology Investigation team develops core computer vision and machine learning algorithms driving revolutionary future Apple devices. We push the state of the art in areas such as object recognition/tracking, scene understanding, lighting estimation, material classification, 4D reconstruction, novel view synthesis, semantic segmentation, image compositing, automated reconstruction/modeling/animation of users and spatial user input.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Solid foundation in computer vision in at least one of the key areas listed above</li>
<li>Passion on cutting edge computer vision / machine learning technologies and product delivery</li>
<li>Solid C/C++ and system building skills</li>
<li>Excellent understanding of data structures and algorithms</li>
<li>Self motivated</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving skills</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills</li>
<li>Key advantage: Deep understanding of deep learning technology and experience on turning machine learning technologies into practical systems</li>
<li>Advantage: Experience in Python or Matlab programming, TensorFlow/Caffe, 3D computer graphics, computational imaging, multiple view geometry, SfM/SLAM, activity recognition, computational geometry, applied mathematics, non-linear optimization, CPU/GPU optimizations, HW image processing, parallel compute architectures, asynchronous processing, embedded systems, real time OS development, or low-level OS/driver programming</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Technology Investigation team is looking for talented engineers who are passionate about creating products for millions of customers around the world. You’ll be working on cutting-edge technology and develop algorithms that enable a high-quality user experience across a range of tentpole use cases and applications. As a part of Technology Investigation team, you will closely collaborate with HW engineers (cameras, silicon, electrical engineering, product design) and other technology investigation software teams (computer graphics, video engineering, data generation/annotation, drivers/OS). You can make a difference by researching and prototyping novel algorithms beyond the state of the art and/or by optimizing the performance of real-time algorithms running on Apple silicon.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">PhD or Master of Science degree in Computer Science or similar, alternatively a comparable industry career with a proven track record of successful projects.
</p>
</div></body></html>
