<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113082074">Search Ads Client Partner</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113082074</li>
<li title="SF - Corporate, California, United States">SF - Corporate, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking an experienced Search Ads Client Partner with a passion for B2B sales to join our Marketing Platforms team to help businesses with promotion and discovery across Apple Services. A successful candidate will have very strong communication and inter-personal skills, be highly analytical, resourceful, customer focused, team oriented, and will have an ability to work independently to meet revenue and business objectives. You will have a proven track record of meeting or exceeding revenue targets in the mobile and app developer space with performance type advertisers and agencies. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5 years experience in performance media sales with at least 2 years experience leveraging a self-serve type platform</li>
<li>Strong understanding of the mobile ecosystem</li>
<li>Strong understanding of how Performance Advertisers go to market and measure success</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Manage relationships with clients and agencies in the performance marketing space 
Maintain high level of outreach via email, phone and meetings to ensure a strong business pipeline 
Develop a strategy for long-term success across your portfolio of clients &amp; prospects 
Act as a thought-leader with both clients and agencies 
Work closely with your Manager &amp; Platform Specialist team to ensure proper execution and alignment with customer objectives 
Leverage internal &amp; external data sets to understand how to best help grow your customers' businesses</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in a related field or equivalent </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Strategic selling aptitude working with performance advertisers as well as advertising agencies 
Excellent communication and presentations skills - both in person and over the phone 
Must be a team player and be able to work in a fast paced, exciting environment 
Extremely professional and positive demeanor 
Track record of overachievement</p>
</div></body></html>
