<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113168336">Machine Learning Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113168336</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Natural Language Processing Group is responsible for a wide range of text-driven technologies, including auto-correction, spellchecking, predictive typing, Chinese &amp; Japanese input, tokenization, tagging and other solutions that are at the intersection of machine learning and NLP. Our diverse, multi-faceted team delivers intelligent and highly performant technologies driven by natural language text data. We are looking for a passionate machine learning engineer to develop new statistical models for delivering high-quality text input experiences on all Apple platforms.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong working knowledge of machine learning techniques (generative and discriminative models)</li>
<li>Experience applying machine learning techniques to NLP problems</li>
<li>Knowledge of fundamental natural language processing techniques</li>
<li>Research experience in machine learning or natural language processing</li>
<li>Ability to run experiments scientifically and analyze results</li>
<li>Fluency in Python or similar scripting languages</li>
<li>Strong communication skills &amp; collaborative mindset</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Natural Language Processing group is looking for a passionate and talented machine learning engineer to develop algorithms and models to enable seamless text input on all Apple platforms. The position will involve all aspects of the use of natural language processing in software, including design, implementation, algorithms, correctness, user experience, and performance. You will be a key member of a team that is responsible for delivering the natural language intelligence behind keyboard input on the world’s most advanced mobile operating system. The ideal candidate will be proficient in machine learning and natural language processing techniques, self-motivated, and will have a strong focus on details and quality.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS or Ph.D in Computer Science, Computational Linguistics or an equivalent field</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">• Experience working with large data sets
• Programming experience with C++</p>
</div></body></html>
