<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55795952">Siri Server Quality SW Engineer - Platform</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55795952</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in ensuring the quality of groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, natural language, big data, and artificial intelligence. You will be interacting with various teams of cross functional engineering and project management to help identify issues, test features and drive the quality of the Siri user experience. Work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking. 

Join the Siri QA team at Apple!


</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Must have 3 years professional work experience</li>
<li>Degree or working experience in software engineering</li>
<li>Strong organizational skills and experience working on large cross functional teams</li>
<li>Self-motivated and pro-active with demonstrated creative and critical thinking capabilities</li>
<li>Flexibility to respond and react to a rapidly evolving software environment</li>
<li>Familiar with iOS, Mac OS X, debugging tools and Terminal</li>
<li>Experience with Java, C++, Perl, Python, Bash</li>
<li>Experience working with large scale server software features</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Contributing to server-side test automation efforts
Enhance and build tools as needed for server testing
Feature scoping and test plan engineering
Finding, debugging, and reporting of software bugs
Escalating key quality issues and driving to resolution
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS/BS in Computer Science or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
