<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57830446">Corporate Lease Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57830446</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">This position is within Apple's Real Estate &amp; Development team and will report to the Senior Manager of Real Estate. Position is located in Cupertino, CA.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>7-10 years of experience in commercial or corporate real estate with familiarity of construction practices as well as managing internal and external teams</li>
<li>Strong skill set in the following areas: financial modeling, budgeting, negotiations, computer programs (Word, Excel, FileMaker Pro), team building and communication</li>
<li>Strong financial, analytical and communication skills required</li>
<li>Ability to travel internationally</li>
<li>International experience required</li>
<li>Energetic and extremely flexible; motivated and able to work in an incredibly fast and fluid organization</li>
<li>Able to work independently and as part of a team</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Experienced in all facets of acquisition, administration and disposition of leased/owned property. Skills to include commercial leasing, industrial/warehouse leasing, subleasing, sale–lease back, license agreements and land acquisition and disposition. Skilled in planning, tracking, evaluating and reporting on the performance of assigned activities. Ability to work with a wide variety of corporate wide functions to assist in the development of short and long range real estate requirements. Skilled in negotiating multi-million dollar, complex real estate agreements. Experienced in overseeing tenant improvement projects.

Skilled in the leadership, management and coordination of domestic and international real estate leased property acquisition and disposal activities composed of multiple projects in various stages of planning, investigation, negotiation, execution through implementation.

Prepare financial and sensitivity analysis for all transactions and projects.

Develop business justification and recommendations for presentation to user groups and executive management team for approval.

Ability to work with a wide variety of corporate wide functions to assist in the development of short and long range real estate requirements.

Assist with the strategic planning for the acquisition and disposition of Apple owned facilities properties, including financial analysis, market information, offering terms and conditions, marketing materials, contract review, and negotiations.

Review and update real estate best practices, forms and documents and enhancements to the real estate database that will improve the quality of real estate delivery. Develop benchmarking standards, and key metrics and update periodically.

Coordinate with project and construction management team for field projects and oversee conformance to lease requirements such as obtaining landlord consent, negotiating restoration requirements and collection of Tenant Improvement dollars.

Manage current real estate assets by taking a proactive approach by anticipating lease renewals and terminations and all critical dates, lowering and auditing operating expenses, managing subleases and collecting sublease rents, coordinating landlord approval of alterations, completing estoppel certificates, paying rents and property taxes on a timely basis, and assisting in property tax appeals.

Maintains excellent relationships with internal customers, senior management, legal, tax, risk management, landlords, vendors, consultants, and outside brokers throughout the U.S.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS degree from an accredited institution; advanced degree preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
