<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-49261807">Acquisition and Activation Lead</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 49261807</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 8, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking experienced, entrepreneurial leaders with a passion for media and entertainment to massively grow its services, including Apple Music. The Acquisition and Activation Lead will work with marketing, product marketing, business development, design, analytics, and other teams to efficiently and effectively bring customers into our services and activate them.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Sophisticated understanding of subscription or recurring revenue business models</li>
<li>A minimum of 10+ years of online consumer product management and/or marketing experience</li>
<li>A proven track record of accelerating conversion and identifying new conversion opportunities</li>
<li>Data-driven experimentation and testing as part of your DNA</li>
<li>Previous success partnering with research specialists to translate insight into action</li>
<li>Experience driving massive impact in matrix structures using influence</li>
<li>The ability to deliver results individually, to build a team opportunistically, and to lead inspirationally</li>
<li>Humility and a sense of humor</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Define the best KPIs to focus the team and drive results, and ensure they are correctly measured and widely socialized
- Understand and monitor all the business activities that drive those KPIs
- Partner with research specialists on a roadmap of useful insights, and with tool builders on a roadmap of necessary tools and improvements
- Build cross-functional plans to improve performance against those KPIs, with a focus on experimentation and iteration
- Work with functional heads and business-line specialists to execute these plans
- Develop a process of continuous improvement, where the results of this work are analyzed and learnings fed back into the plans
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/BA degree, MS/MA/MBA a plus</p>
</div></body></html>
