<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113076705">Siri Data Engineer, Language Technologies</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113076705</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large-scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence. And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking. Join the Siri team!</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong data analytical skills</li>
<li>Past experience with gradings tasks and tools, e.g. for transcribing speech audio, labeling tasks, language translation, etc.</li>
<li>Excellent coding skills in one or more of following languages — Python, Java, Shell scripts, C/C++</li>
<li>Experienced in big data processing, tools development and/or web crawling </li>
<li>Great communication skills</li>
<li>Knowledge in the field of language technologies/NLP, such as speech recognition, machine translation, text mining, parsing, etc.</li>
<li>Multilingual speaker a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for highly motivated engineers to fulfill our data needs and drive the product quality to the next level. You will be working closely with a group of talented researchers and engineers on the cutting edge machine learning technologies. Your responsibilities include data creation, data management, processing pipeline and tools development. The role also involves the collaborations with other cross functional teams on data related projects.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in Computer Science or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
