<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57380637">Sports Editor </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57380637</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for an experienced editor to lead content curation and programming for the recently-announced live sports feature in the Apple TV app.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Extensive experience in, knowledge of, and enthusiasm for sports, both domestically and internationally, as an editor and a consumer.</li>
<li>Ingrained familiarity with digital media trends, particularly in sports.</li>
<li>Practiced knowledge of the broader television business, from content to distribution.</li>
<li>Exacting attention to detail and exceptional communication skills.</li>
<li>Strong analytical skills; adaptive to data.</li>
<li>Highly motivated team-player, driven self-starter, and able to work in a fast-paced environment.</li>
<li>Experience in developing digital editorial tools and process.</li>
<li>Deep passion for the role Apple’s video platform and device ecosystem will play in bringing an incredible sports experience to customers.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Conceive and maintain a thoughtful, dynamic, and always relevant editorial voice for sports programming in the Apple TV app.
Collaborate with internal Apple teams – engineering, marketing, operations, analytics, production, design – to define and continually evolve Apple’s live sports product so as to meet and exceed both Apple’s own standards and the needs of the most passionate sports fans around the world.
Flexible with schedule; weekend and evening work will be necessary to execute sports programming when it matters most to customers so as to keep the Apple TV app sports offering hyper relevant.
The sports editor must be based in Cupertino, CA.

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS required.  Experience in Sports and Editorial desired. </p>
</div></body></html>
