<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112942415">Connectivity Insights Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112942415</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 16, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Characterize consumer data usage patterns — by device, geography/location, content/media type, and connection (both wireless &amp; wired). Create and implement first-of-a-kind, comprehensive user connectivity studies. Corroborate these direct quantitative findings with existing research sources (Nielsen, etc), to critically assess trends and forecast user demands &amp; requirements. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Undergraduate degree in Engineering or Computer Science</li>
<li>8+ years of experience in a mixture of software engineering, data engineering and analytics.</li>
<li>Demonstrated track record of creating and building complex evaluation tools for assessing/tracking product performance and associated user behaviors.</li>
<li>Expertise across an array of qualitative and quantitative research methodologies.</li>
<li>Experience with analytical tools supporting statistical data evaluation and reporting, as well as querying large, complex data sets (Tableau, Spotfire, STATA, SAS, SQL, SPSS/R, etc).</li>
<li>Strong familiarity with computer/IP networking (bandwidth estimation, packet loss, latency, streaming protocols, video codecs, FEC)</li>
<li>Impressive track record of being able to deliver on complex initiatives, solid project management skills and attention to detail.</li>
<li>Flexibility and comfort working on a dynamic, fast-growing effort with minimal documentation and process.</li>
<li>Quick learner. Aptitude to deal with ambiguity, and enthusiasm to help solve difficult issues.</li>
<li>Exceptional communication skills, for collaborating across many participating teams.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Direct experience and familiarity with a variety of syndicated and secondary research sources, specifically in internet, wireless, and/or digital media.
Understand market dynamics, trends, size, segmentation, customer needs, applicable and emerging opportunities, and competitive landscape.
Experience defining market requirements for consumer-­facing technology products and services, to include target segments, competitive analysis, and industry trends.
Demonstrated experience designing and executing empirical consumer digital data behavior surveys &amp; monitoring campaigns. 
Deep understanding of “last-mile” consumer device connectivity methods (DSL, cable, wireless cellular, WiFi/Ethernet, Bluetooth)
Hands-on experience in software development methodologies and working knowledge in one or more programming languages (Java, C/C++, Python, Bash).</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Technical engineering BS required
MS in EE or CS OR MBA preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
