<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113153884">Data Center Shipping and Receiving</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113153884</li>
<li title="Newark, CA, California, United States">Newark, CA, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Assist with all shipping, receiving, storage and distribution activities of the datacenter. Ensures products, parts, or supplies are shipped, distributed, or received in an efficient manner. Takes precautions to secure warehouse contents against loss. Evaluates inventory on hand. Prepares or reviews distribution documents. This is a hands-on position and requires an individual who leads by example. Must maintain safe and healthy work environment.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Understanding of inventory control policies and procedures</li>
<li>Must have a solid understanding in both warehouse standards and shipping/receiving procedures processes</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple shipments and activities concurrently</li>
<li>Basic math and strong interpersonal skills are necessary</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Assist with the shipment or receipt of outgoing or incoming materials, parts, or products.
Maintains accountability for receiving, storing, and delivering all incoming shipments.
Ensures the accuracy of all receiving documents and gathers and matches forms (PO, packing slip, computer printout) relative to receiving activities.
Studies the shipping and receiving processes for effectiveness.
Examines outgoing shipments to ensure shipments meet specifications.
Maintains inventory of shipping materials and supplies.
Suggests improvements to distribution procedures, and acts to improve timeliness or reduce costs.
Tracks and documents all shipping or receiving information for the datacenter.
Prepares outbound parcels and freight in accordance with local, company and legal requirements.
Completes reports for management.
Works with vendors as well as internal customers.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Prefers 3-6 years relevant experience in a large-scale technology warehouse environment</p>
</div></body></html>
