<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113021375">Prototyping Technician</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113021375</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 11, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Touch/Sensor Technology team develops cutting-edge Touch and Sensor solutions and technologies that are central to Apple’s products, including the iPhone, iPad, watch, MacBooks, and more. The key goal of the Sensor Technology team is to enable the world’s best user-experience. New challenges arise everyday that require the sharp problem-solving skills of talented and smart individuals. The team features a collaborative and hands-on environment that fosters engineering excellence, creativity, and innovation. Come, join us in crafting best-in-class solutions!

In this role, you will work with the sensing and imaging incubation engineers to realize prototype concepts that synthesize electrical, mechanical and software components.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have many of the following qualifications:</li>
<li>Mechanical fabrication skills including 3D printing, laser cutting, drilling, turning, milling, lathe, sanding, painting, applying adhesives, and fine-scale assembly</li>
<li>Mechanical design skills including 3D CAD (NX preferred), and CNC (Good to have) Electrical fabrication skills including SMT and through hole soldering, PCB layout, harness and flex assembly</li>
<li>Ability to balance speed and quality of work based on objectives Great interpersonal and communication skills</li>
<li>Excellent troubleshooting skills</li>
<li>A passion for doing the best possible work</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a technician and model maker, your responsibilities will include:

• Modification, fabrication and assembly of prototypes
• Administration of tools and equipments for group use
• Educate users proper use of the tools
• Perform operational test, data collection, data analysis, and fault isolation on systems
and equipment.
• Assists in determining methods or actions to remedy malfunctions
• Procurement and stocking of materials
• Assists in the design, construction, test and use of test equipment
• Facilities organization
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">A two year technical degree or bachelors degree in a technical field and 5+ years of experience assembling, debugging and working with prototyping teams.</p>
</div></body></html>
