<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55247315">Sensor System Architect (EE)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55247315</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Feb. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Design, develop, and launch next-generation Sensor Technologies in Apple products.

The Sensor Technology team develops Sensor solutions and technologies for Apple’s products, including the iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch, MacBooks, and more. The key goal of the Sensor Technology team is to enable the world’s best user-experience. New challenges arise everyday that require the sharp problem-solving skills of talented and smart individuals. The team features a collaborative and hands-on environment that fosters engineering excellence, creativity, and innovation.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Multi-disciplinary understanding of EE, ME, and Physics principles</li>
<li>Familiarity with mechanical design principles, FEA, and advanced materials</li>
<li>Demonstrated experience in modeling complex cross-disciplinary systems</li>
<li>Experience with statistical tolerance analysis in a production setting is a plus</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills and solid teamwork and leadership skills. Proficiency in MATLAB, SPICE, or similar simulation and modeling tools.</li>
<li>Experience with sensor technologies a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">
Develop and maintain comprehensive, cross-functional sensor system models
Feature definition, block-level simulation, and spec authorship of sensor modules
Development and negotiation of cross-functional requirements to ensure module performance Development of detailed module architecture specifications
Analyze engineering and production data sets in order to reconcile system models
Work closely with firmware team to develop advanced algorithms to ensure module performance Work closely with mechanical engineering team in optimizing material and mechanical design trades Author regular technical communication for executive and cross-functional briefings
Design analysis, characterization, and validation.
Business travel to support product development</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• M.S. or PhD in Electrical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Physics or industry experience equivalent.</p>
</div></body></html>
