<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53940748">Siri Data Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53940748</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, spoken language, big data and artificial intelligence. Work with the creators of the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking. Join the Siri team at Apple.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Exceptional programming skills - Java and/or Scala development experience is necessary.  Strong scripting ability in Scala / Python / Bash</li>
<li>2+ years of Spark and Hadoop applications development using MapReduce framework experience.</li>
<li>Experience in the development and maintenance of tools for analyzing and processing large amounts of data.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Work closely with data scientists, analysts and engineers to design and maintain scalable data models and pipelines
Develop and maintain cross-platform ETL processes
Lead development of architecture and standards for a business metric warehouse
Passionate about data and its quality. Implement systems for tracking quality and consistency
Architect, build and launch new data models that provide intuitive analytics to your customers
Design and develop new systems and tools to enable folks to consume and understand data faster</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS in Computer Science or a related field (ideal) or 5+ years experience in developing big data applications.
</p>
</div></body></html>
