<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113188461">Security Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113188461</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking an exceptional Senior Security Engineer with a focus on infrastructure security to lead the innovative Internet Services Organization. This is a technical, hands-on role in a dynamic and fast paced environment. The candidate will need to have a good mixture of technical know-how as well as a background in higher level information security concepts, risk assessment methodologies, and integration of security practices into the development and systems architecture.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Passionate about keeping Apple’s customers safe</li>
<li>Able to articulate technical details and risks to business leaders</li>
<li>Highly collaborative</li>
<li>Enjoys multitasking, organizing and prioritizing complex projects to meet deadlines</li>
<li>Experienced in developing more than one of the following: network-based appliance, web/SaaS service, and advance data analytics</li>
<li>Ability to listen for nuances and dig into details in order to understand systems deeply</li>
<li>Share your breadth of technical knowledge, including security best practices, principles and threat landscape</li>
<li>Shift perspectives to understand the goals and methods of an attacker</li>
<li>Learn about new security technologies and methodologies</li>
<li>Collaborate with other motivated colleagues working towards a similar goal</li>
<li>Act with high ethical standards and integrity</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will:
Be the leader of the security team responsible for Internet Services including: iCloud, iTunes, Maps, and Siri, among other properties
Manage and improve a set of critical security infrastructure services for authentication, logging, scanning, and detection
Design, develop, and implement security controls and tools that improve the defense of Apple internet services infrastructure and applications
Work with engineers to threat model new features and design responsive controls to ensure end-to-end customer protection
Lead cutting-edge security efforts at a scale you’ll only be able to find at Apple
Work cross-functionally with teams throughout Apple on technology and initiatives to enhance security and bring security best practices to our products and services
Develop production infrastructure fixes to complex vulnerabilities
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors in Computer Science or Engineering with an emphasis in Information Security or a related field, or equivalent experience.
</p>
</div></body></html>
