<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-44652928">Siri Text-to-Speech Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 44652928</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking.  Join the Siri Text-to-Speech team at Apple.  
 
The Siri team is looking for exceptionally skilled and creative engineers eager to get involved in hands-on work improving the Siri experience.
 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong background in C++, C, and/or Objective-C</li>
<li>Solid software engineering fundamentals including implementation of algorithms and data structures</li>
<li>Interest, curiosity, and willingness to learn in text-to-speech related areas</li>
<li>Outstanding communication and presentation skills</li>
<li>Experience with speech, text-to-speech, and/or NLP</li>
<li>Experience working with machine learning algorithms</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will join a team that is responsible for creating and powering the voice of Siri. The Siri Text-To-Speech team conducts a wide variety of TTS activities, including software development, linguistic analysis, statistical modeling, signal processing and voice development.  We are looking for a software engineer that has the ability to implement software and solutions for complex products. 
 
Because you will be working closely with engineers from a number of other teams at Apple, we are looking for a team player who thrives in a fast paced environment with rapidly changing priorities.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S or M.S in Computer Science, or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
