<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83999973">Siri Data Scientist</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83999973</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 14, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile and desktop computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking.  Join the Siri team at Apple.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong background in statistics and Bayesian methods.</li>
<li>Fluent in Python.  Familiar with numpy and Pandas.</li>
<li>Comfortable with SQL.</li>
<li>Experience with Tableau, Druid/Superset, or similar.</li>
<li>Familiarity with big data (MapReduce, Spark, Pig, or similar) desirable.</li>
<li>Experience with survey design theory or item response theory desirable.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Siri is powered by sophisticated algorithms and lots of data, with a big pinch of personality thrown in for fun. If you are in the engineering, data, and/or ML field, this is where you can do the best work of your life.

The Siri Evaluation team is responsible for envisioning, developing, and managing the tools and techniques used to evaluate Siri’s quality. You will literally help us redefine what success looks like for Siri.

You will work in an exciting high performance computing environment, with petabytes of data, millions of queries per second, and have an opportunity to wield significant influence on the features that delight our customers every day.

Specific Responsibilities:
Construction and validation of assessment instruments
Design and analysis of experiments and experimental results
Working with external teams to decrease bias and increase repeatability of their evaluation tools and techniques
Communicating results to leadership</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Degree in Statistics, quantitative usability research (i.e. not an HCI designer), similar field, or equivalent experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
