<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-39041878">GPU Silicon Validation Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 39041878</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 10, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Graphics Silicon Validation Team is responsible for validating the functional behavior, electrical behavior, power, and performance of Apple's embedded GPU processors.  Team members are involved in test planning, test execution, data analysis, failure triage, and tool development.  We work hand-in-hand with the design, verification, hardware and software teams to achieve Apple's goal of delivering an outstanding experience to our customers.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>6 plus years of experience in silicon validation in a system environment</li>
<li>Strong experience debugging SOC hardware and software issues</li>
<li>Strong scripting skills (TCL, Expect, Python, Bash)</li>
<li>Strong written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Intermediate experience in C-programming</li>
<li>Intermediate understanding of SOC, CPU, or GPU Architecture</li>
<li>Intermediate understanding of PVT effects</li>
<li>Experience with CPU or GPU power and performance measurements is desirable</li>
<li>Lab skills (operation of lab equipment, interested and able to work in the lab)</li>
<li>Ability to work well on a team, but to be responsible and self-driven</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Develop and execute silicon bring-up/validation test plans
• Triage SOC fails and debug underlying embedded GPU issues
• Port, maintain, and continue to develop silicon test environment
• Develop automation to improve the productivity and efficiency of the team
• Run tests on silicon across multiple parts, voltages, frequencies
• Review coverage of existing tests with design/pre-silicon DV team
• Track and report progress toward test plan goals against aggressive milestones
• Drive new silicon feature testing methodology, tools, and flows
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• BS/MS/PhD CE, EE, or CS</p>
</div></body></html>
