<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-48830605">Software Pattern Recognition Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 48830605</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Are you interested in applying your knowledge of computer vision and machine learning algorithms to develop a magical user experience? Would you like to be part of the team who built the capture technology for iTunes Gift Cards, as well as the Credit Card Scanning experience for Apple Pay? The Core Recognition team is looking for an exceptional engineer to help create the next generation of pattern recognition tools and solutions for both iOS and macOS.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Significant experience leveraging and developing vision-based recognition systems.</li>
<li>Intimate knowledge and experience developing statistical pattern recognition and machine learning algorithms</li>
<li>Exceptional problem solving, critical thinking and communication skills</li>
<li>Strong programming, debugging and design skills</li>
<li>Programming experience with C, C++, Objective-C and familiarity within Unix/Linux development environments</li>
<li>Familiarity with scripting languages such as Python or Perl</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Core Recognition team is looking for a candidate with exceptional experience developing modern computer vision solutions. We are seeking an engineer who will be responsible for prototyping new features, contributing to the overall design and architecture of future components and improving existing codebases. Ideal candidates must have significant experience and low-level knowledge of image-based pattern recognition systems. Expertise in neural networks and other statistical pattern recognition systems as well as experience managing large datasets is a plus.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Ph.D. or M.S. in Computer Science, Computer Engineering or a closely related field.
</p>
</div></body></html>
