<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113026338">Procurement Specialist</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113026338</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">• Identify and prioritize project tasks and risks
• Support various sourcing and supply projects by providing relevant data analytics and recommendations.
• Support the development of long range strategic sourcing plans to reduce total costs, optimize value from suppliers, and meet internal customer requirements.
• Coordinate project reviews; communicating project status and top engineering issues to project team and management
• Coordinate design process to ensure design meets intended project goals
• Coordinate and delegate incoming procurement requests from all employees.
• Drive suppliers / vendors, integrating their deliverables and schedules into project
• Partner with internal and external stakeholders to capture and develop key requirements and work to direct into appropriate buying channels in order to extract maximum value. 
• Lead and manage special projects to ensure procurement objectives are being met; collaborate with procurement team and business unit stakeholders</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>• 5+ combined experience in procurement.</li>
<li>• Excellent communication, organizational skills</li>
<li>• Ability to filter and distill relevant information for the right audience</li>
<li>• Self motivated and proactive with demonstrated creative and critical thinking skills</li>
<li>• Understands and deals well with rapid development cycles; remains flexible and calm in the face of ambiguity</li>
<li>• Detailed knowledge and understanding of product development processes </li>
<li>• Detailed project tracking and track record of meeting deliverables</li>
<li>• Experience interfacing with operations team, vendors and contractors</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Procurement Specialist within Apple’s Special Projects organization, you will be responsible for managing project schedules, budgets, and vendors. We are a group of self-starters, capable of providing on-site leadership with an eye for detail. We have a solid track record of delivering projects on time while exemplifying the utmost attention to quality. Candidate will work in close collaboration with various cross-functional engineering and design teams, vendors, and contractors.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">* BS Degree with 5-10 years of direct experience required</p>
</div></body></html>
