<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57501592">Hardware Design Validation Engineer - Apple Watch</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57501592</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 11, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Watch team is looking for a Hardware Design Validation Engineer. This person will be part of the Apple Watch hardware team with responsibilities for the Validation and test of analog and digital sub-systems on the next generation Apple Watch.   </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>This position will require close cooperation with the various hardware and software cross functional teams including core OS, QA, Silicon Engineering, Test, Operations, Reliability, etc.</li>
<li>This position requires excellent verbal and written communication skills and the ability to adapt and learn new skills quickly.</li>
<li>3+ years overall experience in HW/SW development. </li>
<li>Electrical signal characterization experience in one or more of the following areas: DDR, PCIe, USB, MIPI, audio, DC/DC convertors, I2C/SPI/UART busses. </li>
<li>Software development experience in one or more of Python, C/C++, Perl, Ruby, etc.</li>
<li>Experience working in a laboratory environment with oscilloscopes, multimeters, lab power supplies and other validation test equipment.</li>
<li>Good understanding of EE fundamentals.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Duties will include: 
- Develop HW validation plans with design teams. 
- Automate tests at the board and system level. 
- Functional and electrical verification of Watch subsystems. 
- Debug test and manufacturing issues at factory. 
- Reporting validation status. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Minimum Bachelors in Electrical Engineering or equivalent is required. </p>
</div></body></html>
