<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-58007347">Software Engineer - Algorithms/R&amp;D Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 58007347</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join the Apple Maps team in the R&amp;D branch to shape the future of Apple Maps. We create and seamlessly integrate technologies that enrich people’s lives with a focus on user-experience. If you're passionate about building technologies that are going to make a difference in the future,  we would like to talk to you! </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Background in mathematics and/or statistics is highly desirable</li>
<li>Strong analytical and problem solving skills</li>
<li>Hands-on programming skills in a major language, such as C++ or Java</li>
<li>Hands-on knowledge of prototyping languages, such as MATLAB or Python with NumPy/SciPy libraries</li>
<li>Ability to take ideas from concept to prototype and to the software product</li>
<li>Ability to work in cross-functional teams with a strong sense of self-direction</li>
<li>Pro-active attitude</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will be a key member of a team that is pursuing future products of Apple maps. In that role, you will be expected to think out-of-the box, investigate a set of research hypotheses and shape them into a meaningful definition that can be demonstrated with a prototype and subsequently implemented in a production-grade code. The problem space may include various numerical methods, machine learning, 3D geometry and/or routing algorithms.  </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">- M.S. or PhD in Computer Science or related field such as Mathematics, Statistics, Physics or Electrical Engineering. </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Preferred, but not necessary:
- Familiarity with Geo Spatial data or computational geometry
- Numerical methods, machine learning, routing algorithms, big data, computer vision or computational geometry</p>
</div></body></html>
