<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113051457">Asset Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113051457</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 28, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The role of the Internet Service Organization Asset Lifecycle Team at Apple is to ensure flawless data accuracy and execution of world-class equipment deployment for Apple Owned and Remote Data Centers in support of Apple’s business goals. As a member of the Apple’s Internet Service Organization this person holds responsibility for large scale ordering of Equipment Data Operations.

This role is responsible for overseeing all logistical order operations and delivery, including reporting analysis, order processing  and managing project delivery planning efforts designed to align resources for strategic priorities.

Ensuring the relationship and support of our internal and external stakeholders and equipment vendors. Contributes high levels of team collaboration and performance in addition to driving supplier performance and contractual adherence in line with Apple’s outsourcing strategy.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li> Formulates and implements processes, procedures and systems for tracking and analyzing software, hardware, and equipment from requisition through retirement.</li>
<li> Account for the IT assets throughout the enterprise utilizing tools to manage all assets within the organization and affiliated department.</li>
<li> Manage acquisition of assets from planning through deployment.</li>
<li> Verify, enter, and adjust equipment IT asset management data in a variety of forms, schedules, and reports.</li>
<li> Track entire life-cycle management for each asset in order to maintain warranty information, -refresh date, and end of life data information.</li>
<li> Work directly with the administrator(s) to maintain inventory accuracy.</li>
<li> Develop written plans, policies, and procedures to document processes to support the asset management lifecycle.</li>
<li> Conduct inventory audit(s) and develop process and procedures to ensure accuracy.</li>
<li> Develop and implement eWaste policies and procedures.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline"> Specific experience evaluating, developing and implementing infrastructure solutions.
 Experience in scoping, planning and managing complex and concurrent technical activities supported by a strong understanding of IT project management; demonstrated ability to manage scope, timeline, and budget; PMP certification a plus.
 Experience with business requirements gathering and analysis.
 Understanding of information processing principles and practices.
 Experience developing business cases and negotiating with cross-functional teams

Personal Attributes

 Proven ability to translate business requirements into technical solutions.
 Strong analytical and problem-solving skills; resourceful and capable of working in the abstract, with the ability to understand multiple facets of complex technologies.
 Experience leading the deployment of complex solutions involving multiple vendor technologies.
 Effective facilitator of technical decisions; comfortable with working through ambiguous initiatives to develop effective solutions.
 Excellent written, presentation, and verbal communication skills with experience communicating complex, technical concepts to all levels.
 Solid relationship management skills interacting horizontally and vertically across organizations.
 Ability to effectively prioritize and execute tasks in high-pressure environment.
 Exceptional customer service orientation.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/BA from an accredited university or equivalent work experience</p>
</div></body></html>
