<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113205801">Manager International Transaction Taxes</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113205801</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking a Manager International Transaction Taxes based in the Santa Clara or Austin to provided international tax law analysis for Apple’s various business offerings and initiatives.  The ideal candidate will operate as a business partner and be comfortable working closely with various business teams and software engineers in order to gain a deep understanding of Apple’s various products and offerings, including hardware and media products, along with the supporting financial systems.  Using this deep understanding the candidate will help develop taxability determinations, design related tax requirements that clearly articulates the taxability requirements, and drive the implementation of the tax transaction tax solution.  Area of responsibility is the non-Americas regions.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Deep knowledge (5+ years of experience) of indirect tax in at least one non-Americas jurisdiction;</li>
<li>Working knowledge of non-America’s indirect tax;</li>
<li>Knowledge of Vertex, Taxware, Thomson Reuters, etc. a plus.</li>
<li>Strong tax research and analytical skills;</li>
<li>Able to extract, analyze, and review data and make appropriate recommendations;</li>
<li>Ability to simplify complex modeling and tax issues into high level presentations for business partners;</li>
<li>Experience working in a large multinational or a professional services firm; </li>
<li>Exposure to or basic knowledge of transaction tax calculation and compliance software highly beneficial;</li>
<li>Hard working, quicker learner with a positive ''can do'' attitude and solid professionalism;</li>
<li>Able to work in a fast paced, informal, and often ambiguous environment;</li>
<li>Must be a self-starter who is able to work independently and interface with all relevant internal teams and external business partners is needed;</li>
<li>Strong organizational, interpersonal, communication, and project management skills;</li>
<li>Ability to communicate clearly and concisely with all levels of management; and</li>
<li>Some travel domestically and internationally.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Primary job duties:

Reviewing new business initiatives and scoping any effect on existing transaction tax calculation processes and systems;
Providing transaction tax subject matter expertise to various business and IT organizations and various product groups;
Providing indirect tax calculation requirements for projects and business initiatives, including analyzing product type, taxability, rates, and invoicing for non-America’s countries;
Actively participating in projects throughout their lifecycle – from design, delivery, and ongoing maintenance;
Product taxability research across a wide range of categories for the non-Americas region;
Involvement in general non-Americans indirect tax research related to tax calculation and compliance, and tax collection responsibilities;
Actively participating throughout the indirect tax solutions lifecycle from planning through delivery (including directly or indirectly providing project management support) and ongoing support; and
Collaborate with business units to proactively identify and research non-Americas indirect tax planning opportunities.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Must have BA or BS, preferably in accounting, taxation, or business; JD, CPA or graduate degree in accounting, taxation, or business is a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
