<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113144348">Senior Software Engineer, iTunes Infrastructure</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113144348</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 16, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Senior software engineering for the iTunes Digital Supply Chain Engineering team.

As a member of the Infrastructure team, you will:

Be leading the design, development and deployment of large scale services and platforms
Be a team mate, a leader, a student, and a mentor
Be eager to learn new technologies and solutions
Be curious about how systems work and how they fail, because they always do
Have some cool war stories to tell from your past experience
Believe in automation and testing as a critical part of the software lifecycle
Love measuring all things so we can make the right decisions

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>8-10 years hands on engineering experience</li>
<li>Strong development skills in Java</li>
<li>Experience designing and building distributed systems with strong latency and SLA requirements.</li>
<li>Understands different data storage solutions and when to use them (e.g. RDBMS, Cassandra, Redis, Solr, etc.)</li>
<li>Understands large scale data pipelines and when to use them (e.g. Kafka, Storm, Samza)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">iTunes has been leading the digital media industry by constantly developing innovative features since its launch in April 2003.  We are looking for a self starting, energetic individual who is not afraid to question assumptions and with excellent written and oral communication skills.  You will be developing mission critical infrastructure that will impact millions of users.  The ability to be a good team player and the ability to tackle problems with imaginative solutions are keys to success in this position.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science, Mathematics, or EE, or relevant industry experience is required. MS in Computer Science or related technical field is desired.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Preferred:
- Experience with Cassandra</p>
</div></body></html>
