<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-86229088">User Experience Designer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 86229088</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">From ideation through implementation, you'll work with content creators and engineers to define the best user experience for developer documentation. Understanding and empathizing with the Apple developer mindset, you'll work through scenarios faced by developers as part of their learning process and define solutions that help them find answers with greater ease. You'll work with engineers to build and test those solutions and polish them to the last pixel.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>UI/UX design experience</li>
<li>An ability to quickly grasp and distill highly complex concepts and interactions into visuals</li>
<li>Fluency in Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Keynote and other design tools</li>
<li>Fluency in Axure or other interaction prototyping tools</li>
<li>Familiarity with creating and conducting usability testing and distilling meaningful results from the data</li>
<li>A passion for polishing pixels</li>
<li>Enthusiasm for an iterative design process, driven by group critique</li>
<li>Outstanding written and verbal communication skills, and ability to present work to groups</li>
<li>Excellent collaboration skills</li>
<li>Familiarity with HTML &amp; CSS is a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsibilities

• Help define the UI and UX for how we display developer documentation

• Create use-case driven scenarios for developer documentation to understand pain points and inspire solutions

• Take an iterative approach to design with rapid cycles of design sprints, prototyping, and usability testing

• Work closely with engineers to define the design and behavior of each feature and provide feedback during the feature's implementation

• Align UI and visual design language with existing design standards defined for Apple's platforms

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA Degree in Graphic Design, Visual Communications, or other design field, or relevant industry experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
