<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-50834584">Camera Electrical Architect - Camera Hardware</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 50834584</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is responsible for the design, development, and innovation of camera hardware for all related Apple products. Our target is to deliver superior camera hardware to enable best-in-class camera user experience.  

We are looking for an enthusiastic, high energy individual who can help us with tomorrow’s challenges.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10+ years relevant experience</li>
<li>Demonstrated excellence in imaging system architecting and engineering</li>
<li>Expertise in high speed, low power design, data analysis and design trade-offs</li>
<li>Broad knowledge of camera module, image sensor, AF/OIS, electrical interface, material, packaging, process, image pipeline and ISP</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills to work with all levels of the organization</li>
<li>Self-motivated and proactive with critical thinking capability</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Major responsibilities:
Investigate forward-looking technologies and features for camera HW
Define electrical interface and architecture for new camera modules
Author camera sub-system electrical requirements and specifications
Build prototype hardware to experiment with new concepts
Develop robust camera sub-system integration solutions</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS in Electrical Engineering or industrial experience equivalent.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Multi-disciplinary understanding of optical, mechanical and thermal designs
Experience in using Matlab and/or other simulation tools
Occasional travel will be required</p>
</div></body></html>
