<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56309388">Camera Image Quality Field Test Engineer – Camera Hardware</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56309388</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Mar. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is seeking a talented and experienced Image Quality Field Test Engineer to coordinate, execute, and analyze objective image quality tests and subjective image quality benchmark studies. This is your chance to join a team dedicated to continuous improvement of the world’s most popular cameras.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years experience testing image quality of camera systems</li>
<li>Matlab skills related to digital image processing and data analysis</li>
<li>Proven experience in automation using Python or other scripting  languages</li>
<li>Expertise in executing and analyzing objective and subjective image quality tests</li>
<li>Familiarity with camera optics, image sensor technology, and experience with ISP algorithms (AE, AWB, AF,, etc.)</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communications skills</li>
<li>Presentation experience with cross functional teams</li>
<li>Ability to pick up new technologies quickly and self motivation to expand technical knowledge</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will work closely with Hardware and Software development teams focused on developing new camera technologies. You have a strong aptitude for learning new technologies, gaining in-depth knowledge of how new systems function and are comfortable working in a fast-paced environment. Additionally, you’ll design, create, and run manual and automated tests. Developing and fostering partnerships with cross-functional teams is key to long-term success.

Develop/execute objective image quality lab tests of camera systems
Analyze subjective image and video data captured in the field
Create reports and deliver executive level presentations of results to SW/HW teams
Perform tests related to product benchmark studies
Identify, reproduce, and isolate bugs found via image and video analysis 
Contribute to the continued automation of test setups</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in Engineering, Photo Science, or Computer Science</p>
</div></body></html>
