<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113184561">Engineering Program Manager, Hardware Technologies Exploratory Design</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113184561</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this critical, highly visible role, you will manage programs involving architecture scoping, prototyping, design, integration and validation of cutting-edge technologies for Health platform. You will play a key part in providing Apple customers with the best user-experience in the industry by driving the development and deployment of next-generation technologies spanning cross-functional teams of Technology, Module, SW, and System. The Hardware Technologies team features a collaborative environment with creative, smart people and cutting-edge technologies. Engineering excellence is expected and encouraged.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Typically requires 5-10+ years of technical experience, and at least 1+ years of program management experience. Individuals with more experience, can take on additional responsibilities.</li>
<li>Technical background (e.g. semiconductor materials, silicon photonics, optics, EE, etc) with first-hand knowledge of any of cross-functional core competencies</li>
<li>Excellent communication, organizational and leadership skills</li>
<li>Ability to filter and distill relevant information for the right audience and is data driven</li>
<li>Self-motivated and proactive with demonstrated creative and critical thinking capabilities</li>
<li>Great leadership skills and ability to inspire team members</li>
<li>Understands and deals well with rapid development cycles; remains flexible and calm in the face of uncertainty</li>
<li>Teamwork: the candidate must be able to fit in well with a team, understand capabilities and priorities while fostering a collaborative environment</li>
<li>Limited international travel may be required</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Lead cross-functional teams including Electrical, Process and Software Engineering to deliver state-of-the-art solutions
•Define the program plan/schedule and manage program execution
•Deliver executive communication/presentations and drive the decision-making process
•Ensure tight inter-team coordination and communication
•Effectively and consistently communicate overall program status
•Identify and resolve conflicts, inter-dependencies and program issues quickly and efficiently
•Improve the system: Look for patterns, offer best practices and implement change

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS or BS Degree in technical discipline
</p>
</div></body></html>
