<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113186839">Planning &amp; Forecasting Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113186839</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join the Channel Training &amp; People Programs team and help us build the operational foundation that enable us to create amazing content and programs for our global sales organization. Innovation at Apple doesn’t live just in the products that we create—it is part of everything that we do. And we are seeking a talented Planning &amp; Forecasting Manager that can bring innovation to operational planning, budgeting, &amp; forecasting.

You will play a critical role in improving our team’s planning and forecasting model — leveraging the appropriate mix of technology and process redesign to increase our team’s efficiency and accuracy in how we manage our business. Key projects will involve budget planning, delivery planning, new product introduction readiness, and training unit management.

Another important goal for this role is to model the cost of our training initiatives (e.g., content localization and delivery, in-person assessments, and events) into our larger strategy—so we can better plan execution at both worldwide and regional levels. You will do so in partnership with Channel Training &amp; People Programs, regional training teams, channel program teams, and Apple Finance.

As our budget manager, you will be a key point of contact between our team and Apple Finance, and will work with both teams to ensure that our team is on track and making the best possible use of every dollar invested by Apple in the development of our training programs. 

Your work will support training initiatives at a global scale, with a direct impact in our channel’s ability to properly support our customers.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ability to lead multiple projects and adapt to a global, dynamic environment</li>
<li>Ability to effectively solve problems and prioritize your workload</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to build effective business partnerships</li>
<li>Must be able to exercise good judgment and discretion within Apple’s policies</li>
<li>Comfortable working with multiple team managers across multiple business functions</li>
<li>Advanced experience with Microsoft Excel</li>
<li>Proficient with financial databases, SAP preferred</li>
<li>Other financial systems &amp; tools experience a plus, including Filemaker Pro and Tableau</li>
<li>Technical aptitude with database management and analysis</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">-  Partner with our internal team, Apple Finance, Business Process Reengineering (BPR) and, if needed, external vendors — to identify gaps in our planning and forecasting process and to implement solutions to improve our team’s efficiency and accuracy through a re-design of our process, new technologies, or both.

-  Perform the role of budget coordinator, consolidating and tracking the Channel Training &amp; People Programs budget forecasts and spend against our targets, and provide analytical support to our teams in order to identify risks and opportunities

-  Partner with Apple Finance, regional training teams, Localization Shared Services, Channel Sales Programs, and other Apple teams to model the cost of training initiatives into our global programs

-  Work with content design team and Localization Shared Services to model the cost of localization into our planning process and improve its accuracy over time

-  Partner with our internal stakeholders and authorized requestor to create and track purchase orders—including approvals of purchase requisitions, receipting, and addressing questions from vendors

-  Develop reports to handle forecasting and budgeting of all vendor expenses and analyze expenses and provide a status of PO spend to budget on a monthly and quarterly basis.

-  Manage our training equipment forecasting and ordering process in partnership with our internal stakeholders and the WorldWide Readiness team.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/BA in Accounting, Finance, Economics, or equivalent work experience


Apple is an Equal Employment Opportunity Employer that is committed to inclusion and diversity. We also take affirmative action to offer employment and advancement opportunities to all applicants, including minorities, women, protected veterans, and individuals with disabilities. 

</p>
</div></body></html>
