<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57442432">DC Architectural Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57442432</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple seeks an AutoCAD and Revit Operator with significant experience in large construction projects to assist with creating plans and drawings for mission critical data center facilities. This position will have a focus on IT related systems such as server rack layouts, cable tray diagrams, cable distribution details and rack elevation drawings. The CAD Operator will work closely with our Architects and Design Team to create accurate engineered drawing packages and Revit models for new “greenfield” sites, as well as existing locations and expansions. These models will include civil, structural, electrical, mechanical and IT infrastructure details to optimize building designs and avoid collisions. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ Years experience with AutoCAD</li>
<li>5+ Years experience in construction related field (mission critical/ data center facilities)</li>
<li>2+ Years experience in related industries (electrical, mechanical, IT design)</li>
<li>Working knowledge and experience with Revit, SolidWorks, NavisWorks, 360 BIM</li>
<li>Familiarity with IT/ Network Infrastructure design (outside plant, conduit routing, cable tray layouts etc)</li>
<li>Ability to read and understand architectural and engineering drawings and plans</li>
<li>Knowledge of AutoCAD for MAC a plus</li>
<li>Working knowledge or MS Office, Visio, Autodesk and MAC software</li>
<li>Basic understanding of architectural, structural, mechanical, IT and electrical design</li>
<li>Strong organizational skills a must</li>
<li>Ability to multi-task under tight schedules, manage time and workload</li>
<li>Team Player, ready to work within a very fast paced and high pressure environment</li>
<li>Self Motivated, detail oriented, energetic, punctual, reliable, independent </li>
<li>Must be able to sit (or stand at an ergonomic workstation) for prolonged periods of time in front of computer monitor</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Develop thorough understanding of the current “Design Team” standards and base design criteria
Create accurate site plans and detailed drawings in a timely manner using AutoCAD, Revit, Solidworks, Navisworks, PDF etc.
Revise and update drawings and plans based on red lines and feedback from Design Team and other partners
Review and confirm accuracy of drawings and plans provided by 3rd party partners
Assist with creating new standards for Design Packages to be issued for construction
Provide support for multiple projects concurrently 
Organize and manage drawing packages and records for completed projects
Plot drawing sets, provide plotter maintenance
Provide leadership and guidance to other CAD Operators
Work closely with construction team and contractors on BIM coordination
Communicate with management regarding updates, schedules and issues
Perform site surveys as needed to create “as built”documentation
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Technical degree and/ or diploma in drafting</p>
</div></body></html>
