<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83938068">Data Infrastructure Engineer, Siri Search</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83938068</li>
<li title="SF - Corporate, California, United States">SF - Corporate, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Siri Search team is creating groundbreaking technology for algorithmic search, machine learning, natural language processing, and artificial intelligence. The features we create are redefining how hundreds of millions of people use their computers and mobile devices to search and find what they are looking for. Siri’s universal search engine powers search features across a variety of Apple products, including Siri, Spotlight, Safari, Messages and Lookup. As part of this group, you will work with one of the most exciting high performance computing environments, with petabytes of data, millions of queries per second, and have an opportunity to imagine and build products that delight our customers every day. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5 years minimum of experience writing high-performance server software on Linux/Unix</li>
<li>3 years minimum of experience working with large datasets  </li>
<li>Mastery of two of following languages: C++, Python, Java, Perl, Go  </li>
<li>Practical experience with Hadoop and extensive experience w/ SQL and NoSQL databases </li>
<li>2 years minimum experience with data transformation pipelines </li>
<li>Experience with large scale search and machine learning systems a plus</li>
<li>Thorough knowledge of HTTP </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Internet Software &amp; Services organization is seeking a Sr Software Engineer who will play a central role in the delivery of Big Data, Machine Learning &amp; Search based Internet services.  As a member of our fast-paced group, you’ll have the unique and rewarding opportunity to shape upcoming products from Apple.  We are looking for people with experience in creating high performance Linux/Unix server side software and data processing pipelines. 

This role will have the following responsibilities:
-Architect &amp; develop Internet-scale server software for Linux systems
-Develop methods and software to process petabyte-scale datasets
-Work alone or as part of small team to deliver complete systems   
-Work closely with operations and project management teams </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master's Degree in Computer Science or Computer Engineering, or equivalent work experience 

</p>
</div></body></html>
