<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53873843">Text-to-Speech Language Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53873843</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Dec. 1, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking.  Join the Siri Speech team at Apple.  

The Siri team is looking for exceptionally skilled and creative engineers eager to get involved in hands-on work improving the Siri experience.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience building, testing, and tuning pronunciation, normalization and/or other text processing models</li>
<li>Ability to implement experiments using scripting languages (Python, bash) and tools written in C/C++</li>
<li>Experience working with standard modeling toolkits (such as Theano or Torch)</li>
<li>Ability to create, analyze and optimize voice talent recording scripts and other text corpora for areas such as phonetic and prosodic coverage</li>
<li>Solid understanding of phonetic notation such as IPA, SAMPA or CMU</li>
<li>5 years experience working in speech recognition, text-to-speech or related fields</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The Siri Text-to-Speech team is looking for Language R&amp;D Engineers to take part in building the voice of Siri.  In over 30 languages, you will create models used in TTS text processing, develop and fine tune voice talent recording scripts for optimal coverage, take part in the recording of Siri voices and finally, assist in the execution of quality and accuracy evaluations.  You will implement your ideas directly in our TTS engine or tools and hundreds of millions of users will experience your contributions through more natural and expressive Siri voices.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Masters degree or higher in Computer Science, Computational Linguistics or related field

</p>
</div></body></html>
