<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54667232">Senior Data Scientist, Universal Media</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54667232</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple Universal Media is seeking an outstanding lead data scientist to drive the next generation knowledge graph powering Apple’s media and sports discovery. 


</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>7+ years experience working with data science projects </li>
<li>Hands-on experience with NLP, mining of structured, semi-structured and unstructured data</li>
<li>Experience working with large scale data sets</li>
<li>Experience with  Solr/ Lucene, Cassandra and related technologies </li>
<li>Experience with machine learning tools and libraries such as Spark</li>
<li>Intuitive understanding of machine learning algorithms, supervised and unsupervised modeling techniques </li>
<li>Obsessed with quality </li>
<li>Strong communication skills </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are seeking an outstanding applied data scientist to join the Universal Media Team responsible for building a comprehensive knowledge graph for powering Apple's TV App, Siri, Safari search and discovery services across all Apple platforms. Candidate should be a self starting, energetic individual with excellent communication skills to effectively collaborate with all levels of the organization. She/ He will take ownership of projects that focus on topics such as classification, attribute ranking, filtering, mapping or enriching of entity records or their data. Implement standard and proprietary algorithms for handling and processing data. Use distributed data processing and analysis methodologies. Work closely with engineers to implement solutions to the highest standard possible. 

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Masters or PhD in Computer Science, Statistics or related field</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Great to Have

Server side Java development experience
Experience Ranking entities or attributes
Experience with Catalogs generation and Mapping techniques
Knowledge of Graph databases
Multimodal learning application
</p>
</div></body></html>
