<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-58207047">Product Design Engineer - Packaging</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 58207047</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">
 At Apple, the customer experience extends beyond the product itself. Every aspect of product interaction plays a crucial role in creating the customer experience, and the very first one that is often encountered is Packaging. Apple packaging is the first time that many people contemplate and experience delight in the unboxing experience. There is a universal joy in unboxing Apple products, and that experience is designed and created by a world-class team that is continually pushing the boundaries of engineering and technology. 

Apple is looking for a product design engineer to join the Packaging group. This engineer will be responsible for the exploration and implementation of new and innovative designs in the packaging of all Apple products. The position will span from technology development and concept generation to detailed design, analysis and testing through mass production ramp. The position will require close cooperation with cross-functional stakeholders throughout Apple, and collaboration with multiple design teams within Apple. In addition, the job will require interaction with suppliers and periodic travel to sites both within and outside of the USA. 

The successful candidate will need to have knowledge in many areas including materials selection, manufacturing processes (paper folding, molded fiber, CNC, die-cutting, thermoforming, injection molding), textiles, cosmetic detailing, testing, etc. The candidate should be extremely well organized; able to manage multiple, complex, dynamic, interrelated packaging programs. The candidate should be an excellent communicator who is able to quickly grasp issues and drive them to resolution. They must be able to interface with other departments and all levels of management within Apple and its partners. An
ability to work in a quickly changing environment and to be a creative problem solver is a must.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>       ▪the candidate should have 2+ years of experience in mechanical engineering, packaging engineering, or similar</li>
<li>▪the candidate must have experience working in a team environment and be self motivated to identify and close design issues</li>
<li>▪the ability to articulate design issues in quantitative terms both verbally and with documentation is required</li>
<li>▪experience designing parts and assemblies for high volume manufacturing and experience supporting production ramp is valued</li>
<li>▪computer industry experience not required, serious consideration will be given to qualified candidates from medical, consumer electronics, automotive, aerospace, sporting goods, footwear, outdoor industry, and other fields with relevant technology and development models</li>
<li>▪an understanding of tolerance analysis, statistics &amp; process control</li>
<li>▪able to drive people/groups for quality, schedule and design both internally and externally</li>
<li>▪CAD design experience using both 2D and 3D applications (Siemens NX and Artios CAD preferred)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Developing initial packaging design layouts and new technology concepts
Mechanism design
Model/prototype building to prove function, manufacturability, and robustness
Analyze data generated from builds and lab experiments
Partner with industrial design team on concepts and detailed design
Support technology investigation and development
Generating and accepting constructive feedback in brainstorming and design review forums
Perform tolerance analyses to verify performance of mechanisms and cosmetic specifications in the presence of high volume dimensional variation
Detailed design and 2D documentation of all parts and assemblies
Interacting with vendors to develop manufacturing processes and tooling concepts
Travel to support build activities including finding root cause for failures and solutions for issues that impede build progress
Work with operations teams to evaluate and develop supply chains capable of manufacturing new subsystems and products define testing requirements and equipment
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSME preferred MSME</p>
</div></body></html>
