<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113208848">Siri Designer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113208848</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Siri design team is looking for inventive interaction and voice designers who are ready to apply their expertise to the exciting challenges of conversational interaction design. This is a unique opportunity to shape the intelligence and interaction model behind consumer products that radically change how people use technology. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>4+ years work experience in interaction design for consumer products</li>
<li>Master's degree in HCI, Interaction Design, or related discipline, or Bachelor's degree with extensive work experience</li>
<li>Demonstrated experience in articulating, negotiating, and refining design solutions with stakeholders</li>
<li>Demonstrated experience collaborating with software engineers and other development team members</li>
<li>Excellent visual, written, and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Strong abilities in sketching, mocking up, and evaluating interaction design</li>
<li>A strong portfolio demonstrating both personal and team-based work</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Siri designers apply a broad range of user experience design skills to envision, design, and specify conversational behaviors. They analyze content domains, create scenarios and use cases, define verbal query patterns, determine interaction flows, create design specifications, and write Siri responses. And they work collaboratively on multi-disciplinary, cross-functional teams with people from speech, natural language, human interface, server and client engineering, localization, editorial, marketing, project management,  data science and other specialties. 

Experience with conversational interaction design and its related technologies (natural language understanding, speech recognition, dialog generation, and speech synthesis) is highly desirable. Ideal candidates also have considerable experience designing for mobile devices and services, and are adept at synthesizing requirements, constraints, and multiple points of view to create useful and delightful conversational experiences.

Finally, candidates must be able to advocate for design at all stages of the work and at all organizational levels, and demonstrate a history of close and productive collaboration with software engineers and engineering managers.

Desired Experience:

Solid experience designing voice-operated user interfaces or conversational agents
Expertise in qualitative user research methods and research analysis
Expertise in creating, conducting, and analyzing usability evaluations
Interactive prototyping skills
Technical writing and communications design
Fluency in one or more non-English languages

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master's degree in HCI or related discipline; or Bachelor's degree with extensive work experience
</p>
</div></body></html>
