<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83643580">Advanced Manufacturing Engineer - Mac</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83643580</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 29, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong working knowledge of precision assembly, inspection and automation equipment </li>
<li>Required to understand and create tolerance analysis for parts and assemblies </li>
<li>Knowledgable in creating machine qualification requirements, design of experiments and  failure analysis </li>
<li>Understands machine qualification including calibration, correlation, capability, repeatability  and reproducibility </li>
<li>Able to communicate effectively in a worldwide environment </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsible for designing precision assembly and measurement processes for Apple products. Perform the research and development on new technologies necessary to solve complex assembly and automation problems that have direct impact to the quality and delivery of Apple products. Design, implement and successfully scale automated and semi-automated solutions based upon sound engineering principles and the technologies developed for a specific application. 

Develop new and or improved processes through the application of theoretical and practical engineering 
Keeps abreast of all relevant technical trends and developments and incorporates them in appropriate assignments 
Provide direction and guidance to third party machine/automation suppliers and/or CM’s; be the technical leader and driver on owned projects; serve as a technical resource to other engineering groups and project leaders 
Organize cross-functional reviews of the machine requirements, design, qualification and capability 
Create Request for Quotation/Proposal (RFQ/RFPs) that documents the design requirements of the automated equipment, delivery schedule, required documentation and qualification for acceptance at machine supplier facility and contract manufacturer’s factory 
Engage machine suppliers for automated equipment design reviews and proposals 
Travel to the machine supplier and contract manufacturer for equipment bring-up,  qualification, acceptance testing and support during build events 
Drive machine qualification including correlation, process capability (CP/CPK) and Gage  Repeatability / Reproducibility (GR&amp;R) 
Drive failure analysis and machine issue resolution, working with the machine supplier and  contract manufacturer 
Run equipment experiments to bound the capability of the machine 
Responsible for data analysis reports to communicate machine capability to the cross  functional teams 
Performs assignments in several of the following manufacturing engineering functions:
Design for Manufacturability - Provide early and on going manufacturing involvement to  ensure new products are mechanically manufacturable. 
Product Engineering - Works all phases of a product from concept to repeat manufacturing  to end of life. Provides production support engineering with respect to technically complex  testing methods, procedures and failure analysis. 
Process Engineering - Designs and develops technically complex processes to improve  quality and efficiency. Utilize statistical tools (such as GR&amp;R, SPC and Cp/pCk) to ensure  processes/fixtures are scalable and are continuing to perform properly once qualified. 
Failure/Data Analysis - Plans, develops and implements technically complex procedures for  the testing and evaluation of soon to be released products. Specifies test to be performed, compiles data and makes recommendations for product design changes and final assembly standards. This will include the use of Design of Experiments (DOE) and statistical analysis using Six Sigma principles. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSME or equivalent (MSME desired), with 5 plus years in an engineering role with experience in automation equipment used for alignment, assembly and/or measurement of components. 
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">New product introduction and Manufacturing Operations experience desired 
Proven track record of cost reduction, project management and engineering design required 
Working knowledge of GD&amp;T principles favorable 
NX, SolidWorks CAD or ProE experiences a plus 
Knowledge of optics principles as they relate to CCD cameras, 2D and 1D lasers, and their  use for positioning and critical alignment machines 
Basic understanding of liquid adhesives, PSA’s and VHB’s a plus 
Working knowledge of robotics (6-axis and/or SCARA), pneumatics, servo motors, motion  controllers, PLC and and PC-based control systems 
JMP, Minitab &amp; Six Sigma experience preferred </p>
</div></body></html>
