<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57387336">Maps UI/UX Designer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57387336</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 5, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple Maps team is looking for an experienced and creative UI/UX Designer to lead the design of our new and existing web portals and iOS applications for data management and new product integrations. You will work with a team of inspired and fast moving business and product leaders, software engineers, and data analysts to transform complex user interactions into beautiful and intuitive user experiences. 

Candidates with a proven track record of successfully completing large projects involving all stages of modern web and iOS applications design—from high level mockups to detailed UI specifications—will be given preference. We’ll also appreciate your ability and willingness to deliver clear and beautiful presentations to our stakeholders, including seasoned executives. Brainstorming on new products and building prototypes that capture our imagination must be also in your DNA.  

Your other day-to-day responsibilities will include collaboration with product owners to define product requirements, creating detailed interaction and pixel specifications, and preparing assets for web and iOS engineers. Please be prepared to demonstrate your ability to uphold to Apple’s high standards and design aesthetic by presenting relevant accomplishments from your portfolio.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Expert in information architecture and creating highly detailed design specifications for web and iOS applications</li>
<li>Expert knowledge in understanding what engages and motivates users</li>
<li>Mastery of Sketch, Photoshop, Keynote, Illustrator, and other common design tools</li>
<li>Passionate about perfection</li>
<li>Experience creating process flow charts, wireframes, and mockups</li>
<li>Ability to rapidly prototype with HTML5/CSS3/JS</li>
<li>Ability to create clear and engaging data visualizations is a plus</li>
<li>Understanding of modern web and core iOS frameworks</li>
<li>Experience with working directly with developers to ensure the successful implementation of a design specifications</li>
<li>A strong portfolio demonstrating a history of creating great web and mobile designs</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple Maps team creates and manages various datasets used in Maps, Siri, Spotlight, Safari, and other Apple and 3rd party applications. We integrate with thousands of data sources and service providers using Apple’s proprietary B2B and B2C applications. These integrations are often tedious and complex, but we make them simple and engaging. Everything we release is built with the same amount of love, passion, and attention to detail like all other Apple products. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">- Bachelors degree in Design or equivalent experience
- 5+ years designing large web-based applications
- 2+ years of designing iOS applications

</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">- Self-motivated and pro-active with demonstrated creative and critical thinking capabilities
- Able to implement new ideas quickly and follow Apple design guidelines
- Familiar with Agile development methodology
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- Strong team player with a high degree of flexibility
- Ability to work independently while maintaining a high level of efficiency
- Very detail oriented and organized with a strong discipline of adhering to standards
- Excellent problem determination and resolution skills  


</p>
</div></body></html>
