<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113082099">Developer Support Manager </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113082099</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 11, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">App Review is looking for an expert communicator adept at resolving complex business issues. Great verbal and phone skills are a requirement. Technical customer relations experience preferred. Foreign language proficiency is highly desirable.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Thrive in a fast pace environment</li>
<li>Strong negotiator who can be firm, yet diplomatic</li>
<li>Well-versed in customer service and conflict management</li>
<li>High decision quality and sound judgment</li>
<li>Strong data analysis, time management and reporting skills</li>
<li>Ability to effectively manage sensitive situations</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal and critical thinking skills</li>
<li>Good understanding of mobile eco systems including key players, business models for application developers and a fundamental understanding of mobile technologies</li>
<li>Excellent attention to details</li>
<li>Analytical thinker with an ability to break down complex problems</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This position will interact with developers worldwide, with particular focus on the Asia Pacific region including China, and work hours will reflect this. General responsibilities include communicating, tracking and managing escalations from day-to-day operations with business partners. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS or equivalent is preferred.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">5+ years experience in a Technical Account Manager or Customer Relations Level II, Developer Relations role or similar environment. Technical experience with iOS and Mac development platforms a plus. Fluent in Chinese and English languages.</p>
</div></body></html>
