<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52852894">Senior IP Design Engineer - Implementation/Integration</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52852894</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Dec. 12, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will be at the center of a multimedia IP design effort interfacing with all disciplines, with a critical impact on getting functional products to millions of customers quickly. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 5+ years of experience in multimedia IP/SoC design:</li>
<li>•Previous experience in multimedia IP design and integration.</li>
<li>•Industry exposure to and knowledge of ASIC/FPGA design methodology, especially logic synthesis, static timing analysis, logic equivalence checking, and working with physical design teams for floorplanning and timng closure.</li>
<li>•Experience with system design methodologies that contain multiple clock domains.</li>
<li>•Familiarity with common on-chip bus protocols such as AMBA (AXI, AHB, APB).</li>
<li>•Experience in low-power design issues, tools, and methodologies including UPF power intent specification highly desired.</li>
<li>•Experience in datapath and video-centric designs a plus.</li>
<li>•Excellent collaboration skills</li>
<li>•Outstanding written and verbal communication</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a senior IP Design engineer you will have responsibilities spanning all aspects of multimedia IP design:
•Will be responsible for imaging subsystem design/integration.
•Integrate and design subsystem architectures containing both internal and external IPs.
•Responsibility includes feasibility, micro-architecture, RTL design, front-end implementation and post-silicon system bring-up.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•BSEE / MSEE is required</p>
</div></body></html>
