<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113163717">Audio Experience &amp; Prototyping Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113163717</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 18, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Technology Development Group is looking for an Audio Experience and Prototyping Engineer to prototype and develop next generation audio hardware and software products. This engineer will work closely with the acoustic design, audio software, product design, experience prototyping, and other teams to guide the future of Apple’s audio technology and experience across our products.

Responsibilities include:
Develop &amp; maintain next-generation iOS/macOS audio software tools such as AudioUnits and frameworks for use in product prototyping (C++ / Objective-C / Swift)
Integrate emerging audio technologies for use in executive demos and user studies
Independently proposing &amp; developing audio technology demos and user studies
Analysis of competitive landscape of audio software and products

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong understanding of audio/acoustics</li>
<li>Excellent C/C++ coding skills</li>
<li>Knowledge of advanced audio production tools and workflows</li>
<li>Experience with audio DSP programming in a framework such as Max/Faust/PureData</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills and experience with executive presentations</li>
<li>Experience in the following strongly preferred:</li>
<li>Swift / Objective-C</li>
<li>experience with prototyping media capture/transmission/playback systems</li>
<li>Audio DSP for telephony or music applications</li>
<li>Running DAW software such as Logic, ProTools, REAPER, etc.</li>
<li>Scripting languages such as Python and MATLAB</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Technology Development Group is a special projects group within Apple charged with research and development of new product categories and core technologies.

Candidate will join a fast-paced audio experience and software prototyping group that is charged with researching, designing, and developing next-generation audio technology and demonstrating the results to executives and decision makers within Apple. The team also develops and maintains a suite of audio tools used by engineers and sound designers across the company for crafting the sounds used in Apple products.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA, MS or PhD - Computer Science, Electrical Engineering</p>
</div></body></html>
