<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112958197">macOS Applications (Swift) Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112958197</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Developer Publications Authoring Tools team is looking for an experienced software engineer with a passion for great user experience and design. The ideal candidate will thrive in a small team environment, working together to design, implement, and integrate unit-tested software features into complex macOS applications written in Swift.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Proven ability to develop and ship high quality software products on schedule</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of Swift and Cocoa technologies</li>
<li>Demonstrated understanding of macOS UI/UX principles</li>
<li>Experience developing networked apps that communicate with remote web services</li>
<li>Knowledge of Apple's app testing infrastructure (XCTest, UI Testing, Xcode Server)</li>
<li>Excellent cross-functional communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As part of the Authoring Tools team, you'll define the tools our writers use to create and publish all of Apple's developer documentation. Your deep knowledge of AppKit will enable you to present highly structured content in a way that hides its complexity and encourages writers to follow best-practice guidelines. At the same time, your experience working with networked apps and data will make sure that content is always correct between the local desktop app and the web services that power it.

Our authoring tools suite of apps is written in 100% Swift. This role is a great opportunity to develop your Swift skills on a real-world project alongside engineers and writers who've been using Swift since day one.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">The Authoring Tools team is responsible for developing and supporting mission-critical internal software used to produce developer documentation for Apple-ecosystem and Swift developers around the world. This software enables our writers to author highly structured content in an editor that looks and feels like a first-class word processor.

As part of this team, you’ll have a direct impact on the evolution of our tools and benefit from rewarding and immediate feedback from our on-site and remote users. Your responsibilities as a contributor will include:
Individual and collaborative design of software architectures and user interfaces conforming to Swift and macOS best practices
Developing tools and features that achieve current and future authoring needs
Debugging and troubleshooting code individually and in collaboration with cross-functional teams, including server-side, front-end, and QA engineers
Developing and maintaining unit tests, and participating in peer code review for new features and fixes
Communicating goals, achievements, and technical expertise with the team and cross-functional stakeholders through presentation and written media</p>
</div></body></html>
