<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56792047">Software Engineer, Language Technologies</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56792047</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large-scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence. And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking. Join the Siri team!</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in the field of language technologies (e.g. speech recognition, machine translation, text mining and analytics,  etc.), </li>
<li>Knowledge of Machine Learning (e.g. deep learning), big data processing, system integration</li>
<li>Experience in building system and automation tools at scale with production quality</li>
<li>Strong coding skills in one or more of following languages — Python, Shell scripts, Java, C/C++</li>
<li>Proficient in some of the following systems/technologies — Linux, SGE, GPU, Github, Hadoop/MapReduce, Spark</li>
<li>Ability to apply Computer Science principles to solve complex problems</li>
<li>Good communication skills</li>
<li>Multilingual speaker a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for highly motivated software engineers to build the infrastructure to bring the latest and greatest technologies from lab to Apple products. You will play a key role in designing and creating the tools and processes to enable the language and feature expansion at scale. You will be working with teams across Siri to enable products that impacts millions of Apple customers.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in Computer Science or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
