<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113155024">Sr. Software Engineer, App Store Engineering</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113155024</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 24, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">App Store Engineering R&amp;D team is looking for talented software engineers to break new ground on our App delivery platform. At Apple, great ideas have a way of quickly becoming great products, services and customer experiences. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no end to what you can accomplish.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Extensive experience with Java or equivalent object-oriented languages</li>
<li>5+ years designing, implementing and supporting highly scalable backend applications</li>
<li>Deep understanding of HTTP and REST APIs</li>
<li>Ability to design and establish coding patterns/standards across multiple code repositories</li>
<li>Mentor team members on writing code that is efficient, maintainable and testable</li>
<li>Ability to re-architect an expansive code base while transitioning to new technologies/frameworks</li>
<li>Experience with NoSQL &amp; big data technologies like Cassandra, Solr, Kafka and Hadoop</li>
<li>Solid grasp of multi-threaded programming concepts</li>
<li>Ability to thrive on highly collaborative, cross-functional projects that are high profile and critical to the App Store</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The iTunes Connect team is looking for a Senior Software Engineer to design and build features driving the App Store and TestFlight.

We are looking for a self-starter who is energetic and not afraid to question assumptions.  Excellent written and oral skills are a must. The candidate should have experience developing large-scale, server-side systems using object-oriented languages. We are looking an excellent team player who is able to tackle problems under tight deadlines and deliver imaginative solutions.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSCS or equivalent.</p>
</div></body></html>
