<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56271323">Big Data Framework Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56271323</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there’s no telling what you could accomplish.

Join Apple’s iCloud team as a Big-Data Frameworks Engineer to design and build innovative systems, optimizations and services for our Analytics team.  As member of the technical team, you will play a critical role in shaping new systems architecture and technical direction, as well as the future of existing system and services.  This role requires working closely with cross-functional teams to effectively coordinate the complex interdependencies inherent in the project.  
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of experience in core Java or Scala</li>
<li>5+ years of experience in Hadoop/Spark systems</li>
<li>Expertise in architecting, designing and developing big data frameworks for analytics and data management</li>
<li>Direct experience with highly available systems</li>
<li>In depth knowledge of developing large distributed systems</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Architect, design and build a Big-Data Framework that can automate the creation of Self-Serve data Structures
This framework should make Big-Data Technology agnostic to the users so users can concentrate on the business logic
Has in depth knowledge of MapReduce and Spark API to develop this Framework
Designs and develops the features to address the above stated requirements
Designs Self - Serve data structures, sets up the Data Pipe Lines for these structures
Schedules the data pipe lines for daily and history processing
Works closely with cross functional teams to gather requirements for Self-Serve structures
Develops the Application Logic for creating the Self-Serve Data Structures
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science, Information Technology, or EE, or relevant industry experience is required</p>
</div></body></html>
