<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112930814">Labor Planning Manager, Apple Retail Contact Center </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112930814</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">This position manages the WW Labor Planning team responsible for developing the monthly headcount positioning of Apple’s Retail Contact Center (RCC) frontline and back office staff.  This team analyzes contact center performance history, current trends, and real time KPIs to determine the staffing levels needed to maximize the customer experience and optimize call center efficiencies. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10+ years experience in forecasting, modeling, and/or labor planning</li>
<li>Advanced Excel, including the ability to create dynamic models and manipulate large data sets.</li>
<li>Attention to detail and the ability to manage complex processes</li>
<li>An affinity to “talking with numbers”; inherent aptitude to quantify and support conclusions with data</li>
<li>Excellent analytical and communication skills, with the ability to work in a highly cross-functional environment </li>
<li>Experience with Executive level presentations</li>
<li>Experience working in a global role</li>
<li>Able to accommodate domestic and international travel</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Provide oversight and management of forecast attainment to ensure metric performance meets established goals and expectations 
Identify risks/opportunities to short and long term WW forecasts.  Partner with Workforce Management and regional leadership to develop contingency plans
Develop forecasting methodologies/models that evolve with business intricacies
Partner with reporting team to automate and streamline processes related to data management
Partner with Apple Online Store and RCC leadership on capital projects that impact RCC staffing needs
Quantify the impact of business initiatives by partnering with all levels of the organization and forecasting workload impacts appropriately</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree. Business or Statistics preferred, MBA a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
