<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-58238882">Software QA Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 58238882</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Have you ever wondered where the state of charge percentage displayed on your iOS device comes from?  

The Gas Gauge is a collection of hardware, firmware, and advanced algorithms.  The Gas Gauge measures battery and environmental conditions and makes predictions about present and future capacity.  

The Gas Gauge SQA team is looking for a highly motivated individual who has interest in learning about Gas Gauging and battery technology.   In this role, you will be testing, automating, and analyzing detailed results and working closely with the cross-functional team to ensure product quality.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years experience as a Software QA Engineer</li>
<li>Ability to make data driven decisions on a regular basis</li>
<li>Experience in automation using scripting or other languages (Python, Perl, Ruby, JavaScript, ObjectiveC, etc.)</li>
<li>Strong written and verbal communications skills</li>
<li>Strong working knowledge of UNIX-like operating systems</li>
<li>Ability to work cross-functionally with other teams and groups</li>
<li>Ability to think creatively, problem solve, and innovate</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">-Setup hardware environments needed for Gas Gauge testing 

-Develop test plans and other test documentation as required 

-Develop, design and execute tests for validation of hardware and firmware 

-Implement automation or write utilities for data extraction

-Prepare, analyze and publish results from planned tests 

-Identify, reproduce, and isolate bugs found via debugging and data analysis 

-Work closely and clearly communicate with all cross-functional teams</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE/CS or equivalent experience
</p>
</div></body></html>
