<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54780830">Web Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54780830</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Internet Services Group is an exciting, fast paced, ever growing and changing environment supporting millions of customers.  The Internet Services Group is responsible for systems related to Apple's internet facing applications.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience with web programming languages such as PHP and JavaScript.</li>
<li>Experience with scripting languages such as Python and Perl</li>
<li>Experience with Java &amp; J2EE</li>
<li>Familiarity with at least one web application framework (such as CodeIgniter and React)</li>
<li>Expertise in modern web development using JavaScript (ES6), HTML5, and libraries such as Bootstrap and JQuery</li>
<li>Strong understanding of data modeling and storage with NoSQL and SQL relational DBs</li>
<li>Solid understanding of performance testing, improvement techniques and caching solutions</li>
<li>Outstanding written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Excellent collaborative skill</li>
<li>Attention to detail</li>
<li>Comfortable working in a loosely structured organization</li>
<li>Highly professional, with the ability to deliver solid work on tight schedules</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a web developer on the ISO team, you have the opportunity to build web-based tools that are crucial for supporting day to day operations of the Data Center staff. You will work with engineers and SA’s to build tools that streamline the hardware management processes for products that support millions of users worldwide each day.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Software Engineering degree or equivalent work experience.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Perl development is a plus.

Knowledge of distributed job server platforms such as Gearman is a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
