<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-99761406">Software Engineering Intern: Back-End</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 99761406</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is currently seeking enthusiastic interns who can work full-time for a minimum of 12-weeks between Fall 2017 and Summer 2018.

Our software engineers are the brains behind some of the industry’s biggest breakthroughs. OS X, Siri, and iCloud — not to mention the system-level software for iPhone and Apple TV — all started here. This team is on the front line of Apple’s constant charge toward innovation. 

Back-end developers are responsible for making the features that our users love, like Siri, work by presenting data to the user-facing applications.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong object-oriented design skills, coupled with a deep knowledge of data structures and algorithms</li>
<li>Proficiency in one or more of the following developer skills: Java, C/C++, PHP, Python, Ruby, Unix, MySQL, Clojure, Scala, Java Script, CSS</li>
<li>Experience in advanced Big Data methodologies such as Data Modeling, Validation, Processing, Hadoop, MapReduce, Mongo, Pig</li>
<li>Natural Language, Machine Learning, and/or Artificial Intelligence experience is a plus</li>
<li>Client-Server protocol &amp; API design skills</li>
<li>Knowledge of key/value and column stores is a plus</li>
<li>Able to gather cross-functional requirements and translate them into practical engineering tasks</li>
<li>Excellent debugging, critical thinking, and communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Back-end development opportunities are available in:
Siri
iCloud
Core OS
OS X Frameworks and Applications
Interactive Media Group
Audio/Video
Software Integration and Localization
Advanced Computation
iLife, iWorks, Aperture, and Pro Apps
iTunes

Apple is an Equal Employment Opportunity Employer that is committed to inclusion and diversity. We also take affirmative action to offer employment and advancement opportunities to all applicants, including minorities, women, protected veterans, and individuals with disabilities.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Must be currently enrolled in a BS/MS/PhD program in Computer Science, Electrical Engineering, Design, or related fields.  Must also return to school after the internship to continue education or an internship must be required for graduation from your school.

Apple is an Equal Employment Opportunity Employer that is committed to inclusion and diversity. We also take affirmative action to offer employment and advancement opportunities to all applicants, including minorities, women, protected veterans, and individuals with disabilities.</p>
</div></body></html>
