<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113185210">Functional Analyst – SAP Material Management</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113185210</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's SAP team within IS&amp;T has an immediate opening for a Functional Analyst, to design new complex, cross-functional global solutions as a functional SME supporting Corporate Procurement, Master Data and Vendor management areas.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum 2 years as a Functional Analyst designing, configuring and testing SAP MM</li>
<li>Knowledge of Procure to Pay Business Process</li>
<li>Knowledge of fit-gap analysis, system design and configuration, writing functional specifications and test scripts  </li>
<li>Eager to learn, self motivated, and curious to stay current on new technology</li>
<li>Ability to adapt and to deal with ambiguity  </li>
<li>Able to maintain focus and to handle multiple tasks / priorities under time pressure</li>
<li>Analytical skill &amp; problem solving</li>
<li>Excellent communication and presentation skills, verbal and written, and ability to drive to consensus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The candidate will work with our business teams to understand their specific needs, analyze business requirements, and design scalable solutions with a slick UI. 

The candidate will work with other IS&amp;T members and teams to implement, test and deliver these solutions in the most efficient and timely manner, leveraging Apple's proven software development methodologies and guidelines.  

The candidate must work well with distributed, cross-department teams in dynamic and aggressive environment, be independent and self-driven.

•Work with Business users to gather requirements and define scope  
•Propose conceptual and detailed designs to support the business needs, produce functional specifications
•Participate in project execution following Apple SAP’s project life cycle methodology including design, test and go live activities
•Prioritize own work and as appropriate lead project tracks

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS / BA with 4 years experience or MS / MBA with 2 years </p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">•Good understanding of web based applications, web services and XML-based interfaces 
•Experience designing UI 
•Good grasp of Reporting and Analytics
</p>
</div></body></html>
