<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113187250">AppleCare Mac/Beats/Audio Business Operations Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113187250</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">This position will lead the procurement activities for AppleCare covering Mac, Beats, and Audio. Success in this role will require close collaboration with key internal and external partners to manage the related service supply chain and provide outstanding support to supply planning, readiness, and SQE organizations. The position will focus on design and management of the service supply chain, including cost, service contract, continuity of supply, and relationship management with OEMs and vendors related to assigned line of business (LOBs). 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10-15 years of progressive Procurement and Supply Chain Operations experience</li>
<li>Service/Reverse Logistics experience a strong plus</li>
<li>Advanced degree in Engineering/Business/Law preferred</li>
<li>Data driven and analytical problem solver</li>
<li>Negotiation and contracts experience required</li>
<li>Ability to travel up to 25%</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">General responsibilities include: 

Leadership
- Create a workplace that fosters credibility, respect, fairness, camaraderie, pride and a drive for business results.
- Development of a high performing organization through effective objective setting, coaching, performance management, and employee development.

Service Supply Chain Management
- Develop sourcing strategies; solicit/analyze request for proposals; negotiate business model, cost, and contracts; manage supplier coordination with internal resources and overall reverse supply chain strategies as needed to maximize product quality, on time delivery and minimize overall product service cost.
- Support the development and implementation of policy-compliant processes and procedures that will optimize the procurement function for all LOBs.

Cross-functional Collaboration
- Coordinate with Service Quality Engineer (SQE) to develop supplier quality performance expectations and metrics. Develop and sustain collaborative relationships with suppliers to drive cost reduction, improve product quality and maintain continuity of supply through end of Service (EOS)
- Be accountable for productivity and capacity optimization at OEMs supporting Mac/Audio/Beats service materials supply.
- Be “hands-on” in managing the day-to-day operations for procurement area.
- Develop and maintain strong relationship with key executives and DRIs both internally and externally. Leverage relationship for effective problem resolution and conflict management.

Continuous Improvement
- Prioritize and focus on high risk and high spend areas in procurement.
- Proactively identify and manage vendor risks and long term site strategy shifts that could impact AppleCare’s supply chain.
- Apply best practice purchasing/procurement methodologies to achieve organizational objectives, best value for the enterprise, and achievement of target return on investments (ROI).

Supplier Management
- Develop seamless relationships with OEM/Vendors and other key suppliers. 
- Manage the OEMs in support of the full service product lifecycle from NPI thru to end of service.
- Coordinate and lead Quarterly Business Review (QBR) process. Develop, align and deliver strategic messaging to OEM/vendors and drive competitive advantage for AppleCare</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Advanced degree in Engineering/Business/Law preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
