<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112866079">Finance Internal Communications Project Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112866079</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Finance Communications team is seeking a talented communications professional to provide executive and employee communication support. This role requires driving projects from initial concept to final delivery, partnering closely with Finance leadership teams, Human Resources, and various other teams and employees.  The Communications Project Manager will be a storyteller, a graphic designer, a writer, a creative thinker, a critical thinker, and a very strong project manager. The ideal candidate will be highly organized, collaborative, passionate, and detail oriented. This position is located in Cupertino.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years proven experience in employee and executive communications</li>
<li>Exceptional presentation and graphic design skills</li>
<li>Natural ability to articulate complex data and concepts to a variety of audiences in a compelling manner</li>
<li>Strong written communication skills</li>
<li>Skilled in creating and fostering productive business partnerships</li>
<li>Comfort around higher management</li>
<li>Strong planning and organizational skills, with the ability to drive multiple projects simultaneously</li>
<li>Comfortable working within an established style and design language</li>
<li>Creative with limited resources</li>
<li>Adaptable to last-minute changes</li>
<li>Ability to display a great sense of humor, even during the most challenging times</li>
<li>Experience working globally, with international and remote stakeholders and audiences</li>
<li>Experience visualizing complex data</li>
<li>Experience with finance-related data visualization, or basic finance business acumen a plus </li>
<li>Fluent in iOS, macOS, Keynote and Pages</li>
<li>Skilled in Photoshop, Excel, and website content management systems</li>
<li>Experience in Illustrator and Acrobat Pro a plus</li>
<li>Experience with video a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Provide internal communication support for the Finance organization (and potentially other G&amp;A organizations as needed)
Create and publish a wide variety of materials such as presentations, email messages, infographics, web content, etc.
Drive large-audience, global communication efforts such as all-hands meetings, email communication, presentations, and infographics
Support executive communication efforts including presentations and high-visibility announcements
Determine the right audiences, timing, and vehicles for effective communication on a per-project basis
Provide communication support for various employee initiatives and programs, such as career development, performance reviews, and rewards and recognition</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA degree in Communications, Marketing, English, Business or related field</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">We’d like to see a sample of your work product as part of the interview process:
Create a presentation for use by a senior leader to inform a large team about a multi-faceted process change that impacts workflow, business partnerships, and organization structure.
• Assume the presentation would be delivered at an all-hands meeting
• Feel free to fabricate specific details in order to create a realistic sample 
• Do not use any real-world content that could be considered confidential 
• Limit your samples to 12 slides or less
• Submit as Keynote or PowerPoint format</p>
</div></body></html>
