<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112861036">WiSE iOS Automation Intern</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112861036</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 7, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.

The Wireless Automation team builds systems which enable other Apple engineers to test and develop products and features. 
We work with all of Apple's major product lines and want to create great UI experiences that are easily accessed and seamlessly utilized.
We are a fun team that get's to work with many other people and teams here at Apple. Every day is different, and exciting. 

Apple is currently seeking enthusiastic interns who can work full-time for a minimum of 12-weeks between Fall 2017 and Summer 2018.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong programming skills in Objective-C/C/C++</li>
<li>Proficiency with iOS SDK Frameworks and Concepts (UIKit, GCD, Foundation, CoreData &amp; MapKit a plus)</li>
<li>Passion for scripting in Python, Shell, and standard UNIX tools</li>
<li>Solid computer science fundamentals</li>
<li>Excellent debugging skills</li>
<li>Experience with automation and developing frameworks</li>
<li>Ability to own a complete functional area of an application or product</li>
<li>Strong communication skills to confidently drive multiple projects across many teams</li>
<li>Obsessively passionate and inquisitive, and seek to solve everyday problems in innovative ways</li>
<li>Laser-focused on the smallest details that are meaningful to our customers</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The iOS Wireless Technologies team is looking for a highly motivated automation engineer to develop frameworks, iOS/OSX apps, and tools.  You should have a deep understanding of the iOS development environment and share our vision of creating highly functional frameworks and beautiful apps.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors Degree in Computer Science, Computer Engineering, or equivalent with 5+ years industry experience
Degree is less important to us. It's your experiences and abilities we really care about.
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience developing user facing iOS Applications and Frameworks
Experience with large scale backend systems and web services
</p>
</div></body></html>
