<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113110437">GBI - Compliance Project Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113110437</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 26, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The successful candidate will have a strong customer privacy focus and background, as well as excellent communication and computer skills. Must be a good communicator and be able to work on own initiative. The candidate will require the ability to maintain priorities and deadlines with strong attention to detail.  Be a team player with planning and organization skills, as well as being capable of working under pressure and meet deadlines. The candidate will be required to liaise frequently with a number of internal and external teams and should be able to influence and corral cooperation from teams to drive result.
The candidate must have the ability to manage cross-functional projects.  Experience in project management needed.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Customer Privacy awareness, high levels of enthusiasm and energy</li>
<li>Ability to initiate and deliver a project independently</li>
<li>An undergraduate degree, plus 7-10 years work experience in data analysis and project management </li>
<li>Able to work effectively within a fast changing environment, tight deadlines, priority changes and multiple constituencies</li>
<li>Experience analyzing large datasets and conveying results in a presentation format</li>
<li>Well-versed in SQL languages</li>
<li>Good business acumen and the ability to see the full picture</li>
<li>Strong analysis, problem resolution skills</li>
<li>Good communication, interpersonal and organizational skills</li>
<li>Ability to display a high degree of professionalism in dealing with senior management and users</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsibility includes:
•Primary contact between business stakeholders and IS&amp;T teams
•Identify, collect, prioritize and document complex business requirements and translate into clear functional specifications and work with technical team to deliver a privacy compliance solution
•Manage development roadmap for phased releases that include addressing the highest risk area first
•Collaborate with technical teams to deliver design, architecture and level of effort assessments
•Prepare presentations to communicate project status to management and business stakeholders
•Establish project timeline; manage project activities by coordinating directly with cross-functional business and technical teams to identify and deliver innovative solutions for aggressive privacy initiatives timelines to mitigate Apple risk
•Evaluate and establish standards and processes to assist easier management of GBI solutions to be in compliance</p>
</div></body></html>
