<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113061597">Technical Program Manager, AMP Analytics and Data Products</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113061597</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking a proven Technical Program Manager to join the Apple Media Products Analytics and Data Products team.

The Program Manager plays a critical role in collaborating with engineering and analytic teams to design, maintain, build or enhance data systems. In this role, you will focus on how GDPR will affect IT &amp; data systems whilst working with legal, business, engineering stakeholders to deliver projects upon this.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3-5 years of industry experience in a technical program management role, focused on big data</li>
<li>Strong technical proficiency - past programming, Big Data, Compliance, or GDPR experience a plus</li>
<li>Strong prioritization and project management skills, including timely and proactive communications of timelines, status, issue escalation </li>
<li>Significant hands-on experience and fluency with big data and traditional database technologies (HDFS, Cassandra, Vertica, and traditional database platforms such as Teradata)</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills, both written and oral, including the ability to convey complex requirements in a clear, concise and credible manner</li>
<li>Deep analytical skills, strong out-of-the-box thinking and a curious mind</li>
<li>Extreme attention to detail and ability to self-audit work</li>
<li>Strong understanding of media- or content-specific data models a plus </li>
<li>Perform root cause and impact analysis to investigate issues and make recommendations for potential solutions</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">* Support the identification of business processes and systems that relate to personal data and are deemed in-scope for GDPR
* Perform a risk assessment to aid a risk based approach for the application/implementation of GDPR
* Understand the internal summarisation of the GDPR requirements and perform a gap analysis of all Business and IT processes, systems, procedures and controls, producing a gap analysis reports
* Verify changes to systems and processes and support test managers in the development of their test plans and test scripts
* Plan post implementation support processes and assist in transfer to business as usual
* Specify and implement data quality metrics throughout the data pipeline to measure data quality and detect anomalies</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's degree or equivalent work experience in Engineering, Computer Science, Business Information Systems.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is an Equal Opportunity Employer that is committed to inclusion and diversity. We also take affirmative action to offer employment and advancement opportunities to all applicants, including minorities, women, protected veterans, and individuals with disabilities. Apple will not discriminate or retaliate against applicants who inquire about, disclose, or discuss their compensation or that of other applicants.
</p>
</div></body></html>
