<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-86355957">Backend Stack Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 86355957</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is working on exciting new technologies and we are looking for a dedicated Backend Stack engineer. As a member of our fast-paced group, you will have a unique and rewarding opportunity to be part of a new project and shape upcoming products that will delight and inspire millions of Apple’s customers every day.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of experience specifying, configuring and deploying Linux full stack backend solutions.</li>
<li>Expertise in configuring and deploying storage, data and asset management systems</li>
<li>Expertise designing and developing client facing API’s for backend services</li>
<li>Excellent communication and collaboration skills.</li>
<li>Curious and loves working with the best creative people in the industry to solve hard technical problems.</li>
<li>Passionate, Inspired by Apple's mission and products. </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will work with a team developing a new digital asset pipeline. As the engineer in charge of specifying, developing and deploying backed solutions you will be experienced in full lifecycle systems development. From the OS up you will be able to specify, configure and deploy the major functional components of a scalable digital asset management system. You will be responsible for specifying the development and deployment schedule and best practices. You are curious and love working with the best creative people in the industry to solve hard technical problems. Grit and ability to persevere are key.
 
 


</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS EE/CS or equivalent.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience developing placeholder front ends
Understanding of security concerns and infrastructures.
Experience designing for scalability
Experience designing systems that support large amounts of complex digital assets
Experience in a managed develop, stage and deploy environment </p>
</div></body></html>
