<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113131954">Video Pipeline Architect - Platform Architecture</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113131954</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, you will be interfacing with software and hardware architects, designers and validation engineers to develop efficient SOC architectures for complex pixel processing and memory compression systems.



 </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 5+ years experience in video pipeline architectures with the following background:</li>
<li>Experience writing hardware architecture specifications.</li>
<li>Experience working on various pixel processing IP such as scaling, tone mapping and enhancement.</li>
<li>Experience developing C/C++ bit accurate models for hardware design verification.</li>
<li>Knowledge of compression algorithms.</li>
<li>Knowledge of memory interface and transaction architectures.</li>
<li>Knowledge of signal processing theory and how it applies to image/video processing algorithms.</li>
<li>Knowledge in hardware micro-architecture.</li>
<li>Knowledge of scripting languages such as Perl and/or Python</li>
<li>Strong communication skills and ability to work across various groups.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Platform Architect owning the architecture for various pixel processing algorithms, you will have responsibilities spanning various aspects of video pipeline architecture:

·      Develop power and area efficient hardware architectures for various video processing IP.

·      Write clear and concise hardware architecture specifications.

·      Develop bit-accurate C-models for hardware/software verification.

·      Work with design and verification teams to define and implement pixel IP data and control path architectures.

·      Work with memory system architects to define define and implement pixel IP DMA architectures.

·      Work across teams to make correct trade-offs between quality, complexity and schedule.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE/MSEE is required
</p>
</div></body></html>
