<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57164712">Financial Analyst - WW iPhone Finance</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57164712</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 20, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for an outgoing professional with high analytical capacity, creativity, and strong interpersonal skills to join the Worldwide iPhone Sales Finance team.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5-8 years finance-related experience</li>
<li>Advanced spreadsheet and modeling skills </li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to conduct complex, data driven analysis. </li>
<li>Strong verbal and written communication skills with the ability to articulate results of analysis in easy to understand business terms</li>
<li>Thrive in a fast-pace, demanding environment</li>
<li>Must be able to think strategically on critical business issues, while simultaneously possessing the ability to act tactically to execute against them</li>
<li>Proven experience developing processes and/or improving existing processes, with desire to influence change across our team and Apple as an organization</li>
<li>Deep understanding of financial principles and theories</li>
<li>Some accounting experience is recommended</li>
<li>Ability to navigate through a large organization</li>
<li>Strong prioritization skills with ability to manage multiple projects simultaneously</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The position requires the ability to complete complex financial analysis, develop and execute iPhone business strategies, consolidate and forecast global demand generation programs, manage peers in other geographies and work as a partner with the sales organization. Candidate must be able to communicate with executives inside our team and outside of Apple.

The ideal candidate is one who has been a top performer in his or her career with a proven track record of accomplishments. The candidate will be joining the WW iPhone Sales Finance with the expectations of being a key contributor in a fast-paced, growth environment. The candidate should feel comfortable dealing with complex &amp; ambiguous situations.

Responsibilities Include:

Own and support our LRF unit forecasting process - how to think about the longer term strategy and how our future demand generation plans impact this. 

Partner closely with the iPhone sales team globally to provide analytical and execution support on various demand generation strategies

Complete complex analysis quickly, in response to ad hoc request from the leadership team on specific questions on the iPhone business

Create content as part of various work streams that are needed for the weekly Sales meeting with the CEO - unit forecasting, DG tracking, etc.

Assist in analysis, writing, and reviewing of highly visible, quarterly summary document which places iPhone performance in a strategic lens, and highlights key headwinds the business may face moving forward</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or BA in Business, Finance, or Accounting; MBA, CFA, or CPA a plus</p>
</div></body></html>
