<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57864886">Program Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57864886</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 22, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Information Systems &amp; Technology has an immediate opening for a Production Support Lead. Application Production Support (APS) Team supports and maintains several global, mission critical production systems. These applications span across multiple technologies in Business Intelligence, Service Management, Middleware Platforms, Internet Commerce and a host of Third-party &amp; Custom applications on various platforms.  The APS team is responsible for day to day user support of applications, trouble ticket resolution, system maintenance, system performance management, bug fixes, migration of fixes across environments, and co-ordination with various stake-holders for all production support activities.  This position is responsible to lead this Production Support team located in Cupertino and Offshore. This role will be the go-to person for the production support team for all day to day activities. This position will interface significantly with Helpdesk, Application Owners, System Engineers, Network Engineers, DBAs and key Business Users on a regular basis.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10 years of overall experience working on multiple IT platforms</li>
<li>Strong verbal and written communication skills and ability to coordinate with multiple technical and business teams</li>
<li>Experience in designing and improving support processes in large IT organizations</li>
<li>Exposure to helpdesk processes is a plus</li>
<li>Should be self-driven, highly motivated, innovative and have a proven track record of managing multiple production environments for large user base</li>
<li>Should be able to manage change, and work in an extremely fast-paced environment</li>
<li>Proactive, result-oriented and organized</li>
<li>Experience in managing teams</li>
<li>Should have significant experience with developing or supporting enterprise applications from end-to-end. Experience in a few of the below technologies is a must and exposure to other technologies is a plus:</li>
<li>-- Unix, Linux</li>
<li>-- Java, J2EE</li>
<li>-- Objective-C, Cocoa </li>
<li>-- JBoss, Tomcat</li>
<li>-- Experience in Oracle Database, PL/SQL or CouchDB or MongoDB</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Provide overall leadership to onsite and offshore teams supporting multiple production applications
Manage and measure quality and process adherence of the support team
Institutionalize best practices for support operations
Review and manage response time and resolution time SLAs
Drive productivity improvements and measurement
Drive root-cause resolution of all production issues
Drive automation of various manual tasks in day to day support
Manage all key stakeholder communication
Plan and manage resource transitions and skill-set assessment
Mentor and coach module leads on a continuous basis
Proactively manage all the significant system events, product launches and transaction growth
Partner with multiple application owners, helpline and key business users for issue prioritization
Manage support transition of new project releases every month
Build knowledge assets by partnering with various development teams
Provide subject matter expertise, guidance and direction to team members
Manage production systems crisis and communication
Conduct critical issue post-mortem (or follow-up) meetings 
Manage Month-end and Quarter-end operations and communications
Key stakeholder engagement for critical issue follow-up and action items
Manage validations and cutover of key infrastructure upgrade activities
Participate in periodic status update meetings with Application Owners and Business users
Manage all the maintenance environments
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS degree or higher in CS or in related field </p>
</div></body></html>
