<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-53265145">Optical Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 53265145</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 9, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is responsible for all research, design, development, test and qualification of camera hardware for Apple products. The team is looking for an Optical Engineer to work on advanced optical technology development.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 5+ years experience in the area of lens design, metrology and integration.</li>
<li>Experience in lens design, tolerance analysis</li>
<li>Experience in Stray light analysis</li>
<li>Experience in lens characterization methodology and instrumentation</li>
<li>Proficiency with ZEMAX, CODE V, LightTool, MATLAB, 2D&amp;3D CAD, etc.</li>
<li>Ability to perform comprehensive optical and image quality characterization of the lens and the camera module</li>
<li>Support metrology methodology for camera lens testing and develop appropriate test charts and methods for camera evaluation</li>
<li>Interface with the assembly and packaging groups to support integration of camera lens into module</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Core Responsibilities:

Work on new lens design, characterization and integration into CMOS imager sensor based camera modules. Drive development of advanced metrology development. Complete analysis of the optical element's influence on the image quality characteristics of the camera module. Work closely with lens supplier for prototype design, evaluation and MTF testing.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Graduate degree in Optics, Physics, Electrical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering, Material Science, Manufacturing, or equivalent work experience</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Desirable

•working knowledge of thin film physics and fabrication

•track record of imaging related innovations

•working knowledge of optomechanics

•must be high energy, multi-tasker, resourceful problem solver, ability to work under pressure, take initiative

•working knowledge of statistical analysis of production data

</p>
</div></body></html>
