<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113084929">Revenue Operations Analyst - Rebates</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113084929</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 1, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, one of the most influential technology leaders in the industry. Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact, where you will share in a commitment to excellence by partnering with world-class teammates, all with one unified vision—creating innovative products that delight customers. Finance is about “fueling innovation.” We do this by hiring quality individuals with integrity and personal accountability, who value teamwork, work product excellence and proactive thinking. If you share these values and want to be part of something big, contact us today.

We are currently seeking an experienced Financial Analyst to support Channel Sales Incentive process simplification and automation efforts across the Americas region. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Background in finance, accounting, or similar field with a minimum 3+ years professional experience</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to deliver high quality work</li>
<li>Work well under pressure and within deadlines</li>
<li>Strong process and data analytical skills</li>
<li>Excellent excel skills</li>
<li>Demonstrated command of details</li>
<li>Communicate effectively; comfortable presenting to customers and senior leadership team on regular basis</li>
<li>Strong customer service, business partnership and cross-functional leadership skills</li>
<li>History of driving process improvement, system automation, and operational metrics</li>
<li>Work both independently and within a team environment</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills; ability to interact with all levels of management</li>
<li>Ability to deal with ambiguity, collaborate with stakeholders, and be a self-starter</li>
<li>Experience working with Sales Operations, Sales Finance and/or Sales Support Operations is preferred </li>
<li>Experience with SAP preferred</li>
<li>Advanced Excel skills preferred</li>
<li>Experience with SEA 2.0 is a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Work with a variety of cross-functional teams and external customers or partners to drive sales incentive calculations and process credits accurately and on time
• Participate in process improvements and systems enhancements initiatives to improve the productivity and scalability of key processes
• Calculate sales rebate customer performance and partner with cross functional teams to execute sales incentive credit processing within SLA
• Ensure deadlines for time sensitive deliverables are met
• Drive system automation, process improvements, and operational metrics
• Build and maintain cross-geography relationships with internal partners and external customers
• Tracking, reporting and managing other ad hoc requests
• Work closely with Information Systems &amp; Technology, Order-to-Cash, various Finance &amp; Sales groups to ensure that processes are sustainable, scalable, and produce accurate results
• General understanding of GAAP &amp; SOX controls
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• BBA, BA or BS in Finance, Accounting, or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
