<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112890985">Data Science Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112890985</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 17, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Analytic Insight team is responsible for mitigating fraud, waste and abuse company-wide. AI Data Science Engineering is building an environment to enable cutting-edge data analysis over Petabytes of data. We work side-by-side with data scientists and implement scalable, easy-to-use systems and tools.

We are seeking a customer-oriented, passionate and driven Data Science Engineer with experience in building big data systems. Must be able to lead the design and the implementation of a big data analytics system.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Mastery of one of C++, Python, Java, Scala or equivalent language</li>
<li>Experience with Relational databases and NoSQL databases</li>
<li>Hands on experience with Hadoop, Spark, Hive/Pig, HBase</li>
<li>Solid understanding of the full software development lifecycle</li>
<li>Excellent problem solving, critical thinking, and communication skills</li>
<li>Strong ability to evaluate and apply new technologies in a short time</li>
<li>Experience in building data science or data analysis tools a plus</li>
<li>Machine learning background a plus</li>
<li>Familiar with Agile software development process, Test-Driven development and Continuous Integration a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will lead the design and implementation of systems and tools to support the fraud prevention efforts of Analytic Insight.  The job will include:

-Working with infrastructure teams to design and implement the Big Data data warehouse and analytics platform
-Design and implement proof-of-concept solutions for new technologies and machine learning algorithms
-Develop new tools, capabilities and infrastructure to improve how data scientists conduct data analysis and model research

The candidate is expected to be self-motivated, pro-active and solution-oriented individual.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS degree in computer science or equivalent field plus 7-10 years experience, or equivalent.</p>
</div></body></html>
