<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-39857632">Sr. Mechanical Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 39857632</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 21, 2015</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Mechanical Design Engineer with expertise in electric actuators, control systems or related fields. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>•Candidate must have detailed mechanical design knowledge including materials, structures, bearings, drive elements and sensors.</li>
<li>•The ideal candidate will have 10+ years of hands-on experience in industry with electro-mechanical systems and electric actuators.</li>
<li>•Candidate must be detail oriented and have passion for doing excellent work in the presence of ambiguous requirements.</li>
<li>•Candidate must have experience managing vendors, and suppliers.</li>
<li>•Experience with design and product definition processes is desirable.</li>
<li>•Candidate must have excellent written and verbal communication skills to interact with management, team members and external suppliers.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Define mechanical system architecture for multi-degree-of-freedom electro-mechanical systems.
•Define mechanical component requirements based on overall system performance requirements.
•Drive innovative actuator design as necessary to meet overall system performance requirements. 
•Perform FEA and modal analysis as required to meet appropriate standards and life requirements.
•Perform detailed CAD design, generate manufacturing documentation, and manage manufacturing of components.
•Manage and/or perform assembly, integration and system testing.
•Develop &amp; manage validation test protocols for the electromechanical system.
•Analyze test data to refine mechanical design.
•Document design specifications, and test protocols.
•Mentor junior engineers.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•       5+ years with a BSME/MSME or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
