<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113037255">NPI Operations Program Specialist</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113037255</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 10, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The New Product Introduction Operations Program Specialist (NPI OPS) plays a key role in launching Apple’s new products on time, with superior product quality and maximum customer availability.

The NPI OPS is pivotal to the fast-paced development and launch of Apple’s products. A successful OPS is self-driven, organized and detail oriented, communicates with ease across engineering and operations teams, thrives in an ambiguous environment and is adept at facilitating actions and resolving conflicts.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>· Drive solutions across multiple cross-functional teams and the supply chain</li>
<li>· Consolidate detailed and extensive cross-functional data into concise executive briefings</li>
<li>· Detail orientation a must; results driven and proven DRI with hands on approach; self- motivated, proactive and driven</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This individual is the key facilitator who defines and drives material to enable manufacturing line bring-up, manages material for early operations builds, and interfaces with engineering to define final bill of materials. Overall mission is a successful product launch with all lines brought up on schedule and within budget, and completion of early operations builds on target.

Key Responsibilities:
· Lead Apple &amp; Original Equipment Manufacturer (OEM) operations teams in executing early operations builds &amp; line bring-up material strategy
· Coordinate &amp; track readiness/risks: working with procurement teams on specific material escalations
· Manage communications: upward and downward through organization; escalate issues and clearly communicate current status
· Influence product cost and product margin through judicious use of NG material and reduction of qualification requirements.
· Communicate system requirements and schedules to facilitate technical readiness with cross- functional teams.
· NPI owner in ordering, tracking and actualizing material to support development builds &amp; product ramp; Drive material delivery through Apple Procurement and direct with suppliers to ensure on-time delivery
· Cross-functional owner for tracking &amp; escalating BOM readiness
· Create Purchase Orders / Requisitions, maintaining invoice tracking and Goods Receipts</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">· Typically requires 2+ years experience in Supply Chain, Procurement, or Buyer roles. · Bachelors Degree preferably in Business, Science or Engineering</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">· Ability to travel up to 15%
· Strong written and verbal communication skills, and ability to articulate complex scenarios in simple terms
· Excel, Database, &amp; Statistical Software (SPSS, SAS, SQL etc.) experience a plus</p>
</div></body></html>
