<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112901777">Sr. Product Designer, iCloud</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112901777</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 27, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">iCloud is looking for a Sr. Product Designer to create new products and extend existing products. He or she is comfortable creating complex interactions based on a high-level concept, illustrating a large number of use cases and conditions, resolving dependencies, working with and pushing against technical constraints. This designer creates experiences for iOS, Mac, PC, Web, Watch and CarPlay.

The position requires deliverables to be provided under tight deadlines — strong communication skills are a must, as well as coolness under pressure, problem solving, attention to detail, the ability to mediate and cope with rapid change. Above all, the role requires a dedicated individual who understands Apple’s high standards and design aesthetic to the core. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Creative and resourceful </li>
<li>Rigorous attention to detail </li>
<li>Adept at solving complex problems </li>
<li>Proficient at extending existing design patterns across platforms </li>
<li>Enjoys improving existing patterns and finding innovative solutions for new features and use cases</li>
<li>Flexible and comfortable with ambiguity and change during a project</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsibilities of this position also include: creating detailed interaction and pixel specs; preparing assets for use in a variety of platforms: engineering implementation, Web use or Keynote presentations; maintaining up-to-date files and uniform naming conventions; ensuring design consistency across all assets and products. 
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Mastery of Photoshop, Illustrator and other design software
Knowledge of Apple products, specifically iOS and OS X
Demonstrated proficiency in the formal elements of design including typography and layout
Excellent communicator and team player 
Experience working across multiple projects at once
Background or interest in prototyping 
Fluency with HTML and CSS highly desired
Expertise with localization design and other visual arts such as texture work, photography and 3D work a plus</p>
</div></body></html>
