<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113092875">IS&amp;S Project Specialist</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113092875</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 29, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, one of the most influential technology leaders in the industry. Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact, where you will share in a dedication to excellence by partnering with extraordinary teammates, all with one unified vision – creating innovative products that delight customers. Finance is about “fueling innovation.” We do this by hiring quality individuals with integrity and personal accountability, who value teamwork, work product excellence and proactive thinking. If you share these values and want to be part of something big, contact us today.

We are seeking a cross-functional process analyst to join the Global Finance Shared Services Operations team (GFSS) based in Austin, TX.   This analyst will specialize in representing GFSS in projects related to the Internet Software and Services (IS&amp;S) organization, which includes the iTunes Store and Apple Music, as well as Apple Pay, Maps, Search Ads, and Apple’s iCloud services.  The analyst will assess the impact of IS&amp;S projects on GFSS functions, and will work within GFSS to develop sustainable and scalable solutions that meet project goals.

This process analyst may work across one or more of the three GFSS pillars (R2R, O2C or P2P) depending on project assignment.  Familiarity with key accounting areas such as revenue accounting, royalties, accounts receivable, invoicing, and consumer payment reconciliation (credit card and e-wallet) will be particularly meaningful for this individual.

This is an exciting opportunity to represent the Americas GFSS team on key initiatives, in support of the IS&amp;S organization.

This position is based in Austin, TX.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in financial process design and analysis</li>
<li>Ability to quickly develop an understanding of the current environment (including systems, policies, processes, and procedures) within the organization, such that decisions will be rooted in a strong foundation</li>
<li>Excellent oral and written communications skills, including process documentation and presentation skills; adept at coordinating efforts between multiple teams</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to influence personnel at all levels within the organization</li>
<li>Ability to thrive in a highly visible position in a fast-paced, deadline-driven environment</li>
<li>Outstanding attention to detail, while maintaining a global perspective, with an understanding of the broader downstream impacts of decisions and directions</li>
<li>Self-starter with the ability to deal with ambiguity and work independently</li>
<li>Knowledge of the project life cycle</li>
<li>ERP experience required; working knowledge of the SAP Financial Accounting (FI) and SAP Sales and Distribution (SD) modules is strongly preferred</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Liaising with the IS&amp;S project team, IS&amp;T, the Global Process Organizations, and the Global Finance Projects Team to define as-is and to-be business processes and systems
• Developing business requirements documents for global applications and conducting gap/fit analyses to drive solutions
• Representing GFSS in reviews of process and systems controls, and the development of project schedules taking into account seasonal volume spikes, fiscal close schedules, etc
• Actively participating in data validation activities prior to system conversions
• Coordinating user acceptance testing including scheduling resources to validate system functionality, and creating and executing use cases
• Readying the GFSS and impacted business partners for systems implementations through effective communications and end user training
• Providing regular project updates to GFSS management, and promptly communicating risk areas
• Attending production team meetings to stay abreast of other initiatives and process changes underway within the organization</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Bachelor's degree in accounting, finance, or business or equivalent work experience required</p>
</div></body></html>
