<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113202008">Software Development Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113202008</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Special Projects Group (SPG) is looking for a highly motivated, highly dedicated Manager to achieve stability, high velocity, and a high volume of data. You will be a critical part of a team focused on processing and enriching data for a larger project researching and developing new Apple products. You will work in a cross-functional team requiring creative problem solving and you’ll get to put these ideas into practice.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>* Experience with ETL frameworks and processes</li>
<li>* Past experience managing direct reports</li>
<li>* Strong interpersonal and communication skills are required</li>
<li>* Experience providing detailed reports to cross functional teams and leadership</li>
<li>* Prioritizing work loads across multiple teams and compute resources</li>
<li>* Tracking and eliminating regressions</li>
<li>* Increasing Yield while decreasing Cycle Time</li>
<li>* Solid C/C++ and system building skills</li>
<li>* Excellent understanding of data structures and algorithms</li>
<li>* Self motivated</li>
<li>* Excellent problem solving skills</li>
<li>* Excellent communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">
The successful candidate will have experience building and leading a motivated team of engineers. You’ll be asked to analyze various data sets to look for opportunities to improve yield and overall productivity. You will be responsible assigning tasks to team members, training on new data entry tools, and assessing efficiencies. This manager will be the first point of entry for feedback on new features and usability of software tools. 

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Master of Science degree in Computer Science or similar, alternatively a comparable industry career with a proven track record of successful projects

</p>
</div></body></html>
