<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-48490826">CAD Engineer - HW/SW Interface</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 48490826</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible and cross-functional role as a member of our CAD team, you will be responsible for developing best in class methodologies and flows for Apple silicon for mobile products.

You will interface with multiple Hardware and Software design teams to define and implement methodologies to enable tighter hardware/software design coupling.  These would include but not limited to: standardized hardware register specification, utilities for generating derived file views and automation for the chip specification process.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Architect, develop, maintain and enhance in-house configuration register management software</li>
<li>Interface with multiple software, CAD, program management, hardware design and verification teams to gather specifications for enhancements and drive them to completion</li>
<li>Maintain and develop automated release and regression system</li>
<li>Develop utilities to unify register file generation and corresponding views (RTL, C, HTML, PDF, XML, etc.)</li>
<li>Evaluate commercial and open-source tools for best-in-class HW/SW interface methodology</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline"> 
•Solid programming experience with C/C++, Java and Perl/Python with emphasis on efficient data structures, software quality and robustness

•Excellent communications skills, ability to bridge the hardware/software gap and work cross-functionally

•Hands-on experience with revision control systems (e.g. Git, SubVersion, Perforce, CVS) and data management.  Emphasis on highly robust code, unit and system-level testing, regression and release methodology

•Good understanding of chip design methodology and computer architecture.  Hands-on experience with RTL design (Verilog, VHDL) and design verification (SystemVerilog, SystemC, testbench generation and simulations) is a plus

•Familiarity with one of the following is a big plus: IP-XACT, SystemRDL, UVM, VMM RAL

•Typically requires 5+ experience in HW/SW interface domain
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS or BS Degree in technical discipline. MS is preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
