<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112932711">Siri Software Development Engineer, Proactive Intelligence</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112932711</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 7, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Have you booked a flight and the event was added to your calendar?  Received a text from someone you don't know, but your phone does?   Siri is just beginning to add intelligence across our iOS apps and need your help.  You will work on our full stack.  From optimizing database queries, to power-efficient text processing, to new UI, you will bring the next generation of intelligent features to a next version to millions of Apple users.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in low-level software development and debugging.</li>
<li>Experience shipping software with low-latency and multithreaded programming requirements.</li>
<li>At least 2 years experience working in one of C/C++/Java/Objective-C.</li>
<li>Strong written and verbal communication skills and the ability to work closely with engineering and design teams.</li>
<li>Ability to focus on new assignments and tasks and deliver great results with minimal outside direction.</li>
<li>Knowledge of MacOS and iOS a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You'll be part of a small, talented and motivated team that operates like a startup within Apple. When software breaks, you will ensure it gets fixed by getting the right information to the right person. Sometimes that will mean trying to reproduce a reported problem yourself. Sometimes it will mean working with the reporter. But you won’t just wait for bugs to show up — you’ll actively look for problems before they’re reported and write automated regression tests. You’ll be exposed to our early prototypes and your feedback will help shape them into to something that will be used by millions of people.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/BA, ideally in CS or related technical field Equivalent professional experience of 2 or more years</p>
</div></body></html>
