<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113081450">Full-Stack Java Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113081450</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 28, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Emerging Technology group is looking for an Enterprise Software Engineer to work on a service’s based messaging and data platform.

The candidate would need to demonstrate analytical and organizational skills with proven ability to adapt to a dynamic project development environment.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong programming expertise in Java, Multi-threading, NIO, Akka, NoSQL and XML technologies.</li>
<li>Implemented solutions that handle high availability and concurrency with low latency requirements.</li>
<li>Hands on experience publishing and consuming services - REST/SOAP.</li>
<li>Experience with relational databases such as Oracle is a must. This would include schema design, writing DML queries and performance tuning queries.</li>
<li>Should have a good understanding of storage solutions.</li>
<li>Should have a strong UNIX background and comfortable writing Unix scripts. Perl will be a plus.</li>
<li>Should be able to performance tune application code and assist team members in reviewing code and provide suggestions to developers.</li>
<li>Working knowledge of C preferred.</li>
<li>Exposure to Unix and Mac OS X is desired.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Development of new code and/or managing existing code as part of a group and/or alone.
Ability to develop detailed design and deliver a scalable implementation.
Evaluate products including open-source modules and if need be incorporate them into projects. 
If required willing to take on a technical leadership role
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS degree in computer science or equivalent field with a minimum of 3+ years hands-on programming experience.</p>
</div></body></html>
