<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-47384916">Senior Text-To-Speech Research and Development Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 47384916</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Mar. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for large scale systems, spoken language, big data, and artificial intelligence.  And work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking.  Join the Siri Speech team at Apple.  

The Siri team is looking for exceptionally skilled and creative Engineers eager to get involved in hands-on work improving the Siri experience.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li> Experience building and tuning state of the art parametric and/or unit selection Text-To-Speech systems</li>
<li>Proficiency in C/C++ including the ability to implement software, algorithms and data structures</li>
<li>Experience working with standard speech synthesis toolkits (such as Festival or HTS)</li>
<li>Background of working on TTS systems in multiple languages is preferred</li>
<li>5 or more years of commercial software development experience</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will join a team that is responsible for creating and powering the voice of Siri.    The Siri Text-To-Speech team conducts a wide variety of TTS activities, including  linguistic analysis, statistical modeling, signal processing and voice development.  We are looking for a research and development engineer that has both extensive experience in TTS systems as well as the ability to implement software and solutions for shipping products. 

Because you will be working closely with engineers from a number of other teams at Apple, we are looking for a team player who thrives in a fast paced environment with rapidly changing priorities.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">M.S. or PhD in Computer Science, Computational Linguistics or related field</p>
</div></body></html>
