<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57596443">Software QA Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57596443</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 15, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The iOS Systems QA Team is looking for a creative and motivated QA Engineer with excellent problem solving and communication skills. Quality is an important aspect of our products; as a System QA Engineer, you will have a significant impact on helping to deliver functional and stable products to millions of customers in a fast-paced environment. The ideal candidate will have 3+ years of SQA or System Test experience on consumer-facing hardware/software products, excellent attention to detail and problem solving skills, communication and interpersonal skills, and a passion for quality.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years of SQA or System Test experience, preferably on consumer-facing hardware/software products.</li>
<li>Experience with hardware development lifecycle processes.</li>
<li>Experience testing consumer electronics and/or mobile devices.</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to own a complete functional area of an application or product.</li>
<li>Demonstrated QA skills with at least two complete product cycles, from concept to customer shipment.</li>
<li>Understanding of SQA methodologies &amp; practices.</li>
<li>Ability to solve difficult problems with innovative and maintainable solutions.</li>
<li>Ability to work with cross-functional and remote teams.</li>
<li>Ability to communicate technical concepts to a non-technical audience.</li>
<li>Experience with defect tracking systems and authoring, tracking, and verifying defect reports.</li>
<li>Experience in automation using scripting or other languages (Python, JavaScript, Ruby, Objective-C, Swift, C++, etc.). </li>
<li>Must be detail-oriented and strive for product excellence.</li>
<li>Nice to have:</li>
<li>In-depth understanding of iOS, macOS, or Unix.</li>
<li>Understanding of electronic assembly or manufacturing processes.</li>
<li>Experience working with contract manufacturing firms.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">-Review and test hardware and software features of multiple products.
-Execute a variety of hands-on/manual and automated tests. 
-Create, modify, and execute tests for hardware and software validation at the system level.
-Write test plans and other test documentation as required.
-Use existing automation frameworks and tools to create and execute new tests or test areas.
-Isolate and report defects, quantify impact, and verify fixes through regression testing and other test methodologies.
-Work closely with development teams to identify and understand key hardware and software features and underlying functionality.
-Analyze data from test results; generate reports from that data.
-Work cross-functionally with other test teams, developers, and project managers.
-Be a vocal proponent for quality internally and externally.
-Report status on a regular basis.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS EE/CE/CS or equivalent (MS preferred)</p>
</div></body></html>
