<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112865575">Supply and Execution Product Planner</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112865575</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">WW Retail Fulfillment Operations is seeking a Readiness Analyst / Project Manager to support the systems and process readiness aspects of new product launches, programs and promotions for Apple’s Retail Business (Store and Online). This role is responsible for aligning people, process, and technologies across multiple departments, functions and organizations to ensure flawless program and product launches. This role collaborates with a variety of functions to build the plan of record for each event. These functions include Operations, Marketing, Sales Planning, Supply/Demand Management, Finance, Business Process and Re-engineering, and Logistics. The majority of work is done under strict confidentiality. Must be self-motivated and have a passion to resolve issues in an efficient and effective manner. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Core Functional Skills: Program / Project Management, Operations, Supply Chain, Sales Support, Business Process Mapping. Candidates with Supply/Demand Planning, Logistics and eCommerce experience will be well regarded</li>
<li>Experienced influencer with proven cross-functional experience in establishing cross-cultural business relationships. Looking for proven leaders with broad business mindset to guide the team</li>
<li>Passion and Drive with great sense of urgency. We are looking for someone with tremendous self-belief, motivation and drive to be successful as a leader in the shortest possible time. Excellence should be a habit for the successful candidate</li>
<li>Ability to make key decisions and deliver results under extremely tight timelines, deal with an immense degree of ambiguity, create in an unstructured environment, multi-tasking, drive end-to-end customer focus, think “outside the box” to solve problems</li>
<li>Time management skills - must display great ability to prioritize deliverables to balance speed and accuracy in making the key decision to make or break an NPI launch</li>
<li>Good eye for details with a “hands-on” and “can do” attitude. The learning curve is extremely steep and while training will be provided, a self-starter will greatly enhance the chance of success in this role</li>
<li>Assertive in the right sense with ability to follow through things seamlessly from end-to-end. Strong stamina to get to the finish line with very low tolerance for errors. Display strong troubleshooting skill set</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This role requires a strong driver who can make things happen, lead the resolution of issues, keep people on schedule, mind every detail, and operate under conditions of incomplete information and extreme ambiguity with agility and comfort
Effective communication and problem solving skills are essential. Typical activities include: Defining key dates and schedules for sales execution activities. Identifying a comprehensive set of launch deliverables and ensuring responsible people deliver 
Keeping executives apprised of the plan and escalating needed decisions. Establish single and consistent communications platform to share and maintain business information with internal and external teams
Document and implement new processes effectively through change management and cross-functional collaboration 
Influence decisions through collaboration, leadership and a customer-focused approach. 
Provide world-class leadership to cross-functional and cross-channel Operations and External Business Teams in program / project management of highly complex launches to ensure flawless end-to-end execution to NPI Launch POR
Drive postmortem analysis for each launch to capture learnings for continuous process improvement
Assess current business processes for improvement opportunities. Develop time dependency models for key launch activities including logistical lead times by country
Transform broad concepts and business strategies into structured projects, lead design and delivery of new programs and business processes and provide solutions to complex, high impact issues</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Minimum 5 years experience of technical project management in retail operations, software development, ideally in consumer electronics and/or eCommerce environment. BS/BA degree required. MBA or advanced degree a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
