<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113081127">iTunes Revenue Accountant</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113081127</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Team up with Apple, one of the most influential technology leaders in the in industry. Join the Apple Finance organization and make a positive impact on a company that is known for its impressive line up of products, including Mac, iPod, iPad, iPhone, Apple Watch and Apple Music. At Apple, you’ll share in a dedication to excellence by partnering with extraordinary managers, all with one unified vision – creating innovative products that delight customers. Finance is about “fueling innovation.” We do this by hiring quality individuals with integrity, personal accountability, teamwork, excellence, and proactive thinking. If you exemplify our values and want to be part of something big, contact us today.

We are seeking an iTunes Revenue Accountant join the Global iTunes Revenue Accounting team in Austin, Texas.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>3+ years of relevant accounting experience</li>
<li>Revenue recognition knowledge preferred</li>
<li>Excellent communication, critical, analytical, and interpersonal skills</li>
<li>Ability to partner with cross-functional teams on production work, initiatives, projects, and testing</li>
<li>Ability to work well independently and in a team environment with minimal supervision</li>
<li>Ability to deal with ambiguity in a fast-paced environment</li>
<li>Ability to query, analyze, and reconcile large volumes of data</li>
<li>A sense of humor, a curious mind, an eagerness to learn, and a positive attitude</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Ensure appropriate revenue recognition and deferral for iTunes products
• Manage and resolve exceptions 
• Participate in month-end and quarter-end close: prepare &amp; book journal entries, prepare close deliverables, maintain and reconcile deferred revenue balance sheet accounts
• Ensure all work is in accordance with company policies, U.S. GAAP, and SOx
• Participate in quarterly balance sheet review for account reconciliations
• Articulate how your work affects various partners in their downstream processes
• Drive efficiency and scalability by streamlining or automating processes
• Participate in projects in their entire cycle - from initiation to production go-live
• Train new team members
• Perform ad-hoc requests by management</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• BA/BS degree in Finance or Accounting is required
• CPA or CPA candidate preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
