<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52499723">Senior Software Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52499723</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 7, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are seeking an energetic and self-driven senior software engineer and architect who will play a central role in the delivery of scalable services. As a member of our fast-paced group you will have the unique and rewarding opportunity to be part of a new project and shape upcoming products that will delight and inspire millions of Apple’s customers every day. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of industry experience</li>
<li>Information retrieval techniques and experience with search technologies and systems</li>
<li>Strong technical proficiency in server architecture and development</li>
<li>Strong knowledge in database engines, transaction processing and distributed systems</li>
<li>High competency in at least one of C/C++, Java, Python or similar</li>
<li>Common web services protocols (HTTP, SSL, REST)</li>
<li>Prior experience deploying large-scale services</li>
<li>Self-starter, self-motivated, self-directed, self-sufficient</li>
<li>Excellent communication and teamwork skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This is a unique role within the team, bridging the gap between system development and cloud computing services. You will work in a x-functional team which is developing innovative computer vision/machine learning algorithms and advanced visualization applications. Your responsibilities will include design and implementation of system architectures and work with other engineering teams to ensure that services meet scalability, availability, security, and performance goals.

The successful candidate for this role will solve distributed systems and performance challenges with hands-on competency in a variety of tools, languages, and algorithms.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS / BS Degree in technical discipline required</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience working with international geospatial data
Knowledge in the field of CV/ML/AI</p>
</div></body></html>
