<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113201946">Alloy Quality Engineer- Manufacturing Design</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113201946</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible and hands-on role, you are empowered to tackle difficult challenges and make your actions impactful. We craft unique metal materials that enable us to deliver unprecedented volumes of the highest quality products in the world today, and are seeking an accomplished quality engineer to lead the development and implementation of efficient, effective, and highly scalable quality control solutions throughout our metal materials supply chain. We manage a global network of suppliers across a broad range of materials and form-factors, and we’re seeking creative and flexible solutions to manage complexity in a highly dynamic environment.  Responsibilities include metrology development, measurement SOP’s, product quality plans, capability analyses, data analytics / DOE, and project management / executive communications.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years in a mechanical manufacturing and process control environment</li>
<li>Specialization in raw materials / metals manufacturing a plus</li>
<li>Demonstrated skills in managing global suppliers</li>
<li>Experience developing and evaluating new measurement systems</li>
<li>Mastery of statistical quality tools (GR&amp;R, statistical process control / capability, Design of Experiment, regressions) and efficient manipulation/analysis of data</li>
<li>Demonstrated project management and cross-functional leadership</li>
<li>Experience developing and scaling new quality systems</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">-Investigate and develop new measurement technologies into mature, scalable tools
-Work with suppliers to drive generation of measurement SOP’s and create alignment throughout our supply base
-Evaluate metrology capability through GR&amp;R and cross-vendor correlation studies
-Generate product-specific quality plans to focus on the attributes most important to our customers
-Build quality systems to collect, track, and report data in a highly digestible and actionable format
-Collect, summarize, and interpret quality signals to produce conclusions on process suitability, capability, sources of variation, projected yields, and expected risks
-Design and execute qualification plans to ensure our materials will consistently exceed expectations
-Represent our materials cross-functionally to a broad audience (internal and external)
-Regular international travel (20-30%) to suppliers worldwide
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Education: BS+ in Mechanical, Materials, or Industrial Engineering
</p>
</div></body></html>
