<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52357689">Analog ASIC Design Engineer - CSM</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52357689</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Highly visible role interfacing with internal subsystem development groups and internal/external ASIC development engineering teams to ensure proper specifications, documentation, implementation and validation of the ASICs.  
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>2+ years of technical management experience.</li>
<li>Direct experience and in depth understanding of analog circuit design specifically op-amps, LDO, PMU, PLL, high-speed CDR and SERDES.   </li>
<li>Hands-on design experience with Cadence schematic capture and simulation tools. </li>
<li>Experience with all phases of product development cycle from definition to transfer to production.</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with analog circuit design, chip integration, verification and validation.</li>
<li>Direct involvement with ATE test plan development, review of results and limit setting.</li>
<li>Familiarity with Digital design and PCB signal integrity is a plus.</li>
<li>Some travel is involved.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•Support Subsystem Engineering groups during engineering specification development and feasibility studies.
•Technical management of ASIC suppliers:
 - Establish and review the simulation methodology and verification requirements.
 - ASIC Development schedules.
 - Establish design review report format and perform systematic review of simulations details. 
 - Analyze the circuit designs and provide feedback to ensure robustness of designs.
 - Review T/O verification reports.
 - Review and provide feedback to the vendors about their bench validation and ATE test plans, limits and statistical data.
•Provide support to subsystem engineering teams for analog issues of ASICs, Signal Integrity and components. 
•Work with cross-functional teams on analog issues.
•Co-simulate circuits in Cadence environment.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BSEE +10 years, or MSEE +7 years of analog design experience.
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Some travel required.</p>
</div></body></html>
