<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52855984">Senior IP Design Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52855984</li>
<li title="San Jose, California, United States">San Jose, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 20, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will be at the center of a multimedia IP design effort interfacing with all disciplines, with a critical impact on getting functional products to millions of customers quickly.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 5+ years of experience in multimedia IP/SoC design</li>
<li>• Previous experience in control centric, high performance high throughput designs with deep pipelines and complex flow and data structures, especially with multimedia applications</li>
<li>• Good understanding of system and fabric interface, arbitration, buffer/queue sizing and management, and bandwidth or throughput performance analysis</li>
<li>• Familiar with common on-chip bus protocols such as AMBA (AXI, AHB, APB)</li>
<li>• Experience in frontend implementation tasks such as synthesis, sta, logic equivalence</li>
<li>• Industry exposure to and knowledge of ASIC/FPGA design methodology</li>
<li>• Excellent collaboration skills</li>
<li>• Outstanding written and verbal communications</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a senior IP Design engineer you will have responsibilities spanning all aspects of multimedia IP design
• Collaborate with platform architecture team to define, analyze, and document micro-architecture specifications
• Perform feasibility analysis on suggested architecture(s) and algorithm(s)
• Perform RTL design and logic implementation of agreed architecture
• Perform front end implementation tasks such as synthesis, logic equivalence check, STA</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•BSEE / MSEE is required</p>
</div></body></html>
