<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113033874">Motion Scientist, Fitness and Health Algorithms</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113033874</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 15, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Join our Motion Technologies team and drive innovation that matters! Our ever-evolving suite of fitness and health features in Watch and iPhone are helping our users live more active, healthier lives. We are looking for a highly motivated algorithm scientist to join our team and work on designing and validating next generation of Health and Fitness features.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Expertise and experience in various aspects of signal processing, statistical modeling, and machine learning.</li>
<li>Experience with algorithm design using sensors on mobile devices, validating algorithms and characterizing performance.</li>
<li>Ability to design user studies, and perform data analysis to extract actionable insights</li>
<li>Excellent technical communication skills</li>
<li>Enthusiasm for working on fitness and health features</li>
<li>Excellent MATLAB skills. Familiarity with C++ is a plus. Working knowledge of Big Data Technologies (e.g. MapReduce, Hadoop stack) is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for a scientist to join us in creating next generation of fitness and health features that utilize motion and other sensors in Apple products. As a member of this team, you will be responsible for designing and validating algorithms, creating user studies, analyzing data, communicating with stakeholders and working with our multi-disciplinary team to ship these features. </p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">PhD or 5+ years experience in Mechanical Engineering, Electrical Engineering, Computer Science or related field with relevant domain knowledge.
Coursework in signal processing, statistics, machine learning, controls, and programming</p>
</div></body></html>
