<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55335945">Security Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55335945</li>
<li title="Cincinnati, Ohio, United States">Cincinnati, Ohio, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Internet Services Organization is seeking a Security Engineer focused on building solutions to secure web sites, services, and data centers.This is a technical, hands-on role in a dynamic and fast paced environment. The candidate will need a good mixture of software engineering know-how, risk assessment methodology, and security engineering practices and tooling.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Passionate about securing Apple’s products &amp; customers</li>
<li>Expert familiarity with multiple programming languages and secure coding practices</li>
<li>Able to discuss risk assessments with audiences of various technical &amp; business backgrounds</li>
<li>Experience integrating security practices into product focused engineering teams</li>
<li>Ability to identify gaps in security focused tooling &amp; lead a peer group through project planning, scheduling, and execution</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will:
Engineer solutions to secure Apple's internet services including: iCloud, iTunes, Maps, Siri, &amp; others
Build and improve critical security infrastructure services including: authentication, detection &amp; response, web application security, data center security, operations security
Develop fixes to complex vulnerabilities
Work with engineers to threat model new projects and design responsive controls to ensure end-to-end customer protection
Lead cutting-edge security efforts at a scale you’ll only be able to find at Apple
Work cross-functionally with teams throughout Apple in all phases of the secure development lifecycle of products and services</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors in Computer Science or Engineering or equivalent experience
</p>
</div></body></html>
