<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113115739">System Integration Test Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113115739</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s engineering team focusing on autonomous technology is looking for a System Integration Test Engineer for the Hardware Integration Test Team.

The team commissions and tests system level hardware/software functions spanning numerous different technology disciplines.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>To succeed within this role, you should have solid experience in several of the following areas:</li>
<li>A genuine passion for diagnosing hardware, software, and process issues</li>
<li>Strong EE fundamentals in analog/digital design, communications, sensors, power, embedded systems, etc.  </li>
<li>Demonstrated critical thinking on system designs, ability to identify potential risk areas</li>
<li>Familiar with OS tools, shell scripting, file system manipulation and process management</li>
<li>Ability to quickly bridge core engineering knowledge into new technology disciplines</li>
<li>Excellent Communication skills, role will require close cooperation with multiple design teams</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Comprehensive analysis of the System EE design, development of systematic methods for definition of tests, and continuous assessment of tests coverage
Collaboration with hardware and software design teams to develop test/validation goals and objectives
Definition of test setups, identification and construction of specialized test environments to support system commissioning and testing
Commissioning of system level hardware/software functions spanning numerous different technology disciplines.
Support sub-system teams for troubleshooting system level issues
Automation of systematic tasks: system design analysis, database queries, execution of tests, operation of test equipment
Development of new testing systems to support new technology development
Definition and execution of test runs, results processing, archiving and reporting
Regular communication of system maturity and validation status to leadership
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS in Electrical Engineering, Computer Engineering or equivalent required</p>
</div></body></html>
