<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113147248">Physical Design Verification - Flows</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113147248</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 13, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As a senior member of our CAD team, you will architect, develop, maintain and enhance physical design verification (PDV) flows. The role requires the candidate to work and lead development of flows for the different technology nodes and tool sets. Working alongside with CAD team, you will be interfacing with the custom digital/analog/mixed-signal design and physical design (PD) teams. You will need to have a deep understanding of design rule checks for (DRC) and LVS runsets, writing from scratch and/or modify existing ones. Also you should have worked with the Design for Manufacturability (DFM) rules at different geometries. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Typically requires 10+ years of industry experience in chip design process.</li>
<li>At least 3+ years of technical management or technical leadership experience in physical verification</li>
<li>Very efficient programming capabilities in Perl, TCL, C, Makefile</li>
<li>Expert in Calibre or Hercules/ICV runset programming for DRC/LVS/ERC/PERC/DFM</li>
<li>Knowledge of parasitic extraction and its interface with Calibre/Hercules a plus</li>
<li>Tapeout experience in various technology nodes</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Develop, maintain and enhance flows for all aspects of physical verification and methodology. 
Coordinate/Lead effort of validating the flows, enhancing for custom checks and data generation
Interact with the design and PD teams to facilitate the chip design process
Familiar with the Electrical rule checks (ERC) and Programmable ERCs
Deep understanding of sub-micron technology nodes and its challenges
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS in EE/CS/CE or equivalent</p>
</div></body></html>
