<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-99607317">Siri Integration Engineer - Music</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 99607317</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Play a part in the next revolution in human-computer interaction. Contribute to a product that is redefining mobile computing. Create groundbreaking technology for artificial intelligence. Help create a smarter, safer way to use your iPhone in your car, and work with the people who created the intelligent assistant that helps millions of people get things done — just by asking. Join the Siri team at Apple.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Ability to understand large scale software &amp; system architecture.</li>
<li>Proficient experience with programming languages and logic (Java preferred.)</li>
<li>Able to communicate technical issues with technical &amp; non-technical folks alike.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">This position involves a combination of technical troubleshooting, clear communication and meticulous organization skills. We need a team player — you will be collaborating with engineers in several technical areas who have created the entire range of Siri's capabilities. We also need someone who is comfortable working in a fast-paced environment with rapidly changing priorities.

Triage &amp; prioritize incoming feature enhancements and functionality regressions that may arise, ensuring that the tickets are appropriately categorized.
Perform initial issue investigation, with the ability to clearly summarize findings.
Test pre-submission engineering changes.
Participate in engineering design and feature discussions.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS in Computer Science or equivalent and 1+ year of industry experience.</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience integrating data and services from multiple providers
Experience with AI technologies including NLP or machine learning
Prior experience with in-car phone, navigation or entertainment systems, or map and local search technology, is a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
