<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113057335">iCloud Software Engineer (Photo Library and Photo Sharing)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113057335</li>
<li title="SF - Corporate, California, United States">SF - Corporate, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.
Join iCloud's CloudKit server engineering team to work on iCloud Photo Library and iCloud Photo Sharing. iCloud Photo Library stores every photo and video you take, and keeps them up to date on all your devices. Any edits you make are automatically updated everywhere. iCloud Photo Sharing makes it easy to share photos and videos with exactly the people you want to see them.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5 or more years software engineering experience and responsibilities</li>
<li>Solid experience in Java on high-throughput applications</li>
<li>Experience designing, implementing and supporting scalable distributed systems</li>
<li>Ability to give and receive technical feedback in code and design reviews</li>
<li>Ability to thrive in a cross-functional team on high profile, critical projects</li>
<li>Excellent analytical and problem solving skills</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The CloudKit server team is looking for a software engineer with a passion for building large-scale Internet applications that can keep up with the demands of hundreds of millions of users. You should have demonstrable experience building high-performing systems that are scalable and extensible. 

Interest in some or all of the following is a bonus:

Scripting languages such as Python
Distributed database systems
iOS and OS X application development
Security and encryption
Digital photography</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's or Master's degree in Computer Science or equivalent industry experience</p>
</div></body></html>
