<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113209922">Full-Stack E-Commerce Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113209922</li>
<li title="Santa Clara (FMK), California, United States">Santa Clara (FMK), California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">FileMaker, Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of Apple Inc., the leading standalone desktop database company, is searching for a full-stack Senior Software Engineer to design and implement major features of new products. FileMaker has an established product line and large customer base. We are advancing the existing technologies and developing new and exciting technologies and products. This position is located in Santa Clara, CA. This position designs and implements major features of new products in Cloud and E-Commerce with the guidance of Product Management and Marketing.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of strong experience with Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of modern web techniques such as JAMstack</li>
<li>Strong hands-on experience with Cloud infrastructure (AWS or Azure preferred)</li>
<li>Strong architecture skills in both front end and back end</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with REST</li>
<li>Experience with architecting and designing modern e-commerce systems</li>
<li>Good understanding of PCI compliance requirement</li>
<li>Good understanding of SaaS</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with SQL and NoSQL systems</li>
<li>Strong object-oriented design techniques and reusable component design</li>
<li>Strong analysis, problem solving, and troubleshooting skills</li>
<li>Strong verbal and written communications skills</li>
<li>Experience with PHP, Zend Framework (not required, but a plus)</li>
<li>Experience architecting and developing multi-threaded systems (not required, but a plus)</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with multi-threaded programming (not required, but a plus)</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Design major features of new products in Cloud and E-Commerce technologies
Implement innovative features on time with excellent quality
Create functional specifications and designs
Implement major features of new products
Create unit tests for features
Work with QA to ensure the top quality of the feature</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science or equivalent. MSCS or Ph.D. is preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
