<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-33934954">Engineering Program Manager - CSM</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 33934954</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Aug. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Silicon Program Manager, you will utilize your Program / Project management skills and have responsibility for driving Silicon program schedules and resolving technical issues that enable on-time quality Silicon delivery to Apple products.  In this role you will be expected to manage full Silicon cycle from initial concept, through implementation, validation and qualification to mass production.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of experience managing a full SOC design flow, from concept to mass production.</li>
<li>2+ years of technical Program or Project Management experience.</li>
<li>Good understanding of hardware and software integration challenges.</li>
<li>Good understanding of both analog and digital design and development flows.</li>
<li>Experience working in a dynamic fast-paced engineering environment and real-time crisis management skills.</li>
<li>Strong desire to own/drive project development using well defined metrics.</li>
<li>Excellent inter-personal and communication skills.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•You will work as part of a PM team responsible for driving technical issue resolution to enable on-time silicon to meet aggressive product schedules
•Driving internal processes to guarantee high quality Silicon definition and timely execution
•Supporting high-level milestone execution in a fast paced core technology design teams
•Driving Silicon issues with cross-functional teams at Apple and with vendors: Design, Verification, Validation, Process Technology, Packaging, Quality and Reliability, System Hardware and Core Software. 
•Focusing design teams on meeting milestones and unblocking technical issues by pulling together the right cross-functional technical expert(s) to resolve issues with emphasis on data-driven decisions. 
•Driving technical sessions with suppliers to track &amp; follow up on issues/escalations. Willing to travel frequently to vendor sites, as needed.
•Highly disciplined issue reporting, bug tracking, and communication of program risks &amp; status.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor Degree in Engineering. Masters Degree is an advantage.</p>
</div></body></html>
