<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113186533">Senior Ontologist - Siri</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113186533</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Siri NL team is creating groundbreaking technology for machine learning, natural language processing, and artificial intelligence. The features we create are redefining how hundreds of millions of people use their computers and mobile devices in their day to day tasks. As a Senior Ontologist, you will have the opportunity to directly and significantly impact Siri's ability to understand and execute, by designing and building strategies and standards for Siri's Ontology.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum of 5+ years experience with building taxonomies, data classification, or creating metadata schemas</li>
<li>Proven taxonomy design judgement with the ability to translate business use cases into sound taxonomy design</li>
<li>Great track record of working with engineering and product teams</li>
<li>A deep curiosity and fundamental knowledge about natural language understanding, representation, and data management</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Develop ontologies, data models, and standards to define and organize Siri's understanding and execution components
Identify mapping approaches for conversion between different ontologies
Own requirements related to ontology tools, metrics, and process improvements
Validate and review requests for ontology changes
Work with teams to capture and integrate ontology requirements across components

</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Familiarity with lexical semantics
Understanding of current approaches to NLP and semantic analysis
Familiarity with Python, Java, C++, or other equivalent programming languages
</p>
</div></body></html>
