<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113124387">Hardware Allocations- Engineering Project Manager</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113124387</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 12, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Software Engineering - Hardware Management team is looking for an Engineering Project Manager passionate about building relationships and large-scale logistics.  The Hardware Allocations EPM role works cross-functionally across many teams at Apple to allocate development hardware and identify and resolve issues in support of software engineering.  The ideal candidate has the ability to balance technical prowess with proactive customer service in a fast-paced, dynamic environment. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Outstanding customer service skills</li>
<li>Advanced knowledge of iOS, OS X and WatchOS product lifecycles</li>
<li>Demonstrated decision making skills in an engineering environment</li>
<li>Ability to quickly establish and manage complex cross-functional relationships</li>
<li>Detail oriented with strong project management lifecycle skills</li>
<li>Experience with relational databases, such as FileMaker and MySQL</li>
<li>At least 2 years project management experience in an engineering environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Hardware Allocations EPM, you will be responsible for:

Managing complex business relationships and hardware demand for all SWE teams
Utilizing advanced engineering knowledge to analyze, interpret and make deductions based on previous experience and business patterns
Maintain accurate and detailed hardware allocation database and library of units to support unexpected demand
Prioritizing hardware processing and allocations based on engineering justification to drive development schedules
Effectively identify program level challenges and constraints through cross-functional relationships
Partnering with factories and international teams to drive shipping and receiving of development hardware
Lead strategic initiatives to increase team efficiency, process management and cost savings
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS/MS EE/CS/CE or equivalent</p>
</div></body></html>
