<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113040109">Electrical Engineer (FPGA Design)</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113040109</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 18, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Apple Engineering Team is looking for an enthusiastic, creative, and self driven FPGA Design engineer with good understanding of Electrical Engineering. The candidate will work in a small team of HW, FPGA &amp; SW engineers who collaboratively build functional Prototypes of Display technologies, which eventually find their way in Apple’s future products.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Min. 2 years of experience utilizing Xilinx Vivado Tool chain.</li>
<li>Min. 2 years of hands-on experience with FPGA architecture, design, coding, simulating, and debugging FPGA on actual HW.</li>
<li>Strong understanding how your HDL/RTL code will be synthesized into FPGA fabric. Code for performance!</li>
<li>Knowledge on FPGA’s HW requirements - DC Power supplies, Terminations, Signal Integrity.</li>
<li>Hands-on experience using any 7 series Xilinx FPGAs -  Artix-7, Kintex-7, Virtex-7, UltraScale, Zynq etc.</li>
<li>Built FPGA designs involving high-performance interfaces like DDR2/3/4, LVDS, DSPs, Ethernet, etc.</li>
<li>Knowledge &amp; Experience using low-speed data/control interfaces like SPI, UART, I2C etc.</li>
<li>Knowledge of FPGA fabric - Clock Regions, Bank IO Constraints, Clocking resources - CMTs, PLLs, DLLs etc. </li>
<li>Understanding static timing analysis, and ability to read timing reports &amp; fix timing issues in RTL.</li>
<li>Must have practical lab debugging skills to bring-up FPGA designs on actual PCBs using Oscilloscope, Protocol Analyzers</li>
<li>Ability to work effectively in a cross-functional product development HW &amp; SW teams.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Strong Analytical aptitude and meticulous attention to detail.
Demonstrate creativity in problem solving, ability to think out-of-box, and adapt quickly to new technical areas.
Create and give presentations before and after prototyping new ideas.
Participate in FPGA design - RTL coding, module &amp; system level test bench design, simulation, synthesis and HW bring-up.
Participate in HW design reviews, and help improve existing design.
Communicate and demonstrate prototypes to Cross-Functional Teams.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS/BS in Electrical Engineering.
MS with 2+ years, or BS with 3+ years of relevant FPGA Design experience.
</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Micro-controller / Xilinx Microblaze experience is a Plus.
EE Schematics &amp; Board Design/Layout experience is a Plus.
FW Development experience using C/C++ is a Plus.
Scripting or Test Automation is a Plus.
</p>
</div></body></html>
