<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-51983762">SoC Product Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 51983762</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role you will be responsible for New Product Introduction (NPI) and defining problems by identifying failure modes related to a SoC.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate should have at least 5+ years of product engineering experience of SoC's in a high volume environment.</li>
<li>Experience handling ATE test program for characterization and data collection.</li>
<li>Knowledge to perform statistical data analysis.</li>
<li>Experience in yield management of high volume product.</li>
<li>Ability to setup design of experiment to drive the root cause of the problem.</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills to work with internal team members and external suppliers.</li>
<li>Travel is required</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">•New Product Introduction of SoC and support mass production needs
•Perform data analysis, characterization and fault isolation to determine the root cause of the issues
•Work with design, process and test engineers to identify and implement corrective actions on both new and mature products and technologies.
•Define and finalize production screening guard-band specifications based upon design intent and characterization result
•Perform statistical data analysis on mass data set
•Perform yield analyses and correlation analyses for all levels of test, pareto building, statistics, etc.
•Define characterization plan and generate characterization report
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•BSEE/MSEE or equivalent is required</p>
</div></body></html>
