<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52159706">Camera Image Quality Engineer - Camera Hardware</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52159706</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 26, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Camera Hardware Engineering group is responsible for all research, design, development, test, and qualification of camera hardware for Apple products. This team is seeking an exceptional Camera Image Quality Engineer with responsibilities for ongoing evaluation, benchmarking and characterization of Apple camera products.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong knowledge of Image Sensor operation and tuning</li>
<li>Thorough understanding of image quality metrics and evaluation methodology</li>
<li>Strong Matlab programming skills on digital image processing and data analysis</li>
<li>Ideal candidates will also have familiarity with Python programming</li>
<li>Familiarity with megapixel CMOS image sensor technology, lens selection and qualification, implementation of camera systems in mobile products, and be familiar with imaging algorithms (auto-exposure, auto white balance, auto-focus, ...etc.)</li>
<li>Experience with objective camera bench testing and subjective image quality analysis.</li>
<li>Familiarity with camera components and functions</li>
<li>Support design team through iterative testing and ongoing support from early prototype to product launch.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Developing/performing lab type testing and software for camera evaluation 
Development of imager test techniques
Optimization in imager sensor settings
Optimization of ISPs
Design/support of production line testing setups
Performing testing/data analysis on benchmark products
Delivering executive level presentations of results</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">MS/PhD in Electrical Engineering or equivalent</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Travel to both Apple and suppliers' facilities will be required for production bring up.
Experience with mobile communication products is an advantage.
</p>
</div></body></html>
