<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52347662">IC Packaging Engineer, Simulation</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52347662</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 14, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for a self-motivated individual who is proficient in FEM simulation with multi-year hands-on experience of FEM software ASNSY or ABAQUS.  The individual should also be an expert programmer of numerical simulation tools, such as: MatLab and/or Python.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Solid training in mechanics and mathematics</li>
<li>Hands-on experience of major FEM tools (e.g., ANSYS, ABAQUS, Hypermesh, etc.)</li>
<li>Familiar with numerical simulation software tools.  Expert programmer of MatLab and/or Scientific Python</li>
<li>Good understanding of electronic packaging materials and their mechanical behaviors</li>
<li>Knowledge of electronic packaging structures and processes</li>
<li>Knowledge of reliability of electronic packages and package qualification requirements</li>
<li>Experience with setting up data acquisition systems</li>
<li>Able to perform independent research and development work</li>
<li>Good written and verbal communication skills; Able to present ideas, design concepts, data and plan with high confidence at team meetings</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Numerical modeling of the stress and deformation of component packages to provide comprehensive understanding of chip-package interaction and package-board interaction to ensure good device yield and reliability
• Programming CAD tools, FEM software, and numerical tools to set up automated model-generation user interfaces and maintain those codes
• Characterization of component packages under various environmental and reliability loading conditions, and also key packaging materials
• Setting up measurement systems (including programming DAQs) for the characterization of packages of various components
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• PhD degree in Mechanical Engineering, Engineering Mechanics, Materials Science, Physics or related fields
</p>
</div></body></html>
