<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112926266">HR Business Partner- Hardware</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112926266</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The promise of working at Apple is the opportunity to do your best work - ultimately contributing to products and services that enrich the lives of millions of people.  Delivering on this promise requires commitment from individual employees, their managers and their leaders.  The stewards of this promise, however, are the HR Business Partners.  HRBPs at Apple facilitate and influence the dialogue and decisions that impact employees, and ensure that conditions are enabling people’s best work.  They partner closely with leaders on short-term and long-term strategies, balancing competing needs and approaches, and arriving at the best decisions for a given situation.  This is a unique opportunity to partner with and support the Hardware Engineering Products teams at Apple. Hardware Engineering is a critical and strategic imperative for the company, delivering products that provide the highest quality experience our Customers expect and deserve.  </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in an HR management, generalist, and/or business partnering role within a complex environment.</li>
<li>Strong interpersonal communications skills, including influencing and ability to encourage innovation. </li>
<li>Highly collaborative style and flexible approach.  Willingness and demonstrated ability to work in teams, as both a lead and a supporting team member. </li>
<li>Ability to coach, mentor and advise where appropriate to help employees grow and develop in alignment with business and personal goals. </li>
<li>Ability to execute foundational Project Management skills where needed and appropriate </li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, you will closely partner with key business leaders, by aligning HR strategy with business strategies.  You will provide a full spectrum of both strategic and tactical HR support and programs on a global basis to employees and managers.

Business Knowledge:  Ensure depth of understanding of organizations supported, including key business functions and processes.

Connects People, Teams and Organizations:  Ensures the right information gets to leaders and key stakeholders throughout the organization.  Finds ways for managers and senior leaders to create meaningful connections with their team members and with each other.  Bridges teams, regions, and individuals, identifying opportunities and mediating issues within the organization.

Culture:  Develop knowledge and skills to be able to reinforce the Apple culture with leaders and employees.  Partner with Apple University and business leaders to develop programs and initiatives which help educate and reinforce Apple culture with teams.  Uses both data and observations to monitor the morale and motivation of the organization.  Consistently assesses the organizational effectiveness of all aspects of the employee life cycle.  Puts programs in place that help managers and leaders build community and address the specific needs of their teams.
Coaches:  Is seen as a trusted and knowledgeable member of the leadership team for the organizations supported.  Provides positive and constructive feedback to leaders.  Guides managers and senior leaders making talent decisions, from everyday decisions to challenging situations.  Helps managers and senior leaders resolve conflict within their teams or with their peers across Apple.  Collaborates with employee relations partners on complex legal and employee relations issues.
Advances the Talent Strategy:  Drives a talent strategy to meet the short and long term needs of the business and Apple.  Diagnoses trends for the organization (growth, attrition, performance, succession) and alerts leaders about trends to watch.  Knows the top talent in the organization and ensures plans are in place to support their growth and development. 

Compensation &amp; Benefits:  Advise and support line management on local and global compensation and benefits initiatives.  Competence in interpreting internal compensation framework and external market survey data.  Identifying emerging trends.  Partner with management and Benefits to assist with the management of leaves, disabilities, and Worker’s Compensation.
Special Projects:  Develop and work on special and cross-functional projects as needed.  Examples include Division HR project, site specific (Austin, Sacramento, Cupertino) projects and global projects.


Training:  Understand the training/development needs of organization and act as liaison with Corporate Training to deliver or secure appropriate training to the organization.  Author and deliver curriculum for site- and division-specific brown bags and training.
</p>
</div></body></html>
