<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55595432">Associate Creative Director, Writing, Marcom Interactive </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55595432</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 26, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for an Associate Creative Director/Copywriter to join our interactive marketing team.
You’ll lead a small group of writers in brainstorming digital campaigns. Developing site concepts. Crafting the kind of fun, thoughtful headlines Apple is known for. And writing long-form websites for new product launches, as well as corporate initiatives like education and the environment. This is a chance for you to do the best work of your career — and have it seen by the millions of people who visit  <a class="bridgeLink" target="_blank" href="http://apple.com">apple.com</a> each month. Beyond directing the creative, you’ll serve as a dedicated mentor and manager, giving younger writers the support they need to build their skills and take the work to new places.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>10+ years of experience writing and providing creative direction for traditional or digital agencies, in-house marketing teams, or digital publications. Along with references.</li>
<li>A killer portfolio full of major marketing campaigns, corporate websites, social campaigns, articles, blogs, or work in other digital channels.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Know what’s happening with your writers and enable them to knock their projects out of the park.
Build close partnerships with the world’s best Design and UX ACDs.
Help come up with creative ways to launch products, tell product stories, and build out websites — all firmly rooted in the content strategy.
Steer the work to keep it surprising and fresh, yet unmistakably Apple.
Work with product marketing teams to translate technical features into meaningful customer benefits.
Write, review, and edit hundreds of headlines for each project.
Master the Apple tone of voice and deliver copy that makes advanced technology easy to understand.
Collaborate with CDs and Editors to refine (and refine and refine and refine) copy until it’s our best possible work.
Confidently articulate ideas and present work to CDs, product marketing teams, and Apple execs.
Ensure that schedules are realistic (or at least kind of realistic) and deadlines are met.
Report to the CD for product launch, values, and campaign work, keeping him or her up to speed on projects.
Keep up to date on the latest Apple products, solutions, and related technologies.
Be a collaborative team player who’s fun to work with.
Offer genuine guidance and support to your direct reports.
Be highly engaged in your partnerships with the Design and UX ACDs.
Deliver exceptional headlines and copy.
Keep the work on strategy and make meaningful contributions to each project.
Motivate the team to do their best work time and time again.
Be hyper-focused on details and product accuracy.
Set an example of resilience when we have to leave good ideas behind (in pursuit of great ones).
Deliver websites that constantly push the creative forward.
Put innovative ideas out there — and inspire others to do so.
Be willing to take risks, fail, and learn from mistakes.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's degree preferred.
</p>
</div></body></html>
