<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-86503432">Data Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 86503432</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 11, 2017</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple's Global Business Intelligence team is seeking an experienced Data Engineer to be part of GBI Sales reporting area, who will be responsible for delivering highly performance optimized reporting solutions. 

The GBI Sales team is responsible for building smart, intuitive applications for Apple’s Sales business teams, which encompass engineering ingenuity in easy to software product.

The ideal candidate for this position will be able think out of the box and come up with solutions quickly to help business in making time sensitive decisions, have strong communication and analytical skills, passion for data visualization, always drives for excellence and self motivated.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Work closely with Analytics, Product teams to understand data and analysis requirements </li>
<li>Design and build dimensional data models and schema designs to improve accessibility, efficiency, and quality of data</li>
<li>Develop the ETL for data induction and implement the application logic to meet the business requirements</li>
<li>Strong understanding of analytics needs and proactive-ness to build generic solutions to improve the efficiency</li>
<li>Develops new reports and perform ad-hoc reporting by working independently </li>
<li>Benchmark application performance periodically and fix performance issues</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Should be an expert in one or few of the following database platforms - Teradata, Hadoop, Oracle, Vertica, SAP HANA, MySQL, MongoDB.
Expertise in a programming language - Python, Java, C, C++, JavaScript, Swift, Unix scripting
Experience with design and development of ETL processes
Fluent in writing Advanced SQLs
Must have good experience in development of unix shell scripts 
Performance tuning of SQL queries 
Experience in developing automated test scripts to help with regression testing 
Sharp troubleshooting skills to identify and fix issues quickly. 
Data modeling experience in building Logical and Physical data model
Experience in building Tableau Dashboards is a plus
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Graduate degree required in Computer Science or related field
5+ years of experience in the related field
</p>
</div></body></html>
