<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52810475">Test Engineering Manager - Maps Search </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52810475</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 21, 2016</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Maps Test Engineering tests some of the most complex systems around, and we need an experienced engineering manager that can work to understand requirements cross-functionally and ensure we deliver better features faster with great quality. You’re a leader with track record of attracting, retaining, and growing test engineers to create a self organized and highly empowered team. You’re equally happy diving deep into a technology area as you are providing guidance and process to get teams pointed in the right direction. Test Engineering is a growing area within Maps, and so we need a manager that knows how to scale a highly technical team.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Minimum 5 years experience leading a highly technical test engineering team</li>
<li>Exceptional written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to recruit and lead teams of test engineers</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to architect testing processes and automation frameworks</li>
<li>Excels at organizing cross functional testing efforts</li>
<li>Experience testing clients that interface with sophisticated services</li>
<li>Strong understanding of Search technologies and customer pain points</li>
<li>Hands on GIS knowledge (into data levels) is strongly preferred</li>
<li>Proficiency in Python or another programming language is a plus</li>
<li>Experience with Linux/Unix operating systems and networking</li>
<li>Proven bug detection and bug isolation skills</li>
<li>Creative thinker and strong problem solver</li>
<li>A passion for user-focused design and a seamless customer experience</li>
<li>Strong hands on experience testing complex client/server environments</li>
<li>Comfortable and adaptable in a fast-paced and informal environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">
The Maps team is seeking a strong leader to build and scale the test engineering team for Maps Search. In addition to building and mentoring an exceptional test engineering team, you will coordinate large scale testing efforts across Apple to ensure successful Maps client releases.

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science or equivalent experience.
</p>
</div></body></html>
