<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-84004064">SWE Security Infrastructure Web Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 84004064</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 29, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Software Delivery is seeking an experienced web developer to join our team and help create outstanding tools for monitoring and visualizing key systems. Software Delivery creates, deploys, and operates systems and services that build Apple’s software products.

This role will have a wide range of responsibilities, from creating visualizations for existing data to working cross-functionally to improve our monitoring capabilities from the ground up. The work environment is fast paced and dynamic, requiring the ability to work autonomously and balance the needs of multiple different business priorities. Suitable candidates should have excellent problem solving skills and a passion to improve existing process and systems. The right mix of technical, organizational, and communication skills is key to success. Attention to detail and a proven ability to manage priorities are essential.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>2+ years experience in web development</li>
<li>Background in security, networking, and web protocols</li>
<li>Hands-on experience with Linux/UNIX operating systems </li>
<li>Scripting and automation expertise with Linux/UNIX operating systems</li>
<li>Great written and verbal communication skills; ability to create procedures and document processes</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Job Responsibilities

- Develop visualization and monitoring applications for SWE services using appropriate technologies (Splunk et al)
- Identify areas that need additional data to be useful and actionable, and drive for the collection and monitoring of that data
- Work with development teams during new service development to determine monitoring requirements for security and reliability of the service

Preferred Experience

- Development experience with Splunk 
- Development experience with Ruby and/or Python
- JavaScript expertise
- Exposure to Perl programming</p>
</div></body></html>
