<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-57109414">Web UI Developer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 57109414</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: May. 8, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking to hire outstanding individuals to join our team of Site Reliability and Software Engineers. Build tools that help us run the platform that delivers Apple’s services to all of it’s customers around the world. Help us build the Apple experience on a global scale.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience delivering rich Web UI experiences, from concept to completion</li>
<li>Proficiency with modern UI frameworks such as React, Django, Bootstrap, node.js</li>
<li>Preferred Python, fine with other language like Ruby, Perl, Java, C</li>
<li>Familiar with JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, and Javascripts with 2-5 years experience in this area</li>
<li>Knowledge of Mysql or other database</li>
<li>Knowledge of networking is a plus</li>
<li>Knowledge of Linux environment</li>
<li>Knowledge of GIT or other source control system</li>
<li>Ability to express ideas clearly within the team and across other groups.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Leverage skills to build tools with rich and innovative UI that help us measure and deliver world class availability.
Building software and systems to manage network infrastructure and applications through automation.
Building software and systems to measure, monitor, and optimize network availability and service levels.
Collaborating on and influencing software designs and architectures.
Explore and evaluate new technologies and solutions to push our capabilities forward, getting ahead of our customers’ needs, getting people incentivized to transform, innovate, and relentlessly pursue availability.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
