<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113183173">Senior Software Engineer - Big Data</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113183173</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 31, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Are you passionate about developing data platforms at scale? Do you love the idea of solving a new business, technical problem every other day with open source technologies? Do you have it in you to be part of a fast paced growing environment with many exciting responsibilities? If so, Apple’s Global Business Intelligence (GBI) team is looking for highly motivated, detail oriented, technical savvy, energetic professionals who like to think outside the box! </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>4+ years of experience in professional programming experience</li>
<li>A strong foundation in Computer Science fundamentals such as data structures and algorithms is required</li>
<li>Experience with Java or scala programming language</li>
<li>Familiarity with Hadoop</li>
<li>Familiarity with Hive and Spark is a plus </li>
<li>Passionate about Big Data technologies</li>
<li>Working knowledge of the full SW development lifecycle</li>
<li>Proven ability to develop and ship high quality software products</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The GBI Hadoop Engineering team in responsible for building tools and frameworks that many application depend on to analyze Apple’s big data.  We use the latest big data technologies.  We’re looking for someone who is passionate about working in team to build platform which can live up to Apple’s high standards.   As a part of our team you’ll be responsible for designing and developing well engineered creative solutions to solve our business needs.  You’ll be working at the framework and application level.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS CS, BS MIS or equivalent</p>
</div></body></html>
