<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54568492">Business Analyst, iTunes Retail Gift Cards </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54568492</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jul. 14, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking to fill a key analyst role supporting the iTunes Gift Cards Business within the iTunes Retail for the Asia Pacific region (APAC).   This candidate will be responsible for supporting the implementation of iTunes Gift Cards related sales/marketing/merchandising programs by providing insights on sales trends, promotion effectiveness, business risks, and opportunities for APAC.   Specifically, the candidate will manage sales forecast creation, generate reports on sales, conduct promotion, marketing and merchandising effectiveness studies, track key business metrics and train the Gift Cards Team on standard usage of sales reports, dashboards and tools.  This candidate will play a critical role in enabling the Gift Cards Team to achieve Apple financial and customer experience goals.   A successful candidate is highly motivated, team oriented, able to work independently and strong in communication with the proven ability to analyze data effectively and thoroughly.  The candidate will be located in Cupertino but will be supporting the APAC region, requiring flexible work hours.   The Data mining experience working with R and Python is a plus. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>▪   Exceptional analytical and data gathering skills</li>
<li>▪   Top knowledge in working with databases including Excel, BO and SQL</li>
<li>▪   Strong experience of finance and/or business analysis in the retail, technology or internet industry</li>
<li>▪   Solutions-driven approach to systems and processes</li>
<li>▪   Ability to meet deadlines, prioritize workloads while maintaining strong attention to detail and working independently in a fast paced and rapidly changing environment</li>
<li>▪   Strong communication skills with the ability to present data and insights in a clear, concise manner to stakeholders with varying levels of experience with data and analytics</li>
<li>▪   Positive energy &amp; attitude with a desire to drive constant improvement and change with creativity</li>
<li>▪   Experience in using SAS or other statistical software</li>
<li>▪   Working knowledge of Linear Programming, Optimization, and forecasting methodologies that model seasonality and trend such as R and Python</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Provide analytics that support Sales/Marketing/Merchandising decisions for the iTunes Gift Cards Team (impact of promotions, merchandising, in-store placement modifications and etc.,)
Understand sales strategy, and how variables such as historical performance, seasonality, promotions, and macro economic factors affect current business trends
Provide sales forecasts, budget planning, and presentations to support the business
Understand the reasons behind forecast vs. actual variance to continuously improve forecast accuracy and to influence sales strategy 
Provide weekly, monthly and quarterly reporting of sales, market share and other key business data to management
Responsible for data maintenance and clean-up
Unveil revenue drivers such as market development opportunities and efficiencies optimization
Prepare data driven insights and recommendations to help strategic decision making
Build metrics and business cases based on existing best practice examples
Provide standard reporting and ad-hoc analyses to support sales activity and business decisions
Support business process and system improvement projects</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Degree in Statistics, Industrial Engineering, Operations Research, Math or related field is desirable.
Advanced degree a plus.</p>
</div></body></html>
