<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113210496">Strategic Space Planner</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113210496</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Our Workplace Planning team is the group that manages Apple’s global real estate portfolio.  This is the team that tracks all corporate space and develops the real estate strategy to meet Apple’s growing needs.  We work directly with the Real Estate, Project Management, Facilities and Site Services teams to service the various business units within Apple with critical data, space &amp; migration plans.
 
We’re looking for a Strategic Space Planner – a dynamic individual contributor that will be dedicated to a group of Apple business units and assist them in their current space planning needs as well as strategically plan their future moves and migrations.  In this role, you’ll be tasked with being the primary point of contact to business units for their space planning and space management needs, proactively seeking new methods to streamline the delivery of RE&amp;D’s services to your assigned business units, creating the short and long term occupancy and utilization strategies for your assigned business units, and supporting executive level reporting, analytics and strategic real estate portfolio decisions.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years relevant work experience in a global company preferred</li>
<li>Excellent communication &amp; presentation skills (both written and verbal)</li>
<li>Detail oriented with an ability to see the forest through the trees</li>
<li>Prior space management, facility management or project management experience</li>
<li>Proven experience in a client relationship management role</li>
<li>Familiarity and experience with CAFM/IWMS systems</li>
<li>Must be a self-starter who is comfortable working independently and managing high-profile client relationships</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">·      Manage key client relationships

·      Assist &amp; coordinate stakeholder needs with RE&amp;D service groups

·      Develop strategic plans (both strategic &amp; tactical/detailed level) specifically related to post-new-campus migrations and portfolio backfill/projects

·      Develop and define space needs, migration strategies, project justifications

·      Assist business units to track headcount and discrepancies, and keep our space planning systems &amp; data up-to-date

·      Be a key resource for internal RE&amp;D and external business unit stakeholders

·      Improve service delivery workflows</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelors Degree</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Familiarity with database systems (SQL, Oracle) a plus
Experience with current IWMS systems and trends a huge plus
Experience with AutoCAD a huge plus
Proficient in Word, Excel, Keynote and similar software on Apple platforms</p>
</div></body></html>
