<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113205345">Apple Music -  Data Program Manager   Apple Music -  Data Program Manager   </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113205345</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 1, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is seeking a proven Data Program Manager to join the Apple Music Analytics and Data Products team. This team seeks to promote productivity and innovation through diverse hiring. 

The Data Program Manager must coordinate the analytics workflow across various teams who design, build, maintain, or enhance business-critical datasets from a multitude of sources. These datasets are the foundation for the analysis, tools, and reports provided to the growing Apple Music business organization and partners. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>* Significant experience establishing and running teams on Agile or other project management methodologies </li>
<li>* Strong prioritization and project management skills, including timely and proactive communications of timelines, status, issue escalation </li>
<li>* Experience in creating data specifications (instrumentation, aggregation, induction) is beneficial</li>
<li>* Familiarity with big data and traditional database technologies (HDFS, Cassandra, Vertica, and traditional database platforms such as Teradata)</li>
<li>* Ability to work on a diverse team or with a diverse range of people</li>
<li>* Excellent communication skills, both written and oral, including the ability to convey complex requirements in a clear, concise and credible manner</li>
<li>* Extreme attention to detail and ability to self-audit work</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">* Erect and manage a program management framework across multiple streams of work
* Coordinate dependencies in migrating, inducting, and enriching data from production into downstream environments
* Track milestones and roadmaps, clearly articulating progress to leadership 
* Evaluate and solve difficult problems across various teams ranging from client instrumentation to data product development
* Perform root cause and impact analysis to investigate issues and make recommendations for potential solutions</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor's degree or equivalent work experience in Engineering, Computer Science, Business Information Systems.</p>
</div></body></html>
