<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113115981">MDM Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113115981</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 4, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">We are currently seeking an experienced data and configuration management professional to join our small, but dynamic team.  In this role, you will be responsible for seamless, rapid and global implementation of material, BOMs, and product data supporting AppleCare service business strategies and supply chain requirements.  Additionally, you will support global service master data setup for Apple’s products throughout the product lifecycle.  

This position can be based out of Sacramento, Austin or Cupertino</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5 years of experience in product data management, document control or similar function</li>
<li>Strong knowledge of SAP Material Master, Agile PLM, and Excel</li>
<li>Expertise in BOM management/configuration management </li>
<li>PDM/PLM/ERP system implementation and enhancement expertise</li>
<li>Problem solving skills, demonstrating good judgment in identifying methods and techniques for obtaining solutions</li>
<li>Strong track record of producing analytic insight that has led to significant improvements</li>
<li>Adept in prioritizing work and coordinating tasks</li>
<li>Ability to resolve issues using analytical tools</li>
<li>Manufacturing background with an understanding of post-sales service business</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Responsibilities
• Key AppleCare resource for product data management across multiple system interfaces 
• Analyze, process and track Agile ECR, ECO, MCO submissions to minimize processing time between submission and implementation, optimizing department throughput
• Interface with all necessary individuals in supporting departments in order to accurately process changes and structure new products 
• Capable of handling multiple projects simultaneously with the ability to set priorities
• Provide clear input to the project team on schedule, issues, and deliverables related to master data management
• Analyze problems of diverse scope to identify solutions
• Drive timely part setup, BOM releases, BOM changes to support new product introduction (NPI) as well sustaining business globally
• Catalyst for new and sustaining product release process creation and improvement (Ease of Use, Cycle Time, data analysis efficiencies)
• System support for master data escalations and governance
• Participate in continuous process improvements focused on systems, reporting, and data analysis efficiencies
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA or BS degree or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
