<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-58263079">Advertising Platforms - Operations Technical Solutions Specialist</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 58263079</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 9, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple is looking for experienced Operations Technical Solutions Specialists for its Advertising Platforms Business Operations team.  This is an an opportunity to be a part of a fast-paced team that is focused on establishing industry leading support and new innovation with Apple’s News and Search Ads platforms.  We are in search of an experienced person who has a proven track record of managing complex integrations and troubleshooting technical issues that help solve systemic problems.  Some of the core strengths for this role is to have the ability to construct robust technical test plans, analyze complex data sets, and to be able to effectively communicate clear concise results/solutions. Additionally this role is a balance of understanding our operational challenges, investigating and solving technical issues, helping scope improvements for future Advertising Platforms offerings, and working closely with Engineering and Product stakeholders to bring innovative ideas to life.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Exemplary written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Expert knowledge of the latest advertising technology</li>
<li>Expert knowledge of various ad serving platforms (DFA/DFP/DCM, Marin, Kenshoo, AdWords)</li>
<li>Experience with API integration and troubleshooting</li>
<li>Experience with SQL, writing and troubleshooting queries</li>
<li>Experience working with clients, product and engineering teams - with the ability to breakdown complex concepts to non-technical stakeholders</li>
<li>Experience with a formal project management methods</li>
<li>Experience writing and reviewing technical requirements documentation</li>
<li>Experience in driving partnership/collaboration that resulted in win-win solutions</li>
<li>Must have pragmatic process acumen to focus on maximizing throughput in the fewest steps possible, while maintaining quality</li>
<li>Must have strong Excel and analytical abilities</li>
<li>Must have demonstrable creative thinking and problem solving abilities</li>
<li>Must be detail oriented and have exceptional organizational skills</li>
<li>Ability to work independently and with a team in a fast paced, rapidly-changing environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">- Write and review technical requirements documentation
- Manage complex API Integration projects while providing technical guidance
- Investigate ad serving and platform escalations from internal and external teams
- Provide data and analysis on systemic issues
- Work with Engineering and Product teams on technical requirements for platform issues and improvements
- R&amp;D for new platforms, products and technologies being deployed on a monthly cycle
- Manage internal/external resources to effectively conduct our QA certification process across platforms
- On-board internal and external partners on new products and platforms
- On-board documentation and training plan
- Ability to resolve issues while handling competing priorities
- Lead roadmap support and prioritization for Business Operations
- Maintain relationships and certification procedures with third-party vendors
- Maintain continuous outreach with third-party partners
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS required with 5+ years prior experience in a Technical Operations/Solutions Role</p>
</div></body></html>
