<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-112969709">Maps Platform Java Software Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 112969709</li>
<li title="Seattle, Washington, United States">Seattle, Washington, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Nov. 2, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Maps do more than just get us from point A to point B.  They let us know where we stand in the world, help define our communities, and highlight what is of cultural importance to us.  Tasked with building the world’s best map you will use large data sets, distributed processing systems, domain expertise, and top-notch development skills to ensure a complete and accurate map.  We are looking for passionate, creative software engineers motivated by challenging problems of scale that impact every Maps user.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Exceptional object-oriented programming skills – Java or Scala preferred</li>
<li>Solid understanding of distributed systems and highly scalable environments</li>
<li>A track record of developing and delivering high quality software in a collaborative team environment</li>
<li>Excellent analytical and debugging skills </li>
<li>Great solutions come from talented engineers with diverse backgrounds and at all levels</li>
<li>A passion for maps!</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Our team combines disparate signals such as data analytics, community engagement, and user feedback to improve the Maps Platform.  On any given day you may find yourself building complex corrective mapping functions, defining algorithms that validate map data and sending detected errors to visualization and correction tools, or brainstorming with developers and analysts ways to detect and fix map anomalies.

Successful candidates will have exceptional engineering and communication skills, as well as a belief that data-driven feedback leads to great products. 
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s / Master’s degree in CS or related field</p>
</div></body></html>
