<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113154622">Reliability Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113154622</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 25, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">
The candidate will work with Apple’s innovative Reliability Engineering team working with hardware development groups. The engineer will be responsible for leading and executing reliability tests on new Apple and supplier technologies, development of new test procedures to quantify the reliability of a design, and failure analysis resulting from these tests.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience performing reliability testing including Mechanical Stress Tests, Shock/Drop/Vibration Testing, Environmental Testing</li>
<li>Failure Analysis analytical techniques (Optical Microscopy, X-Ray, SEM/EDS, FTIR, XPS etc)</li>
<li>Ability to use fundamental failure analysis methodology to derive a root cause of failure</li>
<li>Knowledge of industry test Standards (JEDEC, ASTM, IEEE)</li>
<li>Solid understanding of mechanical assemblies</li>
<li>Application of DOE (design of Experiments)</li>
<li>Application of FMEA (Failure Modes an Effects Analysis)  </li>
<li>Exceptional problem solving abilities</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Strong attention to detail</li>
<li>Ability to manage multiple projects at the same time</li>
<li>Ability to complete tests and resolve problems in an unattended manner</li>
<li>Flexibility and adaptability to accept new tasks</li>
<li>Dynamic and “can do” attitude with a desire to work with a great team and product</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">
• Preparing concise and detailed test plans and test reports
• Development of new reliability tests procedures and specifications
• Statistical data analysis to provide risk assessments of a design
• Researching a technology to determine possible failure modes
• Prioritizing and completing tasks to meet deadlines
• Providing design input to improve product reliability when necessary
• Interacting with a wide variety of individuals and teams to communicate results</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">• Engineering degree and 5+ years of experience in a related field or industry required
• MS or PhD in Materials Science, Mechanical Engineering or an equivalent field desired
• Consumer electronics experience is preferred  </p>
</div></body></html>
