<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54763157">Big Data Front End Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54763157</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Feb. 3, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Interactive Media Group at Apple is looking for a highly motivated front end engineer. You will be a critical part of a team focused on Big Data analytics applications for media streaming and their underlying networking architecture on iOS and OS X. You must enjoy the excitement of rapid development, tight deadlines, and interacting with other high energy   teams. You’ll be asked to build user interfaces to present and visualize data sets for troubleshooting and improving how our software behaves in real-world situations. The candidate should posess solid front-end engineering, leadership, and communication skills.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Well-versed in fundamental visual and interactive design discipline</li>
<li>Strong communication and presentation skills</li>
<li>Strong command of JavaScript, HTML/HTML5, AJAX, DOM, CSS/CSS3, JSON</li>
<li>Experience with Ruby</li>
<li>Familiar with contemporary JavaScript frameworks (JQuery, Backbone, Underscore, etc.)</li>
<li>Ability to write high-performance, reusable code for UI components</li>
<li>Knowledge of user interface design and proven ability to work with business counter parts to create compelling user experiences</li>
<li>Ability to define new approaches to complex design problems for data presentation</li>
<li>Must be process driven, possess strong prototyping design skills, careful attention to detail and have a solid understanding of user centered design principles</li>
<li>Strong knowledge Git and Linux environment</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Provide guidance and leadership to the front-end team
Play hands-on development and design role, and deliver products in a rapid and dynamic environment
Prototype, define, and develop web solutions that meet modern web standards using semantic markup, CSS, and JavaScript
Consider scalability and ease of maintenance in all solutions
Engage business and technical teams for feedback and validation
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">B.S or M.S in EE/CS with a strong focus in software engineering</p>
<h3>Additional Requirements</h3>
<p class="preline">Experience developing web pages optimized for desktop, mobile devices and tablet devices a plus
Experience with cross-browser compatibility issues and browser degradation strategies a plus
Experience with Ruby Web frameworks (like Sinatra) a plus
</p>
</div></body></html>
