<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113167910">Tools and Annotation Manager, Frameworks</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113167910</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Building intelligent systems requires data, lots of data. To facilitate future machine learning, handwriting recognition, and computer vision efforts, the Core Recognition team is looking for a manager to help coordinate the development of engineering tools and supervise data annotation deliverables. Collaborate with the core engineering team to build, train, and manage data entry and annotation specialists and enable the next generation of Apple products.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience hiring, building, and managing small teams</li>
<li>Proven ability to effectively measure and quantify employee performance</li>
<li>Ability to coordinate and translate technical requirements into actionable data annotation processes</li>
<li>Familiarity supervising the development of software tools or data entry services</li>
<li>Demonstrable understanding of when and how to best automate repetitive annotation tasks</li>
<li>Ability to appropriately scale software tools, teams, and processes to meet big data demands</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Staff, train, and supervise data entry and annotation specialists. Coordinate the development and maintenance of tools and technology required for collecting, organizing, annotating and sharing mission-critical data with the core engineering teams. Develop the software infrastructure and internal processes necessary for efficiently annotating large datasets and help define and evolve the software interface between the annotation and engineering teams.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree in Computer Science or related field, or comparable industrial experience, with history of team management and experience with software development.</p>
</div></body></html>
