<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113025016">Software Engineer - ML Development Tools</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113025016</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 19, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Core ML team is looking for an exceptional software engineer to design and implement Apple development tools for machine learning. In this highly collaborative role, you will be at the center of multiple efforts to make machine learning an accessible and powerful tool for all developers. 

We are looking for someone with proven mastery of software development and familiarity with the internals of software development tools. You should have a strong mix of education and practical experience with a passion for diving in to challenging problems head first. 
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Strong and proven software development skills</li>
<li>Proficiency in C/C++ or similar</li>
<li>Proficient analyzing and debugging complex programs</li>
<li>Experience with the internals of debuggers and/or compilers (e.g. LLDB, LLVM)</li>
<li>Experience with basic data analysis and statistics a plus</li>
<li>Experience building user interfaces a plus</li>
<li>Experience with Swift, Objective-C and Xcode is highly desired</li>
<li>Creative, collaborative, and product-focused</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Work includes: Building and maintaining machine learning development tools and utilities for interfacing with Core ML. Ensuring high quality and agility with unit, integration and performance tests. You will work collaboratively to make the integration of Apple's machine learning frameworks seamless with development tools in the Apple ecosystem to maximize the developer user experience. You should possess strong skills in software design and programming and be excited about delivering the best possible developer experience for Core ML users. You are excited about developing new features, maintaining existing code, fixing bugs, and contributing to Apple's ML development tools strategy.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS in Computer Science with 3+ years experience
</p>
</div></body></html>
