<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-52776340"> Full Stack Development Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 52776340</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 26, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Full Stack Developer on the Maps Evaluation team, you will build high performance, highly scalable, fault tolerant back-ends for critical internal systems.  You will design and build highly usable, powerful, clean, and beautiful Web UIs. You will work closely with a small agile team of talented engineers, collaborating with users and product owners as well as other engineering teams and operations to design, build, and deploy top-quality applications.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience developing applications with service oriented architectures</li>
<li>Experience developing RESTful web service APIs</li>
<li>Seasoned developer with strong Java skills</li>
<li>Experience scaling high QPS Java services preferred</li>
<li>Experience with ETL pipelines and batch data processing a plus</li>
<li>Distributed data store experience (e.g. HBase) a plus</li>
<li>Expertise with relational databases (e.g. PostgreSQL) a plus</li>
<li>Extensive development experience with JS/HTML5/CSS3</li>
<li>Experience with one or more Javascript application frameworks (e.g. AngularJS or Ember.js)</li>
<li>UI/UX Design experience strongly preferred</li>
<li>Responsive Web Design (RWD) experience preferred</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">You will work across the organization, collaborating with statisticians, data scientists, other tools developers, product owners, engineering, operations, and management. Our products interact with many internal systems and are used by engineers and executives alike, making this a high-visibility team with lots of opportunity for collaboration.</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS in computer science or mathematics, or equivalent professional experience</p>
</div></body></html>
