<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-51437602">Storage Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 51437602</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Hardware Technology Compute and Storage Group has an opportunity available for a customer service oriented, self-driven, and motivated Storage Engineer to join our operations team. The ideal candidate should possess excellent communication and troubleshooting skills as well as a solid working knowledge of complex storage systems, Linux compute clusters, and the infrastructure used to support a large scale HPC. You will run and expand the existing compute and storage infrastructure used by the geographically diverse silicon design teams within Apple.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Typically requires at least 5+ years of experience in a large compute environment. EDA, Finance, Special Effects/Animation, Oil &amp; Gas, Scientific Research or R&amp;D environments preferred</li>
<li>Experience with enterprise storage administration</li>
<li>Experience with NFS, NAS, and D2D appliances (NetApp or EMC preferred)</li>
<li>Experience managing a multi-site storage environment</li>
<li>Experience with site-to-site data replication and WAN optimization</li>
<li>Experience with Linux system administration (Red Hat/CentOS preferred)</li>
<li>Experience working in and trouble shooting a high-uptime, high-availability environment </li>
<li>Experience with monitoring systems (Nagios, Zenoss, Sensu) </li>
<li>Experience with centralized configuration management (Puppet, Ansible, Chef)</li>
<li>Experience with revision control systems (SVN, Git, Perforce)</li>
<li>Experience using scripting languages like bash, Perl, Python, or Ruby </li>
<li>Understanding of Layer 2 / Layer 3 networking (Arista / Cisco preferred)</li>
<li>Knowledge of common application protocols like DNS, LDAP, SNMP, DHCP, NTP</li>
<li>Must be analytical and possess strong organization / problem-solving skills</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline"> •Perform implementation, maintenance, monitoring, performance analysis, proactive troubleshooting, and continual improvement of the storage and compute infrastructure
•Drive automation of the implementation, maintenance, and alerting of the storage environment
•Deploy and maintain a storage infrastructure that requires 24/7 global accessibility
•Participate in programs to deploy POC systems for evaluation and testing
•Review entire environment and execute initiatives to reduce failures, defects and improving overall performance
•Perform tasks that require different perspectives and creative approaches
•Participate in a regular on-call rotation
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">•BS/MS Degree or equivalent experience</p>
</div></body></html>
