<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55752671">SoC Characterization Product Engineer </h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55752671</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, you will be responsible for Product Characterization on different setups and defining correlation between ATE and other logic boards. You will also focus on studying the impact of hardware on SOC performance.</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate should have 5+ years of product engineering experience.</li>
<li>In depth knowledge of Semiconductor Manufacturing Process and solid understanding of Electronic Engineering Fundamentals and DFT concepts. </li>
<li>Experience system level / mother board characterization and data collection.</li>
<li>Prior bench test definition, design and execution experience for SoC characterization.</li>
<li>Expertise in programming scripting languages (i.e., PERL, Python).</li>
<li>Knowledge to perform statistical data analysis using various tools (JMP etc.).</li>
<li>Able to work with test equipment (i.e., oscilloscope, logic analyzer, etc.). </li>
<li>Board bring up, hardware design and PDN noise analysis experience is a plus.</li>
<li>Excellent communication skills to work with internal team members and external suppliers.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">• Perform data analysis, characterization, and fault isolation to determine the root cause of the issues.
• Perform correlation between ATE and different hardware setups.
• Work with design, process, and test engineers to identify and implement corrective actions on both new and mature products and technologies.
• Define and finalize production screening guard-band specifications based upon design intent and characterization result.
• Perform statistical data analysis on mass data set.
• Perform yield analyses and correlation analyses for all levels of test insertions.
• Coordinate test related activities with both internal and external groups. 

</p>
</div></body></html>
