<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113047355">Photonic Device Scientist - Exploratory Design Group</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113047355</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 18, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">In this role, you will work within an Optical Science team, collaborating with a highly multi-disciplinary group, to develop and demonstrate new photonic sensor concepts. You will take advantage of your technical breadth as well as your depth of experience with optical systems.

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>The ideal candidate will have 4+ total years of experience with photonic device physics, including significant experience with silicon photonics, plus most of the following:</li>
<li>- Excellent grasp of optical physics fundamentals.</li>
<li>- Experience with simulation of integrated optical active and passive components at both component and circuit level, including FDTD, waveguide mode solvers, and scatter matrix.</li>
<li>- Experience constructing and validating models of optical devices, based on first principles and empirical data.</li>
<li>- Strong programming ability with Matlab, Python, or similar language.</li>
<li>- Good understanding of a variety of optical measurement techniques, with hands-on experience characterizing optical devices.</li>
<li>- Excellent communication and presentation skills.</li>
<li>- Ability to work well in a team environment.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">As a Photonic Device Scientist, you will have the following responsibilities:

•Work with the System Engineering team to invent, implement and test optical sensor concepts.
•Conduct first-principles numerical simulations of optical devices and systems.
•Identify causal relationships between observed system-level performance and specific device-level parameters.
•Write specifications for custom optical devices, based on a combination of modeling and interpretation of empirical data.
•Work with external vendors to fabricate custom optical devices meeting our system-level requirements.
•Work with the team to test and validate fabricated devices.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Masters degree or PhD in Physics, Applied Physics, Optics, EE, or related field is required.
</p>
</div></body></html>
