<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-55729281">Senior System Reliability Analyst</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 55729281</li>
<li title="Sacramento, California, United States">Sacramento, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 6, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">
We are seeking a senior System Reliability Analyst (SRA) to be part of the top tier support team to support one of the most demanding application eco-system within Apple Inc.   The senior system reliability analyst (SRA) position requires a mixed skill sets of analytical problem resolution, effective communication, strategic engineering along with technical hands on I.T operation work.  A successful candidate will likely have a technical background in being one of the I.T functional areas SME that has moved on to Incident Management/DevOps in their career. The analyst will spend a significant portion of their time coordinating and overviewing the ongoing problems or projects, he or she will play a key role in operating this multi-tiered enterprise scale systems to achieve optimal application performance, stability and availability. The SRA will be required to work closely and successfully with systems engineers, network engineers, database administrators, on/offshore production support team, and other external or internal R&amp;D teams. To be successful in this position, one must able to demonstrate exceptional ability to prioritize and act accurately based on the urgency of the problem, at the very same time laser focus in resolving recurring incidents by working in a matrix organization.    

PLEASE NOTE:  This position can be based either out of Cupertino or Sacramento

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Solid hands on experience managing services in a large scale *nix environment, and had often played the role of crisis management before </li>
<li>Used to and made solid contribution in environment of systematic, test-and-measure approach for continually improving service operation</li>
<li>Track record of practical problem solving, excellent communication and documentation skills</li>
<li>Demonstrated ability to perform interpretive analysis based on variety of feedback systems or dashboards to identify problems</li>
<li>Experience with DevOps tools, processes, and culture</li>
<li>Practical knowledge of standard networking protocols and components such as: HTTP, DNS, TCP/IP, ICMP, WAN/LAN and Load Balancing</li>
<li>Practical knowledge of variety of database technologies such as high transactional RDBMS in Oracle/MySQL, Hadoop</li>
<li>Strong understanding of J2EE application servers</li>
<li>Experience with monitoring tools such as Zenoss, Graphite, Grafana, Splunk preferred</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">The successful candidate will be highly self-motivated with a passion for excellence, quality and detail. The SRA will not only support operations, but also work closely with the development engineers within the team to aid in architectural design and assist with the implementation of complex features. 

Responsibilities of the SRA include the following:

- Passion for quality and automation, an ability to understand complex systems and a desire to constantly make things better.
- Determine optimal configurations for application software, application servers (i.e. JBoss, Tomcat, etc.), database connections and network related setting and tuning etc. 
- Develop and maintain scripts used for environment monitoring and task automation (Perl, Shell, PHP, etc.) 
- Deploy, support and monitor new platforms and application stacks  
- Set priorities and work efficiently in a fast-paced environment
- Measure and optimize system performance
- Plan and manage capacity of the systems
- Explore and evaluate new technologies and solutions to push the capabilities forward, getting ahead of customers’ needs, innovate and continually improve
- Strong communication skills and ability to work effectively across multiple business and technical teams
- Demonstrate ability to deliver results on time with high quality

</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Prefer a BS in engineering, computer science or other technical disciplines plus 5 years of related experience</p>
</div></body></html>
