<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-113188666">iDMS Software Engineer, QA</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 113188666</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Oct. 30, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Imagine what you could do here. At Apple, great ideas have a way of becoming great products, services, and customer experiences very quickly. Bring passion and dedication to your job and there's no telling what you could accomplish.

Apple’s Identity Management Services QA group is looking for a highly motivated, result-oriented Engineer with a strong background in Software Development and Quality Assurance to join its team of highly skilled software engineers. You will be responsible for overseeing quality engineering of server side &amp; customer-facing distributed platforms and applications in a fast paced dynamic environment.  Your job is to keep our high-quality bar set ridiculously high, and to help us identify and execute ways to raise it even higher. The QA Engineer in this role will play a key function in delivering highly critical Identity Management/Authentication features to internal and external customers on OS X, iOS, and Web in addition to supporting the development of internal test automation &amp; test management tools.1

</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>5+ years of combined work experience in software development and QA</li>
<li>Admin-level expertise in QA automation architecture, methodologies, processes, tools</li>
<li>Background in automating functional, system, and integration tests on Web, iOS, macOS, Android, Win</li>
<li>Experience testing System Failover and Application Disaster Recovery at platform level</li>
<li>Experience building test programs in Java, Python, Swift, AppleScript, or other OO languages</li>
<li>Familiarity with Identity Management software fundamentals and test methodologies </li>
<li>Expertise in testing Web Services (Rest &amp; SOAP), databases, and batch processes</li>
<li>Proven ability to deliver high-quality work on tight schedules</li>
<li>Ability to work in a fast-paced environment with frequent context switching</li>
<li>Self-motivated, independent, and proactive</li>
<li>Outstanding collaboration and organizational skills</li>
<li>Excellent written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Programming experience in Java, Python, Swift, JavaScript, AppleScript, or other OO languages</li>
<li>Expert-level knowledge of software build tools and CI/CD integrations</li>
<li>Experience managing distributed vendor resources</li>
<li>Working knowledge of Apple hardware and software</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Description
Provide functional and integration quality-assurance testing for features delivered on Web, iOS, OS X, and other operating systems
Build QA test plans and cases with the goal of 100% automation and reduction of regression test cycles
Build test management tools/utilities and enhance existing automation platforms 
Work closely with cross-functional organizations, project teams and clients to develop test plans, execute test plans and cases, and deliver high quality products
Act as a strong advocate for quality in the software development process
Identify gaps or inefficiencies in workflows and suggest necessary process improvements 
Self-motivated and must be able to grasp issues quickly and make educated, critical judgment in the absence of complete requirements
Provide project managers with timely and accurate QA status and progress during all testing phases, including summarizing QA results at project conclusion
Able to multi-task in a dynamic, fast-paced environment
Excellent verbal and written communication skills
Good interpersonal skills and able to work with various cross functional teams to deliver high  quality products.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BA/BS CS or equivalent </p>
</div></body></html>
