<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56213999">Contract Technical Recruiter - Silicon Engineering</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56213999</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Mar. 16, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Apple’s Silicon Engineering Recruiting team is focused on delivering best-in-class recruiting services to our teams that are developing chips to be used in next generation Apple products. </p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Be a cut above the rest. If you know you are one the best recruiters in your field, then this role is probably for you. Typically requires at least 4+ years of full life-cycle engineering recruiting experience</li>
<li>Possess strong organizational skills, attention to detail, excellent follow up skills, and be proficient with applicant tracking systems and Excel</li>
<li>Strong ability to engage and collaborate effectively with senior level management</li>
<li>Must be analytical and comfortable in analyzing data and assessing possible outcomes</li>
<li>Understand the art of negotiating and possess experience in strategically closing very smart engineers</li>
<li>Understanding of immigration, relocation, compensation and overall market trends</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">In this highly visible role, you will:
•Utilize your communication skills by partnering and driving the recruiting process with hiring managers, as well as various cross-functional teams (Sourcing, Research, Coordination, HR, HRIS, HROps, etc)
•Become THE subject matter expert in the field for which you recruit
•Screen, interview, develop offers, and strategically close highly skilled engineers that will execute on developing next generation products for Apple
•Create a value added proposition for candidates by consulting with the business utilizing your vast knowledge in compensation, candidate leveling, market trends, etc.
•Prioritize requisitions on a weekly basis, partner with the sourcing team on strategic and tactical sourcing strategies, ensuring strategy execution
•Strive to be viewed as a value added business partner to your stakeholders, ensuring a positive candidate experience for all potential candidates
•Ensure candidates move expeditiously and smoothly through the interview process
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">BS or MS Degree preferred</p>
</div></body></html>
