<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-54913156">Global Data Center Capacity Management</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 54913156</li>
<li title="Newark, CA, California, United States">Newark, CA, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Sep. 22, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">Reporting to the GDCS Capacity Management team this position will be accountable for driving the effective use of Apple’s DC capacity.  Working closely with the Data Center Site Management teams this group is responsible for:
•Managing Data Center demand against supply including technical evaluation and placement of deployments to maximize capacity utilization and flexibility
•Reporting and reacting to Data Center capacity utilization and other metrics
•Representing GDCS on major projects impacting Data Center supply and demand
•Providing input into the long range supply plan
•Performing routine and ad hoc reporting for business groups and Apple’s senior leadership on DC capacity across all DC’s
•Identification of capacity problems before they happen



</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Candidates will have 5+ years of work experience with a demonstrable record of:</li>
<li>Excellent planning and management skills, strong analytical, organization and problem solving skills and the ability to work independently as well as part of a strong team.</li>
<li>Effective project leadership abilities, able to plan, organize, and motivate others to achieve objectives within challenging timelines and situations of uncertainty.</li>
<li>Skillful and effective listening and communication abilities that have been used to establish and maintain close working relationships with management, colleagues, team members and stakeholders to create value.</li>
<li>Effectively communicating with and influencing all levels of management and peer groups</li>
<li>The ability to make timely and effective decisions based on sound judgment and business rationale.</li>
<li>The ability to gracefully adjust to meet changing circumstances, demands and priorities.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">Likely candidates will have multiple items of the following:
- Data Center Capacity Management and reporting experience.
- Bachelor’s Degree in a technical discipline
- Hands on Data Center site services or management experience
- Data Center build-outs and understanding of rack elevations
- Experience championing the design, development, and deployment of Data Center capacity planning tools 
- History of working with Tools and Automation teams to build better reporting, predictive alerting, and visualization systems
- A solid knowledge of Data Center facilities and their operation
- A solid knowledge of Enterprise IT operations, including network, server and storage hardware software and their operation
- A solid knowledge of supply and demand management through disciplines such as MRP or ERP</p>
</div></body></html>
