<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-56058163">Mac Firmware Engineer</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 56058163</li>
<li title="Austin, Texas, United States">Austin, Texas, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Apr. 11, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The Mac Platform Software team is looking for a firmware engineer to join a new Austin-based team responsible for developing Apple’s UEFI implementation and related technologies for the Mac product line. Mac Platform Software is responsible for bringing up macOS and Windows on all new Mac products, including the development and integration of firmware and systems software for macOS and Windows, the development of platform-level features for the Mac, and the leadership of cross-functional debug and optimization efforts across hardware and software teams.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Experience in firmware/BIOS development</li>
<li>Experience with boot loaders and firmware/kernel interfaces</li>
<li>Excellent understanding of hardware design as it relates to operating systems</li>
<li>Familiar with debugging tools: ICE, JTAG, Logic Analyzers, Oscilloscopes</li>
<li>Strong written and verbal communication skills</li>
<li>Bachelor’s degree in CS, CE, EE or equivalent industry experience required</li>
<li>Knowledge of UEFI and the x86 platform and standards, including ACPI, SMM, PnP, PCIe, and JEDEC DDR a plus</li>
<li>Strong understanding of system power management a plus</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">A Mac Firmware Engineer is responsible for the development of Apple’s UEFI implementation and its related technologies. UEFI provides the boot firmware for all Mac systems and plays a critical role in system stability, performance, and battery life. This role also contributes to development of the boot loader and firmware update mechanisms, as well as other related technologies. Primary job responsibilities include firmware feature development supporting new Mac software and hardware features, supporting ongoing efforts to improve the quality of shipped Macs in the field, and assisting the larger Mac Platform organization in cross-functional efforts to design and build new Mac products.



</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Bachelor’s degree or equivalent experience in computer science or a related field



</p>
</div></body></html>
