<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div id="job">
<h2 id="title-83560683">Motion Scientist</h2>
<ul class="sosumi">
<li>Job Number: 83560683</li>
<li title="Santa Clara Valley, California, United States">Santa Clara Valley, California, United States</li>
<li>Posted: Jun. 23, 2017</li>
<li>Weekly Hours: 40.00</li>
</ul>
<h3>Job Summary</h3>
<p class="preline">The CoreMotion Interaction team has created innovative ways for users to interact with their devices through motion. When your AirPods automatically sense that they are in your ear, or when you play games by simply moving your device, it’s the work of engineers and scientists on this team. Join this team and work with the people who have created the sensor fusion technologies and gestures that power games, AR and numerous other features on Apple’s devices.
</p>
<div class="callout">
<h3>Key Qualifications</h3>
<ul class="square">
<li>Expertise and experience in various aspects of signal processing, motion estimation, and control systems.</li>
<li>Ability to design and execute user studies, and perform data analysis to extract actionable insights.</li>
<li>Experience with algorithm design using sensors on mobile devices, validating algorithms and characterizing performance.</li>
<li>Excellent technical communication skills</li>
<li>Enthusiasm for solving human interaction problems and be obsessively detailed about the user experience</li>
<li>Excellent MATLAB skills. Familiarity with C++ is a plus.</li>
</ul>
</div>
<h3>Description</h3>
<p class="preline">We are looking for a scientist to join us in creating a new generation of interaction mechanisms that utilize motion, proximity, touch and other sensors. As a member of this team, you will be responsible for designing and validating algorithms, creating user studies, analyzing data, communicating with stakeholders and working with our multi-disciplinary team to ship these features. Above all, you will have a positive impact on the user experience of millions of users.
</p>
<h3>Education</h3>
<p class="preline">Ph.D in Mechanical Engineering, Electrical Engineering, Computer Science or a related field with domain knowledge
Coursework in signal processing, controls, statistics, programming

</p>
</div></body></html>
