Taylor Maxson
8001 Greenway Dr. Louisville, KY 40222
(502) 303-3921
taylor.maxson@yahoo.com
https://www.linkedin.com/in/maxsontaylor


Objective and Skills  
Self-starter with strong analytical and problem solving skills. Values a strong, positive, and adaptable company culture. Seeking a career within research or data analysis with the opportunity to contribute to the advancement of both the company and team members within.


Self-starter
Research
Innovation
Critical thinking
Data input, analysis, and auditing
Process improvement expertise
Problem area anticipation, identification, and solution
Emotional I.Q.
Teamwork
Conscientiousness
Adaptability
Social media



Education
January 2017-May 2018
Bellarmine University, Institute for Advanced Analytics – Louisville, KY
Analytics, M.S.A.

August 2011-December 2015
University of Kentucky – Lexington, KY
Economics, B.A.
Microsoft Office Certification 

August 2010-May 2011
University of Mount Union – Alliance, OH
Honors Program

August 2006-May 2010
Sacred Heart Academy – Louisville, KY
International Baccalaureate (I.B.) Program 

 
Work History
October 2015-May 2017 	
Office of the Governor, Department for Local Government, Cities and Special Districts Branch – Frankfort, KY  
Advisor, CSR
Assistance with managing noncompliance database
Research and analysis for database updates 
Data integrity management  
Developed financial forms and data sheets
Audit and analysis of statistical data related to local government finances
Process development leader 
Frequent communication and collaboration with systems and information team to build databases for newly developed processes 
Review of current outdated processes with analysis, interpretation, and presentation of findings and recommendations for improvement 
Customer service

June 2014-January 2016
Daffodils Fine Stationery and Gifts – Lexington, KY
Sales
Management and problem solving skill development
Attention to detail to ensure all orders delivered to customer’s satisfaction 
Customer service in small business setting
Communication and interpersonal skill development 
Built long standing relationships with both customers and brand representatives
Inventory management  


Relevant Experience
January 2013-January 2014
Independent Research Lab, P20 Motivation and Learning – Lexington, KY
Research Assistant 
Data entry and analysis of results 
Designed and administered surveys to students within various school settings 
Independent research on self-efficacy and motivation

January 2012-January 2013
Community Center for Outreach, University of Kentucky – Lexington, KY
Program Coordinator Volunteer 
Researched global issues of interest for potential focus for campus events
Met weekly with small team to plan events to raise awareness regarding global issues 
Managed social media accounts for program to advertise events and raise awareness 
Attended leadership skill building workshops
Volunteered monthly with local nonprofit International Book Project
