<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">Cloud Technical Architect</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">181307</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-WI-Green Bay</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Office, Virtual/Work At Home</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1707.row1" class="subtitle">Travel</span></h2>
<span style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1724.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1734.row1" class="text">Yes, 5 % of the Time</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div>
<b><font face="Arial" color="#40752d">Cloud Technical Architect</font></b> </div>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Business Overview</font></h2>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#333333">Humana Inc., headquartered in Louisville, Ky., is a leading health care company that offers a wide range of insurance products and health and wellness services that incorporate an integrated approach to lifelong well-being. By leveraging the strengths of its core businesses, Humana believes it can better explore opportunities for existing and emerging adjacencies in health care that can further enhance wellness opportunities for the millions of people across the nation with whom the company has relationships.</font></div>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Description</font></h2>
<div>
<div>
<font color="#333333"><font face="Arial" size="1"></font></font> </div>
<font face="Arial" size="1"><font color="#333333"> </font></font>
</div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1"><font color="#333333">We are seeking a Cloud Technical Architect with extensive experience working in a complex computing environment to join our internal Virtualization and Infrastructure team. As a Cloud Technical Architect, you will work as part of a team that designs and architects Humana’s next generation internal and external cloud infrastructure. A thorough understanding of and working experience with an Enterprise computing infrastructure and cloud computing technologies are required. To be successful you will need a strong technical orientation; be a creative problem solver; be motivated to advance in the field; and work well in a team-oriented environment.</font></font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1"><font color="#333333"> </font></font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1"><font color="#333333"> </font></font></div>
<div><font color="#333333"><b><font face="Arial" size="1">Job Responsibilities</font></b> </font></div>
<ul>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Provide technical direction to meet the internal needs</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Design a highly scalable and redundant virtual infrastructure to support the company’s future growth</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Provide innovative suggestions for complex implementation solutions</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Create documentation and implementation plans to allow support teams to build and manage the internal cloud environment</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Stay abreast of current technologies and make recommendations based on knowledge and research</font></div>
</li>
</ul>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d"> </font></h2>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Qualifications</font></h2>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="1"><font color="#333333">Job Requirements </font></font></b></div>
<ul>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Solid architecture &amp; design experience in using virtualization technologies from VMware, Microsoft, or open source solutions like OpenStack</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Established experience with automated, elastic scaling of cloud services, automated deployment and remediation</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Ability to prioritize projects and deliverables</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Excellent oral and written communication skills</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Ability to work collaboratively as well as independently to support deadlines</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Ability to handle multiple complex tasks, with tight deadlines concurrently</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Demonstrate ability to use problem solving techniques such as root cause analysis to resolve issues</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Demonstrate ability to write and present effective materials, including presentations, status reporting, technical diagrams and flowcharts</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Ability to follow and adhere to policies, procedures and standards relating to network and systems management</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Prepare detailed build/test plans to implement new technologies and configurations</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Deliver presentations and tech-talks to both internal and external customers</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Ability to collaborate with a team working across multiple locations</font></div>
</li>
</ul></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div><font color="#333333"><b><font face="Arial" size="1">Role Desirables</font></b> </font></div>
<ul>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">10+ years of experience designing and supporting large scale environment with a mixture of Linux and Windows operating systems</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">5+ years of hands on experience supporting Enterprise computing infrastructure and virtualization computing technologies</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">A track record of success developing and deploying creative technical solutions to business problems for or within large enterprise organizations</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Bachelor’s Degree in Information Technology, Computer Science or a related field</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Demonstrated ability to quickly learn new technologies</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience with the design and development of cloud-native, secure, distributed applications </font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience working on/with microservice architectures, web services, ReST APIs, API Gateways, relational and NoSQL stores and loosely coupled messaging</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience implementing versioning strategies for application interfaces</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience working with dependency management platforms (npm, nuget, ruby gems, etc.)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience deploying change to a live system in an high availability environment (blue-green, feature flags/toggles)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience with DevOps/Automation practices including automations and capabilities for CI, CD, metrics, monitoring, infrastructure as code, configuration management, and the organizational adoption of systems thinking, feedback loops and collaboration</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience with the design and automation of infrastructure as a Service and Platform as a Service capabilities including virtual networks, virtual machines, cloud services, web sites, data services, IOT, etc.</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Knowledge with modern service hosting, security, and risk management concerns such as IAM, access control, monitoring, IaaS/PaaS/SaaS, and containers</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Knowledge of infrastructure automation through DevOps scripting and configuration management required; and strong practical Linux and Windows-based systems administration skills in a Cloud or Virtualized environment required;</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Working knowledge of designing high availability systems in the cloud (fault domains, availability zones, deployment slots, regions)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience developing ARM Templates, Cloud formation templates, or Terraform</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Networking fundamentals, including VPN, security, and WAN concepts</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience using Source Control (GIt, TFVC, etc.)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience with infrastructure Configuration tools (DSC, Puppet)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience writing integration tests for infrastructure (ex: beaker or kitchen)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Knowledge of Cloud Database fundamentals (Azure SQL, RDS, DynamoDB, CosmosDB, MongoDB)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Core object oriented development &amp; architecture fundamentals</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience working in an agile continuous delivery  workflow &amp; team (Kanban)</font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience communicating  technical complexity and change to a broad spectrum of stakeholders </font></div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Experience with technical writing and documentation</font></div>
<div><strong><font face="Arial" size="1"> </font></strong></div>
<div><strong><font face="Arial" size="1">Additional Information</font></strong></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Humana is an organization with careers that change lives—including yours. As an innovator in the fast-paced industry of healthcare, we offer our associates careers that challenge, support and inspire them to use their passion for helping others and to lead their best lives. If you’re ready to help people achieve lifelong well-being, and be a part of an organization that is growing and poised to make an impact on the future of healthcare, Humana has the right opportunity for you.</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="1">Apply now, or join our Talent Network so you can stay informed and up to date on what’s happening at Humana.</font></div>
</li>
</ul>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Schedule</font></h2>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">:</font></b> <font face="Arial" size="1" color="black">Full-time</font>
</div>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Primary Location</font></h2>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">:</font></b> <font face="Arial" size="1" color="#333333">US-KY-Louisville or US-WI-Green Bay</font>
</div>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Role</font></h2>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">:</font></b> <font face="Arial" size="1" color="#333333">Technology</font>
</div>
<h2><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">Work Environment Type</font></h2>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="1" color="#40752d">:</font></b> <font face="Arial" size="1" color="#333333">Office</font>
</div></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">At Humana, we’re also committed to making the resources available to you that will enable you to become happier, healthier, and more productive in all areas of your life.  We know your well-being is important to you, and it’s important to us too.

If you share our passion for helping people, we likely have the right place for you at Humana. After applying, we encourage you to join our Talent Network as well, so you can stay informed and up to date on what’s happening around our organization in the changing world of healthcare.</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
