<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">IAM Domain Architect (remote virtual home office)</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">181730</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-KY-Louisville</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Office, Virtual/Work At Home</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1707.row1" class="subtitle">Travel</span></h2>
<span style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1724.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1734.row1" class="text">Yes, 5 % of the Time</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div>
<b><font face="">Role:  </font></b><font face="">Domain Architect</font>
</div>
<div>
<b><font face="">Assignment: </font></b><font face="">IT</font>
</div>
<div><b><font face="">Location: Lousiville, KY or Virtual(work at home)</font></b></div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div><font face="">In the fast-paced, ever-growing world of Healthcare, Humana relies on the latest technology and trends for sharing and storing information, communication and security. We need experts in technology to help us develop and maintain our networks, hardware, and software—to ensure our systems run smoothly and efficiently, keep us on the forefront of innovation in healthcare, and retain our competitive edge. At Humana, we want to help people everywhere, including our associates lead their best lives and achieve lifelong well-being. We look for talented individuals who share this passion for helping others, who have naturally curious and innovative minds, and who want a career where they can use their technical skills to make a positive impact on the lives of our members.</font></div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="">Assignment Capsule</font></b></div>
<div><font face="">Be a part of the Technology team -- be a strategic leader in cutting edge Healthcare technology.</font></div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div><font face="">Humana is seeking a Domain Architect that will be responsible for the internal architecture design of the enterprise’s strategy for Identity and Access Management (IAM). This role is responsible for defining and documenting architectures using enterprise standards. The Domain Architect is also responsible for the effective integration of their domain into the broader business and IT ecosystem within which it will operate. The Domain Architect is not only called to understand and follow enterprise guidelines and design patterns in their work; they are also expected to share feedback and learning back out to the enterprise. Thus, the Domain Architect also serves as the SME for their domain to other architects, and as a feedback loop back into the enterprise architecture portfolio.</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2" color="black"> </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li>
<font face="">Define current domain architecture<s>,</s> and identify issues within it.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Refine and/or redesign domain architecture to meet the organization’s changing business requirements.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Interact with other architects to make sure the domain aligns with the needs of the consumers.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Interact with other Domain Architects to define domain interactions.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Interact with consumers to promote and explain the domain and domain concepts.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Serve as the “bridge” between Enterprise Information Protection and their related application architectures.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Ensure domain architecture leverages enterprise capabilities wherever feasible.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Ensure enterprise reference architecture standards, patterns, principles, and guides are documented.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Ensure solutions are aligned with the enterprise reference architecture standards, patterns, principles, and guides.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Define domain architectural and technical standards.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Work with third-party solutions that affect the domain, including selection of technology (being sure it aligns with enterprise architecture).</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Treat the services within their domain as a portfolio of business assets.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Review candidate services, and perform design-time governance on their domain’s services.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Provide oversight to ensure implementations are consistent with defined architecture as well as consistent with business needs.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Participate in the architecture design of the applications or technologies within the domain.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Within their domain, recommend technologies that will increase cost effectiveness, user experience, and flexibility.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Create and maintain domain architecture deliverables.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Create consistency and collaboration throughout the domain across sub-area teams.</font> </li>
<li>
<font face="">Ensure appropriate lifecycle plans are created and implemented in compliance with required SOPs.</font> </li>
<li><font face="">Mentor and guide Technology Architects (App, Data, Tech) technically and professionally.</font></li>
</ul></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div>
<b><font face="">Role Essentials</font></b> </div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="">8+ years design, development, and <font color="#1f497d">implementation of IAM program</font><s><font color="#1f497d">s</font> </s></font></li>
<li><font face="">Experience with: </font></li>
<ul type="circle">
<li><font face="">SOA design and implementation </font></li>
<li><font face="">Designing and integrating multi-application solutions </font></li>
<li><font face="">Building application architecture models</font></li>
</ul>
</ul>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div>
<b><font face="">Role Desirables</font></b> </div>
<ul type="disc"><li><font face="">Bachelor’s Degree in Computer Science or a related field </font></li></ul>
<div>
<b><font face="">Reporting Relationships</font></b> </div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div><font face="">You will report to a Technology Manager or Director. This area is under the leadership of the SVP &amp; Chief Information Officer. </font></div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="">Additional Information</font></b></div>
<div><font face=""> </font></div>
<div><font face="">Humana is an organization with careers that change lives—including yours. As an innovator in the fast-paced industry of healthcare, we offer our associates careers that challenge, support and inspire them to use their passion for helping others and to lead their best lives. If you’re ready to help people achieve lifelong well-being, and be a part of an organization that is growing and poised to make an impact on the future of healthcare, Humana has the right opportunity for you.</font></div></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">At Humana, we’re also committed to making the resources available to you that will enable you to become happier, healthier, and more productive in all areas of your life.  We know your well-being is important to you, and it’s important to us too.

If you share our passion for helping people, we likely have the right place for you at Humana. After applying, we encourage you to join our Talent Network as well, so you can stay informed and up to date on what’s happening around our organization in the changing world of healthcare.</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
