<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">IT Finance Consultant</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">183346</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-KY-Louisville</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Office</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="2">Role: </font></b><font face="Arial" size="2">IT </font><font face="Arial" size="2">Finance Consultant<br><b>Assignment:</b> IT Strategy and Operations/IT Capacity and Resource Management<br><b>Location: </b>Louisville, KY</font>
</div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="2">Humana: Inspired for Life</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2">Healthcare isn’t just about health anymore. It’s about caring for family, friends, finances, and personal life goals. It’s about living life fully. At Humana, we want to help people everywhere, including our associates, lead their best lives. We support our associates to be happier, healthier, and more productive in their professional and personal lives. We encourage our people to build relationships that inspire, support, and challenge them. We promote lifelong well-being by giving our associates fresh perspective, new insights, and exciting opportunities to grow their careers. At Humana, we’re seeking innovative people who want to make positive changes in their lives, the lives of our members, and the healthcare industry as a whole</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="2">Assignment Capsule</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2">Under general supervision, you will track and forecast investment project spend from Humana’s Clarity application to Humana Information Technology’s monthly General Ledger.  You will prepare and analyze projections for IT spending and research variances to monthly forecasts and budget.  You will act as a Finance liaison collaborating with associates from IT and other business areas on special projects, and will identify ways to improve current reports and processes.</font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Review contract language to determine appropriate accounting coding for Purchase Orders</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2"><font face="Arial" size="2">Lead the month end close process including preparation/review of journal entries, account analysis, reconciliations, and reporting actual versus budget and forecasts. </font></font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Review Purchase Order and invoice detail to determine appropriate accounting treatment to apply in investment project spend model</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Reconcile the monthly labor, hardware, software and professional services expense back to the appropriate Clarity projects</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Maintain project data in project management (Clarity) system to ensure accurate reporting</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Partner with IT resource managers to determine required reporting metrics for various IT functions</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Combine reporting output from various systems and formats into consumable data</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Develop financial models with key levers for scenario-driven outcomes</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Create and monitor monthly reporting metrics</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Develop methods and criteria for measuring and summarizing financial data and preparing complex analyses</font></li>
</ul>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="2">Key Competencies</font></b></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Attention to detail</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Executive presentation: The materials developed will be presented to the Humana CIO and his leadership team.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Builds Trust: You honor your word by doing what you say you are going to do.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Drives for excellence: You are a continuous learner who encourages others to learn. By constantly upgrading your own work, you achieve results and outperform the competition.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Implementation/Execution: You are good at organizing and managing multiple priorities and/or projects by using appropriate methodologies and tools.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Problem Solving: You are a problem solver with the ability to encourage others in collaborative problem solving. Acting as both a broker and consultant regarding resources, you engage others in problem solving without taking over. </font></li>
</ul></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div><font size="2">
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="2">Role Essentials</font></b></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Bachelor’s Degree in Business, Finance, Accounting, Information Technology or a related field required</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">5-7 years of experience directly related to financial analysis, budgeting and management reporting </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Comprehensive knowledge of all Microsoft Office applications, Word, Excel, Outlook.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Detail oriented with strong analytical and problem solving skills</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Strong oral and written communication skills</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Strong organizational and multi-tasking skills</font></li>
</ul>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"><br><b>Role Desirables</b></font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">MBA and/or CPA preferred.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Executive dash-boarding experience</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Programming skills highly desirable (SQL, QlikView, VB)</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Experience in the health insurance industry and/or with information technology </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="2">Ability to support multiple priorities</font></li>
</ul>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="2">Reporting Relationships</font></b></div>
<ul type="disc"><li><font face="Arial" size="2">You will report to a Manager within IT Strategy &amp; Service Assurance. This area is under the leadership of the SVP &amp; Chief Information Officer </font></li></ul>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="2">Additional Information</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="2">At Humana, we’re also committed to making the resources available to you that will enable you to become happier, healthier, and more productive in all areas of your life. We know your well-being is important to you, and it’s important to us too.</font></div></font></div></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">Humana Inc., headquartered in Louisville, Ky., is a leading health care company that offers a wide range of insurance products and health and wellness services that incorporate an integrated approach to lifelong well-being. By leveraging the strengths of its core businesses, Humana believes it can better explore opportunities for existing and emerging adjacencies in health care that can further enhance wellness opportunities for the millions of people across the nation with whom the company has relationships.</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
