<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">Provider Payment Investigator</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">182368</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-KY-Louisville</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Office, Virtual/Work At Home</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1707.row1" class="subtitle">Travel</span></h2>
<span style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1724.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1734.row1" class="text">Yes, 10 % of the Time</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="3">Role: </font></b><font face="Arial" size="3">Provider Payment Investigator</font>
</div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"><strong>Assignment: </strong>Special Investigations Unit</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"><strong>Location: </strong>Work at Home - Kentucky</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Assignment Capsule:</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">The role of the investigator is to utilize appropriate resources from a variety of sources to investigate assigned cases within the Special Investigations Unit. </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">To accomplish their role, the investigator will rely on their experience and knowledge of necessary resources as well as guidelines and processes designed to ensure successful completion of investigations. The following tasks may be included in the Investigator’s day-to-day work: </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Develop the strategy or theory of the case, by identifying key questions and elements needed to prove or disprove the allegation </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Develop an investigative plan by identifying the information needed to prove or disprove the allegation, the resources needed to gather that information, and provide a timeline and task assignment to facilitate case completion </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Maintain a working knowledge of a variety of Federal Statutes, CMS Regulations and related guidelines including Anti-Kickback, Stark Law, procedural issues and general healthcare crimes so that the appropriate investigation can be completed </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Plan and conduct interviews either in person or by telephone of key witnesses (members, providers, associates, etc...). </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Coordinate working with other SIU staff in various locations around the country to complete in person interviews and other investigative activity as required </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Complete required documentation by utilizing the SIU forms for case notes, evidence, interviews, case activities/tasks, closing and recommendation, as well as maintaining accurate and up-to date activities in the case tracking system </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Develop a case summary to present the findings to management and assist in presenting findings to market leadership, law enforcement, government agencies, law department, etc. as needed </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Prioritize and effectively manage assigned cases, activities, and daily tasks (CCP, CTI, etc…) </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Maintain control and responsibility on all cases including work completed by others (IE. Data Analytics, researchers, clinical team, etc…)</font></li>
</ul>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">Managing Relationships:</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">While working in investigations, it’s imperative the investigator develop working relationships with internal and external associates. </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Build relationships with law enforcement and government agencies in assigned geographic region and ensure those relationships are appropriate and meet all Humana expectations for working with outside agencies </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Build relationships with the market contacts and other business partners in assigned product line and geographic regions </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Work collaboratively with other investigators, researchers in SIU and Clinical associates </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Provide support to other investigators as needed </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Ensure managers and leaders are aware of the status of all external and internal relationships and communications to allow for appropriate oversight and guidance</font></li>
</ul>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">Other Expectations:</font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Ensure internal and external reporting requirements are met for each investigation </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Ensure claims and records are handled appropriately and timely for each investigation (not responsible for final processing, just ensuring all tasks are completed timely and by the appropriate department) </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Adhere to established guidelines and Policies and Procedures; obtain approvals as required </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Effective 01/01/2015 – Completion of 20 Continuing Professional Education (CPE) credits are required annually for each investigator. The credits may include requirements for professional certifications or training related to investigations and related topics.</font></li>
</ul></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Role Essentials</font></b></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">High School Diploma or Equivalent</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Investigation experience. (Prior SIU or general insurance investigations, state or local law enforcement, FBI, CIA, DEA, Secret Service, OIG, General Accounting Office,MFCU, government agencies, corporate investigations, law firm, accounting firm) </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Strong organizational, interpersonal, and communication skills </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Inquisitive nature </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Computer literate (MS Word, Excel) </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Strong personal and professional ethics</font></li>
</ul>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Role Desirables</font></b></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Associates degree or Bachelor’s degree or Graduate degree and/or certifications (i.e., MBA, J.D., Masters in Criminal Justice, Masters in Forensic Accounting, CFE, AHFI, etc.) </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Experience in Medicare and Medicaid regulations </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Understanding of healthcare industry, claims processing, investigative process development, and auditing a plus </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Experience in a corporate environment and understanding of business operations </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Prior healthcare fraud investigations experience preferred </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Familiarity with Federal, state, and local law enforcement processes</font></li>
<li><font style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: white" face="Arial" size="3">Bilingual (English/Spanish)</font></li>
</ul>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Reporting Relationships</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">You will report to an SIU Investigative Lead</font></div></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">At Humana, we know your well-being is important to you, and it’s important to us too.  That’s why we’re committed to making resources available to you that will enable you to become happier, healthier, and more productive in all areas of your life.  If you share our passion for helping people, we likely have the right place for you at Humana.
After applying, we encourage you to join our Talent Network as well, so you can stay informed and up to date on what’s happening around our organization in the changing world of healthcare.</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
