<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">Quality Improvement Nurse (RN/LPN) - Work at home - El Paso, Midland and Odessa, TX area</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">182005</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-Texas-San Antonio</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Virtual/Work At Home</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1707.row1" class="subtitle">Travel</span></h2>
<span style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1724.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1734.row1" class="text">Yes, 75 % of the Time</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div><font size="2"><b>Role: Quality Improvement Nurse (RN/LPN)<br>Assignment: Senior Products <br>Location: Work at home in the El Paso, Midland and Odessa, TX area</b><br><br><b>Assignment Capsule</b> <br>The Quality Improvement Nurse will facilitate and work collaboratively with provider groups focused on Senior Products, Commercial, Medicare and Medicaid plans to guide, document and track practice specific strategies designed to improve all aspects of Stars and Quality.</font></div>
<div><font size="2"> </font></div>
<div><b><font size="2">This is a work at home position in the El Paso, Midland, Odessa, TX market.  This individual will spend about 75% of their time in the field visiting providers offices within the El Paso, Midland, and Odessa area.  The ideal candidate will be self-driven, motivated, outgoing and a real go getter.  HEDIS experience and a quality background are a plus.  Strong computer skills are needed in this role with a good working knowledge of Excel.  Teamwork and ability to collaborate within a workgroup is the key and success to this role.</font></b></div>
<div><font size="2"> </font></div>
<div><font size="2">Responsibilities include:</font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font size="2">Critical thinking to prioritize PCP outreach based on what will deliver greatest return on investment (i.e. who to outreach, frequency of outreach, visit focus, communication method / collateral)</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Evaluate provider current state willingness to work with Humana to improve Stars performance and tailor messaging accordingly</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Identify key point of contact for each prioritized PCP and effectively develop / enhance provider clinical relationship across product lines.  Accurately define gaps in Humana’s service relationship with providers and facilitate resolution through Service Alignment Manager (SAM)</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Deliver provider/member-specific metrics and supporting collateral (e.g., HEDIS Summary, Patient Experience, Rx Opportunity, etc.) and coach providers on improving all aspects of Stars performance</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Educate PCP’s on Stars program, changes and best practices to enhance all aspects of Stars performance</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Identify provider best practices and needs, disseminate for sharing and / or resolution</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Maintain documentation of provider visit, including focus and performance trending (Quality Journal)</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Facilitate effective collaboration and communication with workgroup members (including operations, clinical and MRA) and Stars and Quality team members</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Identify opportunities to improve Stars and Quality processes, methods, team engagement, etc. and present resolution options / cost</font></li>
</ul></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div><font size="2"><b>Role Essentials</b> </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font size="2">Experienced clinical background as RN or LPN</font></li>
<li><font size="2">At least 3 years of varied clinical nursing experience</font></li>
<li><font size="2">History of taking on roles of increased responsibilities with proven results </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Self-directed and motivated, with proven ability to work independently given general instructions </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Strong communication and public speaking skills; proven influencer </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Strong organizational and prioritization skills with ability to collaborate across multiple departments </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Detail orientated, forward looking and comfortable working with tight deadlines in a fast paced, dynamic environment </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Demonstrated proficiency with MS Office Suite (Word, Excel and PowerPoint) </font></li>
<li><font size="2">This role is considered patient facing and is part of Humana’s Tuberculosis (TB) screening program.  If selected for this role, you will be required to be screened for TB.</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Must have accessibility to high speed DSL or Cable modem for a home office (Satellite internet service is NOT allowed for this role); and recommended speed for optimal performance from Humana systems is 10Mx1M</font></li>
</ul>
<div><font size="2"><b>Role Desirables</b> </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font size="2">Knowledge of CMS Stars Program elements, including HEDIS, Patient Experience and Patient Safety</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Strong Communication and Collaborative/Teamwork Skills and abilities</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Physician office practice experience </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Previous experience and/or knowledge of Quality Improvement or process improvement</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Strong analytic skills and ability to use data to drive improvement activities</font></li>
<li><font size="2">Previous Health Insurance clinical or operations experience</font></li>
</ul>
<div><font size="2"><b>Reporting Relationships</b> </font></div>
<ul type="disc"><li><font size="2">This role reports to the Frontline Leader, Manager and Quality Improvement Director. </font></li></ul>
<div><font size="2"><b>Additional Information</b> </font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font size="2">Work  at Home role traveling 75% of the time</font></li>
<li><font size="2">This role works closely with Market Operations, MRA, HSO and Clinical teams</font></li>
</ul>
<div><b><font size="2">Interview Format </font></b></div>
<div><font size="2"> </font></div>
<div><font size="2">As part of our hiring process for this opportunity, we will be using an exciting interviewing technology called Montage Voice to enhance our hiring and decision-making ability. Montage Voice allows us to quickly connect and gain valuable information from you pertaining to your relevant skills and experience at a time that is best for your schedule. </font></div>
<div><font size="2"> </font></div>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px"><font size="2">If you are selected for a first round interview, you will receive an email correspondence <b>(please be sure to check your spam or junk folders often to ensure communication isn’t missed)</b> inviting you to participate in a Montage Voice interview. In this interview, you will listen to a set of interview questions over your phone and you will provide recorded responses to each question. You should anticipate this interview to take about 15 to 30 minutes. Your recorded interview will be reviewed and you will subsequently be informed if you will be moving forward to next round of interviews. </font></p></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">Humana Inc., headquartered in Louisville, Ky., is a leading health care company that offers a wide range of insurance products and health and wellness services that incorporate an integrated approach to lifelong well-being. By leveraging the strengths of its core businesses, Humana believes it can better explore opportunities for existing and emerging adjacencies in health care that can further enhance wellness opportunities for the millions of people across the nation with whom the company has relationships.</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
