<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">Strategic Consultant - Data Governance</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">182741</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-KY-Louisville</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Office</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div>
<div>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="3">Role: </font></b><font face="Arial" size="3">DG Strategic Consultant</font>
</div>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="3">Assignment:</font></b><font face="Arial" size="3"> IT</font>
</div>
<div>
<b><font face="Arial" size="3">Location: </font></b><font face="Arial" size="3">Louisville, KY</font>
</div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">At Humana, we want to help people everywhere, including our associates, lead their best lives and achieve lifelong well-being. We look for talented individuals who share this passion for helping others, who have naturally curious and innovative minds, and who want a career where they can use their technical skills to make a positive impact on the lives of our members.</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">In the fast-paced, ever-growing world of Healthcare, Humana relies on its data and information more than ever to create superior consumer and market value.  We need professionals who can create and implement strategies necessary to enhance, optimize, and modernize the processes and infrastructure impacting how we manage and share our most important data across the enterprise and the healthcare ecosystem.  Governing our data appropriately requires managing dynamic and complex relationships between internal businesses, IT, consumers, providers, competitors, and regulators. We are creating a data and analytics driven enterprise capable of fueling an innovative value-creation engine upon which we will continuously deliver competitive differentiation.  </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Assignment Capsule </font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">The Data Governance Office is part of the Technology Advancement Team.  Together we are leading the way to an Insights Driven Organization.  We need highly motivated innovative thought leaders to help us lead our industry now and far into the future.  Join us!  Be a part of the Data Governance Office -- Be a strategic leader in the exciting cutting edge world of Healthcare.</font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">Successful candidates will be self-motivated, enthusiastic, and proactive.  They will collaborate and share information, best practices, and experiences with others and will be leaders of innovative thought, balanced with practical application and experience.  They will possess both hard and soft skills and be truly cross-functional professionals capable of handling dynamic subjects and business functions easily and collaboratively.  </font></div>
<div> </div>
<div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Responsibilities:</font></b></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Responsible for ensuring the success of all aspects of Humana’s data governance program.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">coordinate with business leaders and their teams to identify systemic issues related to the appropriate and proper use of data which impact the achievement of our corporate and business unit strategic objectives</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">work with others to coordinate and engage the 200+ Business Information Stewards in DG programs</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">identify and document opportunities and use cases for improving our operational and analytical processes through better and more effective use of information</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">translate complex concepts into clear, logical business cases (us cases) relevant to the individual missions of our Business Information Stewards while helping them understand the impact/value to the enterprise</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">facilitate cross-functional focus groups targeted at creating consensus among disparate functional teams to solve complex business problems</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">support strategic business initiatives using a consultative approach, providing expertise on a variety of data governance related subjects including, but not limited to, Privacy (HIPAA), Data Quality Management, Data Security, Business Intelligence, Analytics, and Master Data Management</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">document processes, best practices, standards, and policies for data governance</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">create awareness and adoption for policies, processes, and best practices related to data governance</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">identify and elevate potential data risks and/or issues which may exist within the enterprise and provide guidance on potential action to take</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">actively participate in the development and implementation of our corporate data strategy, strategic blueprints and designs, and overseeing the governance of related standards, policies, and best practices</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Interpreting business needs into data requirements, including such attributes as naming standards, consistent data definitions, data aliases, associated business rules, data sources, systems of record, sources of records, systems of interaction, etc…</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Performing other duties as identified over time by the changing and evolving requirements of the business as they pertain to the governance and stewardship of our data</font></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px"> </p></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div><b>Role Essentials</b></div>
<div>
<b></b> </div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">The DG Strategic Consultant will be responsible for the development of Strategic Technology Blueprints used to define the future state data and analytics infrastructure of Humana.  Additionally, this role will be accountable for the accurate interpretation, correct implementation, and overall adoption of these blueprints.  In order for the chosen candidate to be successful, s/he must be able to demonstrate exceptional proficiency in the following areas:</font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Strong experience (5 years) with Healthcare Business Systems or Processing.</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">1 – 3 years’ experience with healthcare data, reporting, analytics, or modeling </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Working knowledge of data governance principles and stewardship processes</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Deep understanding of how data supports corporate strategy, is used within business processes and its impact</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Able to think strategically, with a solid grasp of business issues and objectives, the implications of different solutions, and the identification of the optimal solution given the current environment’s constraints</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Demonstrated ability to balance team and individual responsibilities; gaining consensus; influence without authority</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Demonstrated knowledge of data structure, data systems/tools and related software and data management policies and practices in a complex organizational environment</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Capability to lead work efforts and deliverables compliant with data policies, standards, and processes with consistency across the enterprise </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Ability to recognize and investigate anomalies and proactively problem solve</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Able to work within a fast-paced environment with quickly changing priorities </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Bachelor’s Degree or work equivalent</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Directly applicable Healthcare experience </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Professional image and excellent communication skills required </font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Possess a solid understanding of operations, technology, communications and process improvement/management</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Prior experience in the healthcare industry (preferably Humana)</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">5+ years business requirements gathering and analysis</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Business process mapping</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Complex problem solving</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Meeting facilitation &amp; presentation skills</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Organizational change management (OCM)</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Excellent communications; both written and verbal</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Project management</font></li>
</ul>
<div> </div>
<div>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Role Desirables</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">Demonstrated work experience in any of the following areas is a significant plus for hopeful candidates:</font></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Business Strategy Formulation</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Six Sigma</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Pyramid Principle</font></li>
<li><font face="Arial" size="3">Information Security and/or Privacy</font></li>
</ul>
<div><b><font face="Arial" size="3">Reporting Relationships</font></b></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">You will report to the Data Governance Office under the leadership of the Chief of Data Governance.  </font></div>
</div>
<div> </div>
<div><b>Additional Information</b></div>
<div>At Humana, we know your well-being is important to you, and it’s important to us too.  That’s why we’re committed to making resources available to you that will enable you to become happier, healthier, and more productive in all areas of your life.  If you share our passion for helping people, we likely have the right place for you at Humana.</div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div>
<div> </div></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">Humana Inc., headquartered in Louisville, Ky., is a leading health care company that offers a wide range of insurance products and health and wellness services that incorporate an integrated approach to lifelong well-being. By leveraging the strengths of its core businesses, Humana believes it can better explore opportunities for existing and emerging adjacencies in health care that can further enhance wellness opportunities for the millions of people across the nation with whom the company has relationships.</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
