<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body><div class="editablesection">
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1463.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" class="titlepage">Technology Business Consultant</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1474.row1" class="titlepage">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqContestNumberValue.row1" class="titlepage">183240</span><span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1515.row1" class="subtitle">Primary Location</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1532.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1542.row1" class="text">US-KY-Louisville</span>
</div>
<div id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1549" style="display: none;"></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1599.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1605.row1" class="subtitle">Work Environment Type</span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1622.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1632.row1" class="text">Office</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1641.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1657.row1" class="subtitle">Schedule</span></h2>
<span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1674.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1684.row1" class="text">Full-time</span>
</div>
<div style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1691.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<h2 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:ftl="http://www.taleo.net/ftl" class="no-change-header-inline"><span title="" style="display: inline;" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1707.row1" class="subtitle">Travel</span></h2>
<span style="" title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1724.row1" class="subtitle">:</span><span class="inline"> </span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1734.row1" class="text">Yes, 5 % of the Time</span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1741.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1750.row1" class="text"><div><font face="'Arial'">
<div><font face="Calibri"><b><font size="3">Role: </font></b><font size="3">Technology Business Consultant </font></font></div>
<div><font face="Calibri"><b><font size="3">Assignment: </font></b><font size="3">Humana Government Business- IT</font></font></div>
<div><font face="Calibri"><b><font size="3">Location: </font></b><font size="3">Office- </font><font size="3">Louisville, KY</font></font></div>
<div><font face="Times New Roman" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><font size="3"><font face="Calibri">In the fast-paced, ever-growing world of Healthcare, Humana relies on the latest technology and trends for sharing and storing information, communication and security. We need experts in technology to help us develop and maintain our networks, hardware, and software—to ensure our systems run smoothly and efficiently, keep us on the forefront of innovation in healthcare, and retain our competitive edge. At Humana, we want to help people everywhere, including our associates lead their best lives and achieve lifelong well-being. We look for talented individuals who share this passion for helping others, who have naturally curious and innovative minds, and who want a career where they can use their technical skills to make a positive impact on the lives of our members. </font></font></div>
<div><font face="Times New Roman" size="3"> </font></div>
<div><font face="Calibri"><b><font size="3">Assignment Capsule</font></b> </font></div>
<div><font size="3"><font face="Calibri">Provide business consulting to proactively identify and manage business process improvement opportunities.  Make use of the work of business analysts, lead and participate in efforts to design innovative and strategic business processes that maximize Information Technology solutions, create sustainable competitive advantage and deliver administrative efficiencies. Provide project and program coordination to guide the implementation of new processes and process modification and assist with change management to minimize disruption and maximize impact. The Business Consultant understands requirements in the broadest context of business problems and opportunities, and recommends solutions that enable innovative delivery of Humana’s brand and value proposition. </font></font></div>
<div><font size="3"><font face="Calibri"> </font></font></div>
<div><b><font size="3"><font face="Calibri">Our Department of Defense Contract requires U.S. citizenship for this position.</font></font></b></div>
<ul type="disc">
<li><font size="3">Proactively identifies improvement opportunities and helps to identify business opportunities based on industry and competitive trends and analysis of current processes and barriers.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Works closely with the user community and formal user groups to elicit project requirements and work with developers to translate those requirements into technical designs.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Perform project work breakdown, task creation, scheduling, scope design, risk analysis, quality control, execution monitoring, and lessons learned.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Work with user groups and business project managers on project ranking, valuation, and scheduling. </font></li>
<li><font size="3">Maintain a business orientation, and understand the contribution and impact of systems work on the stakeholders. </font></li>
<li><font size="3">Leads the design of innovative business processes that support Information Technology solutions, create sustainable competitive advantage and administrative efficiencies.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Guides project and program implementation efforts and manages change to assure expected results are achieved.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Provides analysis to major projects and improvement efforts. Develops and manages project plans for projects.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Assures process documentation meets current and future requirements and supports the successful implementation of business innovation.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Provides assistance to less experienced analysts on a broad range of project management and process engineering disciplines to disseminate learning and promote the development of others.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Extends professional knowledge and develops skills through departmental training and self-motivated opportunities.</font></li>
</ul></font></div></span>
</div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1759.row1" class="contentlinepanel"><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1762.row1" class="text"><div>
<div><strong><font face="Arial" size="3">Role Essentials</font> </strong></div>
<ul>
<li>
<div>Successfully receive interim approval for government security clearance (eQIP - Electronic Questionnaire for Investigation Processing)</div>
</li>
<li>
<div><font size="3">Bachelor’s Degree, technical area preferred, or technical training equivalent </font></div>
</li>
<li><font size="3">5 years of business analysis, project, and process management experience</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Ability to do data analysis using data queries.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Familiarity with standard office tools such as Word, Excel, Visio, and Project.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">May substitute equivalent education and/or experience for degree</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Excellent communication and interpersonal skills</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Excellent organization skills.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Ability to read and interpret documents such as contracts and operations manuals</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Ability to develop project plans encompassing input from internal/external leadership.</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Ability to speak effectively before groups of customers or employees of organization</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Problem solving abilities</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Self-motivated and task oriented</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Able to prioritize assignments with little guidance</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Knowledge of Microsoft Office products</font></li>
<li><font size="3">Ability to get along with others.</font></li>
</ul>
<div><strong><font face="Arial" size="3">Role Desirables</font> </strong></div>
<ul type="disc"><li><font face="Arial" size="3">PMP, CBAP, or CCP certification</font></li></ul>
<div><strong><font face="Arial" size="3">Additional Information</font> </strong></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3"><strong> </strong></font></div>
<div><font face="Arial" size="3">At Humana, we know your well-being is important to you, and it’s important to us too. That’s why we’re committed to making resources available to you that will enable you to become happier, healthier, and more productive in all areas of your life. If you share our passion for helping people, we likely have the right place for you at Humana. </font></div>
</div>
<div>
<font face="'Arial'" size="3"></font> </div></span></div>
<div title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1771.row1" class="contentlinepanel">
<span class="blockpanel"><span class=""> </span></span><span title="" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1780.row1" class="text">Humana Government Business, Inc. (Humana Government) is a wholly owned subsidiary of Fortune 100 health and wellness company Humana Inc. Headquartered in Louisville, KY, we have been a Department of Defense TRICARE Managed Care Support Contractor since 1995, currently serving more than 3 million beneficiaries in the South Region of the United States. Humana Government Business has the proven experience and capability to manage highly complex, large-scale health care programs throughout the federal government.  Humana Government Business is comprised of several lines of business including</span>
</div>
</div></body></html>
