<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body>
<input value="Arlington, VA" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Analysis, Architecture, BI Tools, Business Objects, BW, Cognos, Consulting, Data Analysis, Data Architecture, Data Modeling, DataStage, DBA, Development, EDM, ERwin, ESSBase, Excel, Hadoop, HTML, HTTP, Informatica, Management, Modeling, Recruiter, Research, SAP, SAP BW, SAS" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Enterprise Data Management Consultant" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Analysis, Architecture, BI Tools, Business Objects, BW, Cognos, Consulting, Data Analysis, Data Architecture, Data Modeling, DataStage, DBA, Development, EDM, ERwin, ESSBase, Excel, Hadoop, HTML, HTTP, Informatica, Management, Modeling, Recruiter, Research, SAP, SAP BW, SAS
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time, Permanent</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
				
					
					
						<span class="mL20">Competitive</span>
						<span itemprop="baseSalary" style="display:none"></span>
					
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><div>Are you passionate about working with data? Are you a hands-on technologist interested in how information can transform business and government? If so, Deloitte could be the place for you!  Join our Federal Analytics and Information Management (AIM) team and tackle challenging issues in Advanced Analytics, Big Data Architecture, and Information Delivery.  <font style="BACKGROUND-COLOR: white">A career at Deloitte will put you on the frontline, supporting Federal agencies tasked with the most critical technical challenges. </font>
</div>
<br><div>  </div>
<br><div><b>Work you’ll do </b></div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div>As a Consultant in our practice you will: </div>
<br><ul>
<li>
<br><div>Problem solve and offer ideas to solve client issues </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Conduct relevant research, data analysis, and create reports  </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Identify efficiencies and innovative approaches  </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Maintain responsibility for completion and accuracy of work products </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Assist in proposal development as requested </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Develop your skills through training courses, mentoring, and daily interaction with clients </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Develop your passion for data management </div>
</li>
</ul>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div><b>The team </b></div>
<br><div><b> <i>  </i> </b></div>
<br><div>Transparency, innovation, collaboration, sustainability: these are the hallmark issues shaping Federal government initiatives today. Deloitte’s Federal practice is passionate about making an impact with lasting change.  Carrying out missions in the Federal practice requires fresh thinking and a creative approach. We collaborate with teams from across our organization in order to bring the full breadth of Deloitte, its commercial and public sector expertise, to best support our clients.  Our aspiration is to be the premier integrated solutions provider in helping to transform the Federal marketplace. </div>
<br><div>The Federal Government is seeing massive increases in the amount of information that it creates, collects, and manages to support data driven decision making, and in some cases exceeding the limits of traditional approaches and technology.  Our Federal AIM team helps change the way clients leverage data through innovative and robust solutions within traditional landscapes as well as emerging areas including Big Data, Internet of Things/Everything, cognitive analytics, and machine learning. </div>
<br><div>  </div>
<br><div><b>Qualifications </b></div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div>Required: </div>
<br><ul>
<li>
<br><div>Bachelor's degree and at least 1 year of technology consulting or other relevant industry experience </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Proven ability to effectively prioritize workload and meet deadlines  </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Experience crafting written communications that are clear, succinct and audience appropriate </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Proficiency in word processing, spreadsheet, and presentation creation tools, as well as Internet research tools </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Must be able to obtain and maintain required clearance for this role </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Experience with problem solving in a EDM environment </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Exposure to data queries and data sets </div>
<br><div>  </div>
</li>
</ul>
<br><div>  </div>
<br><div>Preferred: </div>
<br><ul>
<li>
<br><div>Degree in computer science, information systems, or other technology-related field </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Prior professional services or federal consulting experience  </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Professional experience with one or more of the following technologies: </div>
<br><ul>
<li>
<br><div>BI tools: SAP Business Objects, Cognos, OBIEE, SAS, Hyperion </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>DW/ETL Tools: Informatica, ODI, SAP Data Services, SAP BW/HANA, Datastage </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>EPM: Hyperion Essbase, Cognos Planning </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>EDM: Data Modeling, Erwin, DBA </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>MDM ‑ Informatica  </div>
</li>
<li>
<br><div>Data Analytics: Big data, ZoomData, Hadoop, machine learning, text analytics, Tableau </div>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<br><div>  </div>
<br><div>  </div>
<br><div><b>How you’ll grow </b></div>
<br><div>
<font size="2"> <font color="windowtext">At Deloitte, our professional development plan focuses on helping people at every level of their career to identify and use their strengths to do their best work every day. From entry-level employees to senior leaders, we believe there’s always room to learn. We offer opportunities to help sharpen skills in addition to hands-on experience in the global, fast-changing business world.  From on-the-job learning experiences to formal development programs at Deloitte University, our professionals have a variety of opportunities to continue to grow throughout their career.   </font> </font> <a href="https://zoomforth.com/s/deloitte/du#home">Explore Deloitte University, The Leadership Center. </a>
</div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div><b>Benefits </b></div>
<br><div>At Deloitte, we know that great people make a great organization. We value our people and offer employees a broad range of benefits.  <a href="http://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/pages/careers/articles/life-at-deloitte-benefits-and-rewards.html">Learn more about what working at Deloitte can mean for you. </a>
</div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div><b>Deloitte’s culture </b></div>
<br><div>Our positive and supportive culture encourages our people to do their best work every day. We celebrate individuals by recognizing their uniqueness and offering them the flexibility to make daily choices that can help them to be healthy, centered, confident, and aware. We offer well-being programs and are continuously looking for new ways to maintain a culture where our people excel and lead healthy, happy lives.   <a href="http://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/careers/life-at-deloitte.html?icid=top_life-at-deloitte">Learn more about Life at Deloitte. </a>
</div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div><b>Corporate citizenship </b></div>
<br><div>Deloitte is led by a purpose: to make an impact that matters. This purpose defines who we are and extends to relationships with our clients, our people and our communities.  We believe that business has the power to inspire and transform. We focus on education, giving, skill-based volunteerism, and leadership to help drive positive social impact in our communities.   <a href="http://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/pages/about-deloitte/articles/deloitte-corporate-citizenship.html">Learn more about Deloitte’s impact on the world. </a>
</div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div><b>Recruiter tips </b></div>
<br><div>We want job seekers exploring opportunities at Deloitte to feel prepared and confident. To help you with your interview, we suggest that you do your research: know some background about the organization and the business area you’re applying to.  <a href="http://www2.deloitte.com/us/en/pages/careers/topics/recruiting-tips.html">Check out recruiting tips from Deloitte professionals. </a>
</div>
<br><div><b>  </b></div>
<br><div>  </div>
<br><div>Deloitte is one of the leading professional services organizations in the United States, specializing in audit, tax, consulting, and financial advisory services with clients in more than 20 industries. We provide powerful business solutions to some of the world's most well-known and respected companies, including more than 75 percent of the Fortune 100.  <br><br><br>At Deloitte, you can have a rewarding career on every level. In addition to challenging and meaningful work, you'll have the chance to give back to your community, make a positive impact on the environment, participate in a range of diversity and inclusion initiatives, and find the support, coaching, and training it takes to advance your career. Our commitment to individual choice lets you customize aspects of your career path, your educational opportunities and your benefits. And our culture of innovation means your ideas on how to improve our business and your clients' will be heard. </div>
<br><br><b>About Deloitte </b><br><br><br>As used in this document, “Deloitte” means Deloitte LLP and its subsidiaries. Please see www.deloitte.com/us/about for a detailed description of the legal structure of Deloitte LLP and its subsidiaries. All qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, national origin, age, disability or protected veteran status, or any other legally protected basis, in accordance with applicable law. <br><br><br><p style="font-style:italic;">Disclaimer: If you are not reviewing this job posting on our Careers' site (careers.deloitte.com) or one of our approved job boards we cannot guarantee the validity of this posting. For a list of our current postings, please visit us at careers.deloitte.com.
		</p>
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
				
					
						Arlington, VA
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->

			<br><hr>
<div class="row">
					<div class="col-md-12">
						<h1 class="jobdesc">Company Information</h1>
						<div class="highlight-black mTB20">
							
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				<div class="row">
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<iframe class="company-media" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/O3aOXEjHysM?list=PLF25F60F4F02D2BC8" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>
						</div>
					
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<img class="company-media" src="//assets.dice.com/techpro/companies/brandMax/Deloitte/rectangle-400.png">
</div>
					
				</div>
</body></html>
