<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CN-C6qSj7dcCFQFmwQodC9QCbg" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Chicago, IL" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="AB Initio, Agile, Analyst, Call Center, Database, Development, Hadoop, Informatica, Java, Lifecycle, Linux, Management, MS Office, Project, Python, QA, Quality Assurance, Scripts, SQL, Testing, Unix" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Big Data QA Engineer" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				AB Initio, Agile, Analyst, Call Center, Database, Development, Hadoop, Informatica, Java, Lifecycle, Linux, Management, MS Office, Project, Python, QA, Quality Assurance, Scripts, SQL, Testing, Unix
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><div class="editablesection">
<br><div class="contentlinepanel" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1472.row1" title=""><span class="titlepage" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.reqTitleLinkAction.row1" title="">Big Data QA Engineer </span></div>
<br><div class="contentlinepanel" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1484.row1" title="">
<span class="text" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1487.row1" title="">USA-IL-Greater Chicago-Chicago </span> <span aria-hidden="true" class="text" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1493.row1" title="">| </span> <span class="text" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1499.row1" title="">Call Center </span>
</div>
<br><div class="contentlinepanel" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1506.row1" title=""><span class="text" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1509.row1" title=""><br><div><b> <font size="2">QA Sr. Analyst – Data Analytics </font> </b></div>
<br><div><b> <font size="2">  </font> </b></div>
<br><div><b> <font size="2">Dynamics of the Role </font> </b></div>
<br><div><font size="2">  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">This analyst position is responsible for independently conducting test processes for testing projects.  In addition, this position ensures that the documentation of test results is complete and accurate.  At this level, an associate acts independently to determine methods and procedures on new or special assignments.  Additionally, associates at this level fully understand all concepts and applications of quality assurance testing and performs all of the regular functions commonly required in quality assurance testing.  Testing expertise is acknowledged by their peers and application and/or domain knowledge is deemed outstanding by business and technical customers.  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">  </font></div>
<br><div><b> <font size="2">The Team’s Focus </font> </b></div>
<br><div><font size="2">  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">TransUnion Healthcare, one of the fastest growing verticals in a $2-billion global company, is a wholly owned subsidiary of the global credit and information management company TransUnion. TransUnion offers a series of data and decisioning solutions designed to help providers and patients find financial solutions for needed care. In the payer market, TransUnion offers healthcare analytics and reporting solutions to help payers improve the overall health of their members. The implementation of these solutions is changing the way healthcare is delivered in America. As TransUnion’s fastest-growing business, we think of ourselves as a start-up company with a trusted pedigree. We pride ourselves on fostering a fun, friendly work culture that allows associates at every level the opportunity to make meaningful contributions to innovative projects – and allows them a life outside the office. Our salaries, bonuses, and benefits are highly competitive – designed to attract and retain great talent. And our engaged and accessible senior staff members pride themselves on creating opportunities for associates to collaborate, grow, and advance.  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">  </font></div>
<br><div><b> <font size="2">How You’ll Contribute:  </font> </b></div>
<br><div>
<br><ul>
<li><font size="2">Responsible for all of the Quality Assurance deliverables including thoughtful development of test strategies, test scenarios and test cases for all phases of testing.  </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Builds and/ or recommends appropriate test automation where needed. </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Develops test strategies for application changes and new features.  Able to work through project obstacles and removes impediments </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Builds strong relationships across IT and business teams </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Successfully ensures sufficient test coverage for all projects. </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Develops a complete understanding of the application and the underlying technology. </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Able to perform test execution on all tests as needed </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Implements necessary test processes on projects, writes test plans, procedures, and scripts, analyzes test results; actively recommends and implements process improvements for supported projects </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Serves as a ‘risk owner’; communicates and provides documentation throughout the project lifecycle that advises the project teams of potential risk areas </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Remains educated/ informed on the full suite of testing tools, processes and artifacts that are available </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Embraces change and successfully brings innovative ideas to the team </font></li>
</ul>
</div>
<br><div><br></div></span></div>
<br><div class="contentlinepanel" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1518.row1" title=""><span class="text" id="requisitionDescriptionInterface.ID1521.row1" title=""><br><div><b> <font size="2">What You’ll Bring:  </font> </b></div>
<br><div>
<br><ul>
<li><font size="2">3-6+ years of technical QA experience </font></li>
<li><font size="2">2+ years of experience testing ETL processes or experience with data analytics platforms </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experienced with test automation for ETL and analytics applications </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience with any BigData/DataAnalytics solutions built on Hadoop, MapR, Hive/Pig, Hue, Informatica Big Data. </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience with Data Visualization tools such as Tableau or other data visualization tools </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Technical expertise; solid understanding of coding practices (.Net, Java , Ab Initio and/ or database management a plus) </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Strong SQL skills </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience working as part of an agile team </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Ability to describe good quality / testing techniques </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Strong use of MS office and Test management systems </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Demonstrated success at mitigating most risks while proactively escalating issues with possible solutions </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Demonstrated success in delivering on-time with quality </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Proven ability to quickly adapt to new technologies and processes </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience working on Linux or Unix systems </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience working with Ab Initio is a plus </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience with Hadoop technologies is a plus </font></li>
<li><font size="2">Experience with scripting language like Python is desirable. </font></li>
</ul>
</div>
<br><div><b> <font size="2">Who We Are </font> </b></div>
<br><div><font size="2"><br></font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">At TransUnion, we are dedicated to finding ways information can be used to help people make better and smarter decisions. As a trusted provider of global information solutions, our mission is to help people around the world access the opportunities that lead to a higher quality of life, by helping organizations optimize their risk-based decisions and enabling consumers to understand and manage their personal information. Because when people have access to more complete and multidimensional information, they can make more informed decisions and achieve great things. </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">Every day TransUnion offers our employees the tools and resources they need to find ways information can be used in diverse ways. Whether it is helping businesses better manage risk, providing better insights so a consumer can qualify for his first mortgage or working with law enforcement to make neighborhoods safer, we are improving the quality of life for individuals, families, communities and local economies around the world. </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2">We are an equal opportunity employer and all qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, national origin, age, disability status, veteran status, marital status, citizenship status, sexual orientation, gender identity or any other characteristic protected by law.  </font></div>
<br><div><font size="2"><br></font></div>
<br><div><font size="2"></font></div></span></div>
</div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
