<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CPWb76W77tcCFQtqwQodSKkFMQ" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Raleigh, NC" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Analysis, AntiVirus, Architecture, Change Management, Data Analysis, Development, Disaster Recovery, Excel, Exchange, LAN, Manager, Management, Microsoft Powerpoint, Microsoft Project, PowerPoint, Project, Project Management, Project Manager, Routers, Security, Switches, WAN, Windows" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Sr Project Manager (Data Center Migration)" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Analysis, AntiVirus, Architecture, Change Management, Data Analysis, Development, Disaster Recovery, Excel, Exchange, LAN, Manager, Management, Microsoft Powerpoint, Microsoft Project, PowerPoint, Project, Project Management, Project Manager, Routers, Security, Switches, WAN, Windows
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><br><br> Welcome to Allscripts! Our Mission is to be the most trusted provider of innovative solutions that empower all stakeholders across the healthcare continuum to deliver world class outcomes. Our Vision is a Connected Community of Health that spans continents and borders. With the largest community of clients in healthcare, Allscripts is able to deliver an integrated platform of clinical, financial, connectivity and information solutions to facilitate enhanced collaboration and exchange of critical patient information.<br><br> The primary purpose of this role is to manage a workstream of a large data center consolidation effort into private cloud model<br><br> Provide interface with an IT Outsourcing vendor who manages current/future data centers<br><br> Coordinate architecture and process review to define future operating model<br><br>Qualifications<br><br><b>Academic and professional qualifications: </b> <br><br> * Bachelor's Degree in relevant technical field, (Information Technology, Computer Science, Software, Engineering, or related technical discipline)<br> * Project Management Certification highly preferred<br> * Experience managing IT outsourcing (ITO) preferred or third-party (vendors or contracts)<br> * Strong technology background with an understand in one or more areas:<br> + Windows server environments (cloud, virtual and physical)<br> + Network basics LAN/WAN and components (i.e. switches, routers, firewalls, load balancers)<br> + Security basics including antivirus, security and event monitoring, intrusion prevention<br> + Disaster recovery (DR) services or business continuity<br> + Data center, application, or Server migrations<br> + ServiceNow or IT service management toolset (i.e. incident management, assessment management, change management)<br> * Program management experience<br> + Experience in Microsoft Project (Project plan development and tracking)<br> + Experience in Microsoft PowerPoint and Excel (status report and data analysis)<br> + Development of ad hoc presentations<br> + Experience managing risks and issues logs<br> + Experience driving actions and decisions to completion<br> + Experience organizing and facilitating meetings<br> + Excellent note taker<br> + Excellent communication skills required, both written and verbal<br><br>Travel as required<br><br> #LI-JW1<br><br> At Allscripts, our greatest strength comes from bringing together talented people with diverse perspectives to support the technology needs of 180,000 physicians, 1,500 hospitals and 10,000 post-acute organizations across the globe. Allscripts offers a comprehensive compensation and benefits package, including holidays, vacation, medical, dental, and vision insurance, company paid life insurance and retirement savings.<br><br> Allscripts' policy is to provide equal employment opportunity and affirmative action in all of its employment practices without regard to race, color, religion, sex, national origin, ancestry, marital status, protected veteran status, age, individuals with disabilities, sexual orientation or gender identity or expression or any other legally protected category. Applicants for North American based positions with Allscripts must be legally authorized to work in the United States or Canada. Verification of employment eligibility will be required as a condition of hire.<br><br> From a "VEVRAA Federal Contractor" We request Priority Referral of Protected Veterans<br><br><br><br><b>Department: </b> Information Technology
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
