<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CIWp5qe37tcCFZRqwQodKYcHHg" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="West Des Moines, IA" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="data warehouse, devops, technical leadership, data analysis, big data, python, java" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Data Warehouse Tech Lead" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				data warehouse, devops, technical leadership, data analysis, big data, python, java
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
				
					
					
						<span class="mL20">Depends On Experience</span>
						<span itemprop="baseSalary" style="display:none"></span>
					
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<p>We are Athene. At Athene, we are driven to do more. We are a leading retirement services company that issues, reinsures and acquires retirement savings products designed for the increasing number of individuals and institutions seeking to fund retirement needs. We see every day as a new opportunity to measure ourselves against the best - and then we don't stop until we've set the bar even higher. We're ready to help you achieve more.</p>
<p><strong>Purpose:</strong></p>
<p>Builds and maintains Data Warehousing applications that assist the company in minimizing administrative costs and maximizing information flow.</p>
<p><strong>Accountabilities:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lead large project efforts in programming-based data warehouse design, development and testing</li>
<li>Provide technical advice to senior IT management or project managers, assisting them with high level planning or issue resolution</li>
<li>Mentor team members of all levels on application design and development</li>
<li>Monitor data warehousing system to ensure reliability and accuracy of information loaded into the databases</li>
<li>Resolve complex software issues across multiple software applications and platforms</li>
<li>Seek continuous improvement in performance of data warehouse load and consumption processes</li>
<li>Work cross functionally to implement data driven projects</li>
<li>Analyze and document source systems’ data domains and inter-relationships to enable rapid ingestion into warehousing environment and provision high quality and consumable data</li>
<li>Assist in the development of internal policies and procedures (standards, controls and metrics)</li>
<li>Build and maintain high performing ETL (Extract, Transform and Load) processes</li>
<li>Define Big Data implementation framework and lead implementation of advanced analytics capabilities</li>
<li>Effectively communicate and document the application architecture utilizing industry standards as part of a team</li>
<li>Ensure quality and controls are in place, managing escalations and developing and recommending solutions</li>
<li>Execute unit/string testing; may lead creation of development unit/string test plans; Solid understanding of QA testing plans</li>
<li>Implement / follow DevOps methodology and tool sets</li>
<li>In partnership with QA, ensure that existing and proposed software applications meet IT standards, as well as business and customer requirements</li>
</ul>
<p><br><strong>Qualifications and Experience:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>6+ years of Data <span class=" WJQY ">Warehouse experience</span>
</li>
<li>2+ years Technical Leadership experience</li>
<li>Ability to independently manage a delivery team and successfully execute large solutions, while maintaining communication with the business unit</li>
<li>Advanced skills in Project Management and SDLC processes</li>
<li>Experience in Agile development methodology and DevOps implementations is required</li>
<li>Experience in Data Analysis and knowledge of underlying subject areas in respective project domains</li>
<li>Expert knowledge of large-scale internal software applications or related technologies </li>
<li>MUST HAVE Big Data experience</li>
<li>Programming background and an ability to assist developers as needed, Python or Java preferred</li>
<li>Strong sense of teamwork and ability to both lead and execute programs</li>
<li>Ability to function as a strategic partner within a team</li>
<li>Bachelor’s degree in Information Technology, Computer Science, Systems Analysis or equivalent work experience</li>
</ul>
<p><br>NOTE: Successful candidate will be required to complete a pre-employment background check.</p>
<p>Want to learn more about Athene? Athene is driven to hire America’s veterans.</p>
<p>Athene is an Equal Opportunity Employer. We do not discriminate on the basis of race, color, religion, gender, gender identity, national origin, age, sexual orientation, physical or mental disability, pregnancy, marital status, veteran status, or any other status protected by federal, state, or local law.</p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
				<h4 id="contact-name">Stephanie Koogler</h4>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
					7700 Mills Civic Parkway
				
				
					
						West Des Moines, IA, 50266
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
