<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="COnGkqSo7dcCFRBgwQodViYHkQ" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Madison Heights, MI" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Analysis, CRM, Database, Data Warehouse, HTTP, Inquire, Management, Materials, Networks, Oracle, Programmer, Programming, Research, Scheduling, Scripts, SQL, Unix, Validation" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Senior Data Programmer / Data Quality - Oracle/ SQL" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Analysis, CRM, Database, Data Warehouse, HTTP, Inquire, Management, Materials, Networks, Oracle, Programmer, Programming, Research, Scheduling, Scripts, SQL, Unix, Validation
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><strong>Description </strong><br><br><br><br><h1>About the Opportunity </h1>
<br><br><br>The Senior Data Programmer is responsible for working with clients and BSA's to provide the highest quality products and services to our internal and external customers. Works on assignments that are complex in nature and where considerable judgment is required in resolving problems and making recommendations. The Sr. Data Programmer is responsible for new and existing data and data validation assignments that are complex in nature where considerable judgment and initiative are required in resolving problems and making recommendations.  <br><h1>Essential Functions </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>Generates adhoc reports and regular datasets or report information for end-users using system tools and database or data warehouse queries and scripts <br>
</li>
<li>Integrates data from multiple sources to produce requested or required data elements <br>
</li>
<li>Programs and maintains report forms and formats, information dashboards, data generators, canned reports, and other end-user information portals or resources <br>
</li>
<li>Receives and process input feeds <br>
</li>
<li>Verifies input data quality, including identification and communication of file variances and potential issues <br>
</li>
<li>Performs file transfers and performs backup procedures <br>
</li>
<li>Sends all outputs to appropriate location <br>
</li>
<li>Manages the quality and timeliness of updates and output deliverables <br>
</li>
<li>Ensures compliance with production standards and tests/Quality Controls the solution(s) <br>
</li>
<li>Develops specifications and use them to design/code a solution <br>
</li>
<li>Uses and fully understands established appropriate processes to meet customer requirements, and be able to customize if required <br>
</li>
<li>Verifies program execution is successful <br>
</li>
<li>Proactively identifies areas for improving processes and client service <br>
</li>
<li>Focus on meeting and exceeding client expectations <br>
</li>
<li>May create specifications for reports based on business requests <br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h1>Knowledge &amp; Skills </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>Strong written and oral communication and organizational skills <br>
</li>
<li>Ability to deliver presentations and updates to clients. Must be comfortable in a client facing environment. <br>
</li>
<li>Flexible and adaptable in regards to learning and understanding new technologies <br>
</li>
<li>Ability to conduct research into software-related issues and products <br>
</li>
<li>Highly self-motivated and directed <br>
</li>
<li>Proven analytical and problem solving abilities <br>
</li>
<li>Strong understanding of data structures, databases, data processing <br>
</li>
<li>Able to complete data merges <br>
</li>
<li>Able to complete quality control measures, to ensure data integrity <br>
</li>
<li>Strong scripting and programming skills <br>
</li>
<li>Able to advise less experienced peers <br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h1>Duties &amp; Responsibilities </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>
<br><br><br><br>Act as team resource for troubleshooting data related issues and problems  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Where answers are not immediately known, inquire with appropriate subject matter experts for the answer  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Mentor co-workers in business rules as well as the use of processing tools  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Assist in developing training materials and classes  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Organize, implement, audit, and improve workflows for existing and new clients  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Coordinate internally and externally in regards to scheduling and data issues, keeping management abreast of pertinent details  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Suggest areas for improvement to internal processes and carry out implementation where applicable  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Assist in meeting production schedules  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Create and run reports on data and audit content  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Create data transformation mappings  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Perform data converts, sorts, merge/purges and segmentations as per established standards, procedures and operational guidelines  <br><br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h1>Technical Requirements </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>
<br><br><br><br>Data reporting and analysis experience desired  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Experience with data integration process required  <br><br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h1>Preferred Qualifications </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>
<br><br><br><br>Familiarity with UNIX operating systems and direct mail processing a plus  <br><br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h1>Experience </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>
<br><br><br><br>Requires a minimum of 5 years of related experience  <br><br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h1>Education </h1>
<br><br><br><ul>
<br><li>
<br><br><br><br>High school or equivalent required  <br><br>
</li>
<li>
<br><br><br><br>Associate’s or Bachelor’s degree preferred  <br><br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><strong>Qualifications </strong><br><br><strong>Conditions of Employment </strong><br><br><br><p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">All job offers are contingent upon successful completion of certain background checks which unless prohibited by applicable law may include criminal history checks, employment verification, education verification, drug screens, credit checks, DMV checks (for driving positions only) and fingerprinting. <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">  <br><strong>Great People, Deserve Great Benefits </strong><br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">We know that we have some of the brightest and most talented associates in the world, and we believe in rewarding them accordingly.  If you work here, expect competitive pay, comprehensive health coverage, and endless opportunities to advance your career.  From tuition reimbursement to scholarship programs to employee stock purchase plans and 401(k)s, we offer associates a variety of benefits that work as hard for them as they work for us.  <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">  <br><strong>About Epsilon </strong><br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">Epsilon® is an all-encompassing global marketing innovator. We provide unrivaled data intelligence and customer insights, world-class technology including loyalty, email and CRM platforms and data-driven creative, activation and execution. Epsilon’s digital media arm, Conversant, is a leader in personalized digital advertising and insights through its proprietary technology and trove of consumer marketing data, delivering digital marketing with unprecedented scale, accuracy and reach through personalized media programs and through CJ Affiliate, one of the world’s largest affiliate marketing networks. Together, we bring personalized marketing to consumers across offline and online channels, at moments of interest, that help drive business growth for brands.  Recognized by Ad Age as the #1 World’s Largest CRM/Direct Marketing Network, #1 Largest U.S. Agency from All Disciplines and #1 Largest U.S. Mobile Marketing Agency, Epsilon employs over 8,000 associates in 70 offices worldwide. Epsilon is an Alliance Data company. For more information, visit  <a href="http://www.epsilon.com">www.epsilon.com </a><span style="cursor:pointer;" class="easyApplyTojob">Click here to Apply</span><br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">  <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">Alliance Data provides equal employment opportunities without regard to race, color, religion, gender, age, national origin, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, veteran status or any other characteristic protected by law. <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">  <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">Alliance Data participates in E-Verify <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">  <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px"><strong>For San Francisco Bay Area </strong>: <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">Alliance Data will consider for employment qualified applicants with criminal histories in a manner consistent with the requirements of San Francisco Police Code Sections 4901 - 4919, commonly referred to as the San Francisco Fair Chance Ordinance <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">  <br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px"><br><br><br></p>
<p style="MARGIN-BOTTOM: 0px; MARGIN-TOP: 0px">#LI-AN1
		</p>
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
