<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body>
<input value="Austin, TX" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Data Governance Technical Analyst" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			Description:<br><br><span style="color:#00a0df; font-family:arial; font-size:10pt"><strong>We believe that</strong>, when done right, investing liberates people to create their own destiny. <strong>We are driven</strong> by our purpose to champion every client’s goals with passion and integrity. <strong>We respect</strong> and appreciate the diversity of our employees, our clients, and the communities we serve. <strong>We challenge</strong> conventions strategically to create value for our clients, our firm and the world. We live and bring to life the concept of ‘own your tomorrow’ every day. <strong>We champion</strong> our employee strengths, guide their development, and invest in their long-term success. <strong>We hire</strong> optimistic, results-oriented, curious, innovative, and adaptable people with the desire to help our clients and one another succeed.</span><br><br><br><span style="font-family:arial; font-size:10pt"><span style="color:#425563">As a company, we were established by</span> <span style="color:blue; font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt; mso-ansi-language:EN-US; mso-bidi-language:AR-SA; mso-fareast-font-family:Calibri; mso-fareast-language:EN-US"><a href="http://www.aboutschwab.com/about/leadership/charles_schwab">Chuck</a> </span><span style="color:#425563">over 40 years ago to champion Main Street over Wall Street, and to help Americans transform themselves from earners to owners. Through advocacy and innovation, we work to make investing more affordable, accessible and understandable for all. As we enter our fifth decade, we are looking for talented, innovative and driven people who believe they can help themselves, and our clients, create a better future.</span></span><br><br><br><strong><span style="color:#005f83; font-family:arial; font-size:10pt">Our Opportunity:</span></strong><br><br><br><span style="color:#425563">The Data Governance Technical Analyst will work directly with Schwab's technical SMEs to operationalize and maintain data governance goals in Schwab’s suite of data governance tools.</span><br><br><br><span style="color:#425563">Specific responsibilities include:</span><br><br><ul>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Training of data stewards on data governance tools capabilities, policies, and standards</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Specifying data steward requirements for integration among data governance tools</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Partnering with data stewards for required data remediation tool planning, coordination</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Coordinate with data stewards to capture technical metadata and lineage</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Evaluating and enforcing compliance of IT processes within data governance tool policies and standards</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Metadata import job specification and testing Specification and creation of data governance reporting/KPIs for data stewards</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Coordination with Data Governance Tools Engineers to ensure successful job completion and proper reporting execution</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Data profiling specification and analysis</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Codification, testing, and change management of data quality rules</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Supporting implementation of upgrades and future developments of data governance tool suites</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Additionally, the Data Governance Technical Analyst will often be called upon to help champion Schwab data governance policies, standards, and best practices across the STS organization.IPT QA is looking for a Senior Software QA Engineer having substantial hands-on experience in Software Automation. The individual should be extremely conversant with automation testing, having advanced knowledge working in a Java,  .NET and/or C# environment while being open to working in evolving Next Gen technologies.</span></li>
<br>
</ul>
<br><br><br><span style="font-size:10pt"><strong><span style="color:#005f83; font-family:arial; font-size:10pt">What you’ll do:</span></strong></span><br><br><br><span style="color:#425563"><strong>Typical responsibilities will include:</strong></span><br><br><ul>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Participation in local data governance reviews, meetings, and working sessions</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Interaction with SMEs across business units and corporate functions</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Development of presentations, demonstrations, training, and other materials for championing and educating the company on data governance, data management, and Schwab’s data policies and standards</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Participation with Global Data Office and STS technical leadership to continuously improve data governance policies and standards</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Drive continuous improvement and development of best practices for the IDG organization </span></li>
<br>
</ul>
<br><br><br><strong><span style="color:#005f83; font-family:arial; font-size:10pt">What you have:</span></strong><br><br><br><span style="color:#425563"><strong>Required skills</strong></span><br><br><ul>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Bachelor’s Degree in Business, Finance, Information Technology or a related field.</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">5+ years of data-centric IT work</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Experience in data modeling, database administration, ETL, database/date warehouse design &amp; architecture, and/or data system business requirements analysis</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Experience in the financial services industry a plus</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Experience working in a regulatory, risk and compliance environment and supporting associated projects preferred 5 or more years of data governance, or related experience, with one (1) or more years of recent experience assisting in development of a data governance program</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Experience with data governance tools including technical and business metadata, data quality, data profiling, and data lineage, etc.</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Good understanding of data warehousing and associated concepts (OLAP, ETL, Dimensions, Facts, etc.)</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Ability to think and communicate in both a business and technology context</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Project management skills including the ability to effectively juggle multiple, simultaneous work streams with different timelines and demands</span></li>
<br>
</ul>
<br><br><br><span style="color:#425563"><strong>Preferred Skills:</strong></span><br><br><ul>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Masters preferred</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Must understand the importance and benefits of good data quality, and be able to champion results across functions</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Ability to understand, translate and communicate abstract concepts/ideas in a clear, concise, and easy to understand communication style</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Must demonstrate analytical, problem solving and research skills that allow working with problems that are complex and often unique</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Strong interpersonal, influencing, prioritization, decision- making and conflict resolution skills   </span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Experience with one or more programming or scripting languages is a plus</span></li>
<br>
</ul>
<br><br><br><strong><span style="color:#005f83; font-family:arial; font-size:10pt">What you’ll get:</span></strong><br><br><ul>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Comprehensive Compensation and Benefits package</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Financial Health: 401k Match, Employee Stock Purchase Plan, Employee Discounts, Personalized advice, Brokerage discounts</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Work/Life Balance: Sabbatical, Paid Parental Leave, New Mothers returning to work Program, Tuition Reimbursement Programs, Time off to volunteer, Employee Matching Gifts Program</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Everyday Wellness: Health and Lifestyle Wellness Rewards, Onsite Fitness Classes, Healthy Food Choices, Wellness Champions</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Inclusion: Employee Resource Groups, Commitment to diversity, Strategic partnerships</span></li>
<br><li><span style="color:#425563">Not just a job, but a career, with an opportunity to do the best work of your life</span></li>
<br>
</ul>
<br><br><br><span style="font-family:arial; font-size:10pt"><span style="color:#425563">Learn more about</span> <a href="http://www.aboutschwab.com/careers/life_at_schwab/" target="_blank">Life@Schwab</a>.</span><br><br><br><br><span style="font-family:arial; font-size:10pt"><span style="color:#425563">Charles Schwab &amp; Co., Inc. is an equal opportunity and affirmative action employer committed to diversifying its workforce. It is Schwab's policy to provide equal employment opportunities to all employees and applicants without regard to race, color, religion, sex (including pregnancy, childbirth, breastfeeding, or related medical conditions), gender identity or expression, national origin, ancestry, age, disability, legally protected medical condition, genetic information, marital status, sexual orientation, protected veteran status, military status, citizenship status or any other status that is protected by law.</span> </span><br><br><br>Job Specifications<br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><table><tbody>
<tr>
<td>Relocation Offered?:</td>			<td>No</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Work Schedule:</td>			<td>Days</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Languages:</td>			<td>English - spoken</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Current Licenses / Certifications:</td>			<td>None</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Relevant Work Experience:</td>			<td>Analyst/Strategy-2-5 yrs, Business Development and Sales-less than 2 yrs, Capital Markets-2-5 yrs, Investment Management - less than 2 yrs, Financial Services-less than 2 yrs, Brokerage Operations-less than 2yrs, Regulatory, Risk Analysis, IT-Change Management/Release Management-less than 2 yrs, IT-Software Quality Assurance (QA)-less than 2 yrs, Compliance</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Position Located In:</td>			<td>TX - Austin</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Education:</td>			<td>BA/BS</td>		</tr>
<tr>
<td>Job Type:</td>			<td>Full Time</td>		</tr>
</tbody></table>
<br><br><br>Category:Information Technology<br><br>Activation Date: Thursday, August 17, 2017<br><br>Expiration Date: Tuesday, January 2, 2018<br><br><a href="viewjob.html?erjob=307815">Apply Here</a> <img src="https://www.applytracking.com/track.aspx/iFKEg">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->

			<br><hr>
<div class="row">
					<div class="col-md-12">
						<h1 class="jobdesc">Company Information</h1>
						<div class="highlight-black mTB20">
							The Charles Schwab Corporation (NYSE: SCHW) has been a leader in financial services for more than three decades. Through advocacy and innovation, the company has worked to make investing more affordable, more accessible and more understandable to all. Today, Schwab meets the needs of individual and institutional clients through two operating segments: Investor Services helps individuals with brokerage, banking, insurance and other financial services. Clients have easy access online, by phone or at a local Schwab branch. Institutional Services provides dedicated support for independent investment advisors, employers and third-party benefit plan administrators. More information is available at www.schwab.com and www.aboutschwab.com. Who We Hire: Schwab hires people at all levels of experience who have the desire, drive and creativity to help our clients be financially fit. We actively recruit for a variety of roles, including financial consultants, registered brokers and trainees, client service specialists and portfolio consultants. In addition, we offer challenging careers in technology, sales, marketing and other areas of business support.
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				<div class="row">
					
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<img class="company-media" src="//assets.dice.com/techpro/companies/brandMax/CharlesSchwab/rectangle-400.jpg">
</div>
					
				</div>
</body></html>
