<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body>
<input value="Princeton, NJ" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Apache, Browser, Developer, Development, DNS, HTTP, JavaScript, Jenkins, Linux, Programming, Protocol, Python, TCP/IP, Testing, Unix, Web Design" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Senior Web Engineer - Data Technologies" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Apache, Browser, Developer, Development, DNS, HTTP, JavaScript, Jenkins, Linux, Programming, Protocol, Python, TCP/IP, Testing, Unix, Web Design
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><b>Job Requisition Number: </b>57790 <br><br><h3 id="the-role">The Role: </h3>
<br><br><br>The Data Technologies Engineering department is responsible for building websites, web components and other systems to help fuel the global financial markets by giving traders the information they need to make pertinent decisions. Join our team on the Princeton, NJ campus and together we'll build Web products that will be used by the world's biggest financial firms and data scientists. <br><br><br><h3 id="we-ll-trust-you-to">We'll trust you to: </h3>
<br><br><br><ul>
<li> Manage all aspects of your projects, from working directly with product managers to designing and building user interfaces and data visualizations <br>
</li>
<li> Work on deep engineering issues in building and deploying a secure and scalable Web platform for financial information delivery <br>
</li>
<li> Develop rich interactive and responsive applications using the latest browser-based client technologies <br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h3 id="you-ll-need-to-have">You'll need to have: </h3>
<br><br><br><ul>
<li> A Bachelor's or Master's Degree in Computer Science or Engineering or equivalent background <br>
</li>
<li> Expertise in full stack Web development including client- and server-side JavaScript <br>
</li>
<li> 4+ years of professional software development experience, with an emphasis on Web applications <br>
</li>
<li> Proficiency in Node.js and Angular.js (or other related client-side JS frameworks), with an emphasis on structuring a large Web application using patterns like MVC/MVVM <br>
</li>
<li> The desire to keep up with the latest and evolving Web technologies like responsive Web design, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Node.js, JS frameworks <br>
</li>
<li> Passion for performance, monitoring, analytics, debugging, testing, deploying, and building large cross-browser Web applications <br>
</li>
<li> Effective communication skills with the ability to speak to both technical and business counterparts <br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><h3 id="we-d-love-to-see">We'd love to see: </h3>
<br><br><br><ul>
<li> Exposure to Apache, HAProxy, DNS, TCP/IP, CDN, Proxy servers, and HTTP protocol <br>
</li>
<li> Experience with Python and C/C++ <br>
</li>
<li> Knowledge of build/test frameworks such as Gulp/Grunt, Less/Sass, Jenkins, and Mocha <br>
</li>
<li> Experience with writing services that use HTTP interfaces to send requests/responses to Node.js <br>
</li>
<li> An understanding of Linux programming, scripting, debugging, and performance tools on UNiX/Linux, Shell, awk <br>
</li>
<li> Experience with WebSockets in real-time applications <br>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><b>Date: </b> Tue, 28 03 2017 00:00:00 GMT <br><b>Department: </b> Software Developer/Engineering
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->

			<br><hr>
<div class="row">
					<div class="col-md-12">
						<h1 class="jobdesc">Company Information</h1>
						<div class="highlight-black mTB20">
							Bloomberg is a company dedicated to helping solve complex challenges through insight and information. Our strength quickly and accurately delivering data, news and analytics through technology is at the core of everything we do. With over 19,000 employees in 192 locations, we give influential decision makers in business, finance and government a competitive edge by connecting them to a dynamic network of news, people and ideas. To do so, we need constant energy and innovation which is where you come in. At Bloomberg, you will have the opportunity to take risks and be part of an organization that is entering new markets, launching new ventures and pushing the boundaries. Our ever-expanding technology, data, news and media services afford employees the opportunity to expand skills and connect with smart, driven colleagues from a diversity of backgrounds and ideas. We're looking for dynamic, multi-talented people who have a desire to thrive in a forward-thinking culture and a business with global impact. Are you ready to make your mark? Learn more about our businesses and opportunities at bloomberg.com/careers.
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				<div class="row">
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<iframe class="company-media" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/2sINAO5mAqY?list=PLnZuxOufsXnubhqUe0Ev1rQnw5jUAnQsG" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>
						</div>
					
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<img class="company-media" src="//assets.dice.com/techpro/companies/brandMax/Bloomberg/rectangle-401.jpg">
</div>
					
				</div>
</body></html>
