<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body>
<input value="Englewood, CO" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Analysis, Analyst, BI Tools, Ecommerce, Management, MySQL, mysql, Oracle, Project, SQL, Supply Chain" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Sr. Data Analyst" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Analysis, Analyst, BI Tools, Ecommerce, Management, MySQL, mysql, Oracle, Project, SQL, Supply Chain
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time, Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><b>Position: </b><br><b>Sr. Data Analyst </b><br><br><b>Job Description: </b><br><br><br>* <br><br><br>Principal Accountabilities <br><br>Management of data management process to support commercial and technical product data management activities and systems. <br><br><br>* <br><br><br>Support creation of data management and business processes and to support commercial and technical product data related activities and systems. <br><br><br>Job Complexity <br><br>- Requires in-depth knowledge and good understanding of SQL and Data Integration methodologies <br><br><br>- Ability to work in a high performance and results driven startup environment <br><br><br>- Ability to work and translate cross functional requirements with cross functional teams - both technical and business <br><br>- Ability to solve complex problems; able to provide a new perspective using existing solutions <br><br>- Able to work independently with minimal guidance <br><br>- Acts as a resource and point of contact for business/technical stakeholders and colleagues with less experience <br><br>- Uses best practices and knowledge of internal or external business issues to improve products/services or processes <br><br>- Typically resolves complex problems or problems where precedent may not exist <br><br>- Often sets the guidance of the work of project teams; may formally train junior staff <br><br><br>Experience / Education <br><br>Typically requires a minimum of 8 years of related experience with a 4 year degree; or 6 years and an advanced degree; or equivalent professional experience <br><br><br>Desired Skills <br><br><br>SQL (T-SQL/Oracle/MySQL) <br><br><br>Knowledge on Data Integration and BI tools highly desired <br><br>Good understanding on analytics and reporting tool and methodologies <br><br><br>Job Description <br><br><br>Establish processes and procedures for effect management of critical data management activities with supply chain and product data providers (third parties, internal) <br><br><br>Resolve data anomalies and establish corrective action to prevent reoccurrence <br><br><br>Support business analysis for new systems implementations related to or impacting product data <br><br><br>Establish, monitor and report on data processing KPIs to ensure SLAs are met across all information flows related to product data <br><br><br>Establish governance and standards working with ecommerce product owners to support the performance of the commerce channels <br><br><br>#DICE# <br><br><br>* <br><br><b>Location: </b><br><b>360 Inverness </b><br><br><b>Time Type: </b><br><b>Full time </b>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->

			<br><hr>
<div class="row">
					<div class="col-md-12">
						<h1 class="jobdesc">Company Information</h1>
						<div class="highlight-black mTB20">
							The tension between possibility and practicality is what we resolve. At Arrow, we’ve come full circle— from being a parts supplier at the physical heart of the radio business to being a global partner in the ongoing transformation of the most complex and exciting business on the planet. We are visionaries. Innovators. Mentors. In order to thrive and survive in today’s marketplace, we anticipate what will come tomorrow for our forward-thinking partners. Arrow serves as a supply channel partner for over 100,000 original equipment manufacturers, contract manufacturers and commercial customers through a global network of more than 460 locations in 56 countries.
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				<div class="row">
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<iframe class="company-media" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/yueP7V6Wddc" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>
						</div>
					
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<img class="company-media" src="//assets.dice.com/techpro/companies/brandMax/ArrowElectronics/rectangle-400.jpg">
</div>
					
				</div>
</body></html>
