<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CO6IhOen7dcCFZBjwQodgX0BSQ" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="New York, NY" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="SAP HR, HCM, DATA Conversion" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="SAP HR/HCM Data Conversion Analyst" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				SAP HR, HCM, DATA Conversion
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time, FULLTIME</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
				
					
					
						<span class="mL20">Competitive</span>
						<span itemprop="baseSalary" style="display:none"></span>
					
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
					<span>Travel required to 25%.</span>
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><br><br>Job Posting Title<br><br>SAP HR/HCM Data Conversion Analyst <br><br>Company<br><br>Doctors Without Borders/Médecins Sans Frontières (MSF) is an international humanitarian organization that provides medical care to people affected by conflict, epidemics, disasters, or exclusion from health care in over 70 countries.<br><br>We welcome candidates who bring a wide variety of backgrounds and experiences to join us in working toward MSF’s common mission.<br><br>Department<br><br>Symphony is an HR project aiming to optimize HR processes through the MSF movement and to roll-out common HR management software to all MSF sections. <br>Symphony was launched aiming to provide a better HR response to the movement’s operational needs through: <br>• Improving HR effectiveness: by facilitating effectiveness of MSF HR teams and so enhancing our HR response capacity to present and future operational needs. <br>• Integration of data: what smooths the efficiency of administrative processes, allowing us take the maximum benefit of our resources. Thus, focus on the value-added activities by avoiding duplication and improving accuracy.<br>• Improving efficiency in resource usage and allocation: enabling us to exploit information better and make better and faster decisions. <br>• Improving quality of matching: raising the level of services to our operations and to our mobile staff. “The right people, at the right time, in the right place!”<br><br>Project<br><br>Inside the MSF International Office, the Data Conversion Analyst is a member of the Symphony Program Team and will report directly to the Data Migration Manager. He/she will be responsible for all data conversion aspects of the assigned sections within the project.<br><br>As a member of the Symphony team, the Data Conversion Analyst will focus on supporting the delivery of the data migration from the existing Legacy systems to SAP HCM and e-Rec. The Data Conversion Analyst will help MSF by analyzing the local data landscape, identifying the needed data and supporting the local migration process.<br><br>Data conversion: support the global template and global / local info types design. <br>Define the needed procedure to migrate data, follow the defined Generate-Aggregate-Build process for data mapping and ensure the high standard of the information provided by sections. Support the data cleansing process and constantly look for possible improvements. <br>Define the migration timeline with local resources and the agreed project deadlines. Work closely with the Data manager and proactively inform on possible risks and solutions.<br><br>People Management: Able to deal with a homogeneous group of local IT and HR offices with very different service structures. Build strong relationship with local team and be a recognized as a trusted and knowledgeable resource within the organization; be a champion for data conversion in the Symphony team.<br><br>Tasks<br><br>• Manage a data migration effort and workstream the processes <br>• Accountable for MSF data migration deliverables on projects <br>• Agree data migration scope, and define local data migration approach <br>• Understand and simplify complex HR business data and conversion rules <br>• Problem solve errors in databases and migration tool <br>• Create large import/export functionality between different systems <br>• Responsible for the data migration delivery through the entire project lifecycle and for the end-to-end migration process (cleanse, extract, transform, load, reconcile)<br><br>Requirements<br><br>Qualifications and Work Experience<br><br>• 2+ years SAP HR experience and data management with at least 1 full cycle implementation in a multinational project <br>• Flexibility and willingness to travel up to 25% of the time <br>• Proven knowledge of Data Privacy regulations, i.e. Privacy Shield and GDPR <br>• Data protection best practices, training and certifications in data audit (SSAE 16-18, ISAE 3402, ISO 27001) are a strong plus <br>• Proven expertise in SAP data migration via LSMW or similar methods <br>• Work autonomously and able to meet deadlines<br><br>Technical and Personal Requirements<br><br>• Genuine interest in, understanding of and commitment to the humanitarian principles, social mission, operations, and challenges of MSF <br>• Knowledge of SAP HR modules data models PA, OM and e-Rec <br>• Data cleansing tools and procedures knowledge <br>• Technical writing and documentation skills <br>• Strong Excel and data transformation rules <br>• Data conversion via database exposure is a strong plus <br>• Experience of working with third party Systems Integrators <br>• Experience of large IT and HR change programs <br>• Working in a diverse and multicultural environment <br>• Presentation and listening skills<br><br>Type<br>HQ<br><br>Contract Type<br><br>Fixed Termed Contract <br><br>Additional Information <br>Starting salary low to high 70’s (commensurate with experience).<br><br>Desired Hiring Date <br>December 12, 2017<br><br>Working Time % <br>100%<br><br>How to Apply <br>Please visit our CAREER PORTAL to apply for the US Advocacy Advisor position. Submissions without cover letter will not be reviewed.<br><br>Application Deadline: November 22, 2017<br><br>If you encounter any technical problems or issues throughout the application process,<span style="cursor:pointer;" class="easyApplyTojob">Click here to Apply</span>
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
				
					
						New York, NY, 10001
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
