<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CPGtm9Om7dcCFRUHgQodDTYLYA" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Washington, DC" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="API, Architecture, BI Tools, Browser, Business Intelligence, Data Architecture, Database, Data Warehouse, Development, Genetic, Java, Management, NoSQL, Security, SQL, UML, Validation" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Enterprise Data Architect" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				API, Architecture, BI Tools, Browser, Business Intelligence, Data Architecture, Database, Data Warehouse, Development, Genetic, Java, Management, NoSQL, Security, SQL, UML, Validation
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br>Data is a critical asset to the AAMC. The Enterprise Data Architect is a thought leader sitting in the Enterprise Architecture organization partnering with both business and IT stakeholders to define and execute an enterprise data strategy and architecture that supports the organization-s business strategy. The AAMC is transforming its applications and data layers to better control the acquisition, validation, quality and distribution of data across AAMC-s many mission critical applications, data warehouses, and external partners. The Enterprise Data Architect will set the overall vision, strategy and data architecture for AAMC then direct future initiatives that build components of architecture ensuring convergence towards the defined future state. This leadership role will also set the direction for technology including tools for data acquisition, reporting, analytics, data discovery, and visualization. <br><br><b>Responsibilities </b><br><br><br>* Develop, maintain and evangelize data architecture guiding principles, policies, best practices, reference architecture and standards <br><br>* Define and maintain target data architectures and master data management strategies in alignment with business and technology objectives <br><br>* Leader of data transformation efforts from legacy to new and alternative technologies <br><br>* Provide thought leadership for IT-s data security, data integration, data services and API efforts <br><br>* Collaborate with various Business, Operations, Applications and Data and Analytics groups to define, establish and run a process that ensures adherence to enterprise data standards and architecture principles <br><br>* Advocate for, and champion, efforts to close gaps between as-is and to-be architectures <br><br>* Monitor compliance of development work against established standards and principles and work to resolve issues through appropriate formal and informal channels <br><br>* Work closely with other architects and IT managers and developers so that they understand and support data architecture priorities <br><br>* Review and analyze existing systems and make recommendations for improvements <br><br>* Maintain governance over AAMC-s Enterprise Data Model <br><br>* Play a lead role in selecting and implementing technologies supporting MDM, data discovery, data quality, analytics and BI tools, and champion related process changes <br><br>* Provide general guidance to teams on data architecture topics <br><br>* Represent data architecture concerns in design, implementation and deployment reviews <br><br>* Analyze proposed business solutions to understand and document data requirements and partner with solution architects to define required data architecture elements <br><br><b>Requirements </b><br><br><br>* Bachelor-s degree in Information Technology, Computer Science, Data Management or related filed with an emphasis on data and databases required but a Master-s preferred. Equivalent extensive relevant work experience will be considered <br><br>* 8+ years of experience required <br><br>* Advanced knowledge of applying TOGAF methodology (or similar EA framework) to the document data architecture <br><br>* Strong working knowledge of application development processes <br><br>* Advanced knowledge of data management, data integration and database development technologies and processes <br><br>* Advanced knowledge of cloud-based data strategies, NoSQL, SQL, Data Warehouse, ETL, Business Intelligence and Analytics tools <br><br>* Java knowledge, Data science/machine learning a plus <br><br>* Ability to translate complex technical terminology, concepts and issues in terms understandable to technical and non-technical management and staff <br><br>* Strong interpersonal skills to resolve problems in a professional manner, lead working groups, negotiate and create consensus <br><br>* Advanced database development skills and experience required <br><br>* Intermediate knowledge of UML and object-oriented design required <br><br>* Excellent oral and written communication skills required <br><br><br>If a bachelor-s degree is required, related work experience may be substituted in some positions. One year of college course work at an accredited institution is equivalent to one year of related work experience. <br><br><br>The Association of American Medical Colleges (AAMC) is an Equal Opportunity/Affirmative-- Action Employer. The AAMC is committed to the policy of an equal employment opportunity in recruitment, hiring, career advancement, and all other personnel practices. The AAMC will not discriminate on the basis of race, color, sex, national origin, religion, age, marital status, personal appearance, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, family responsibilities, matriculation, political affiliation, genetic information, disability, past or current military service, or any other legally protected characteristic. <br><br><br>Please attach a resume as part of the application process. It is important that files DO NOT include periods ( . ) within the file name. <br><br><br>BROWSER REQUIREMENTS: Applications must be submitted using Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Safari, or Internet Explorer v.10 or higher.
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
