<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body>
<input value="Bloomington, IL" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Algorithms, Analysis, Data Analysis, Database, Data Collection, Development, Hadoop, Hub, Java, Management, Modeling, Programming, Project, Python, Research, SAS, Scientific, SQL, Validation" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Data Scientist" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Algorithms, Analysis, Data Analysis, Database, Data Collection, Development, Hadoop, Hub, Java, Management, Modeling, Programming, Project, Python, Research, SAS, Scientific, SQL, Validation
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time, Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br><div class="cs-atscs-jobdet-rtpane">
<br><br><b>Requisition ID: </b><br><br> req1913  <br><br><b>Job Title: </b><br><br>Data Scientist  <br><br><b>Number of Openings: </b><br><br>3  <br><br><b>Job Category: </b><br><br>Professional/Technical  <br><br><b>Employment Type: </b><br><br>Regular Full-Time  <br><br><b>Shift: </b><br><br>First  <br><br><b>Weekends: </b><br><br>Not Required  <br><br><b>Location: </b><br><br>Bloomington, IL  <br><br><b>Duties and Responsibilities: </b><br><br><ul>
<li>Performs improved visual representation of data to allow clearer communication, viewer engagement and faster/better decision-making </li>
<li>Investigates, recommends, and initiates acquisition of new data resources from internal and external sources </li>
<li>Works with IT teams to support data collection, integration, and retention requirements based on business need </li>
<li>Identifies critical and emerging technologies that will support and extend quantitative analytic capabilities </li>
<li>Manages work efforts which require the use of sophisticated project planning techniques </li>
<li>Applies a wide application of complex principles, theories and concepts in a specific field to provide solutions to a wide range of difficult problems </li>
<li>Develops and maintains an effective network of both scientific and business contacts/knowledge obtaining relevant information and intelligence around the market and emergent opportunities </li>
<li>Contributes data to State Farm's internal and external publications, write articles for leading journals and participate in academic and industry conferences </li>
</ul>
<br><ul>
<li>Collaborates with business subject matter experts to select relevant sources of information </li>
<li>Develop breadth of knowledge in programming (R, Python), Descriptive, Inferential, and Experimental Design statistics, advanced mathematics, and database functionality (SQL, Hadoop) </li>
<li>Develop expertise with multiple machine learning algorithms and data science techniques, such as exploratory data analysis, generative and discriminative predictive modeling, graph theory, recommender systems, text analytics, computer vision, deep learning, optimization and validation </li>
<li>Develop expertise with State Farm datasets, data repositories, and data movement processes </li>
<li>Assists on projects/requests and may lead specific tasks within the project scope </li>
<li>Prepares and manipulates data for use in development of statistical models </li>
<li>Develops fundamental understanding of insurance and financial services operations and uses this knowledge in decision making </li>
</ul>
<br><br><br><br><b>Additional Details: </b><br><br>For over 95 years, data has been key to State Farm. As a Data Scientist, you will work across the organization to solve business problems and help achieve business strategies. Using analytical rigor &amp; statistical methods, you will mine huge dataset to identify opportunities for our company. Implementing solutions is critical for success. You will do problem identification, solution proposal &amp; presentation to a wide variety of management &amp; technical audiences. This challenging career requires you to work on multiple concurrent projects in a community setting, developing yourself and others, and advancing data science both at State Farm and externally. Our data science team employs sophisticated, statistical approaches and state of the art technology. As a member of our team, you will help build and refine our tools/techniques and engage w/internal stakeholders across the organization to improve our products &amp; services <br><br><br>**Note: In addition to Bloomington, these positions may be placed in our Atlanta or Phoenix Hub locations.  <br><br><br>Skills &amp; Professional Experience: <br><br><br>*Develop hypotheses, design experiments, and test feasibility of proposed actions to determine probably outcomes using a variety of tools &amp; technologies <br><br>*Masters, other advanced degrees, or five years’ experience in an analytical field such as data science quantitative marketing, statistics, operations research, management science, industrial engineering, economics, etc. or equivalent practical experience preferred. <br><br>*Experience with SQL, Python, R, Java, SAS or MapReduce, SPARK <br><br>*Experience with unstructured data sets: text analytics, image recognition etc.  <br><br>*Experience working w/numerous large data sets/data warehouses &amp; ability to pull from such data sets using relevant programs &amp; coding including files, RDBMS &amp; Hadoop based storage systems <br><br>*Knowledge in machine learning methods including at least one of the following: Time series analysis, Hierarchical Bayes; or Learning techniques such as Decision Trees, Boosting, Random Forests. <br><br>*Excellent communication skills &amp; the ability to manage multiple &amp; diverse stakeholders across businesses &amp; leadership levels. <br><br>*Exercises sound judgment to diagnose &amp; resolve problems within area of expertise <br><br><br>Competencies desired: <br><br>Critical Thinking <br><br>Leadership <br><br>Initiative <br><br>Resourcefulness <br><br>Relationship Building  <br><br><br>This position will have a 12-mo incumbency period for lateral move &amp; 6-mo incumbency period for a promotional opportunity (beginning on effective date of the position) which must be met before posting. <br><br><br>This opening will consider job grades(s): RD2, RD3, and RD4.    </div>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
					One State Farm Plaza
				
				
					
						Bloomington, IL, 61791
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
					<a data-original-title="Phone: (888) 559-1922" id="contactTT" class="dice-btn-link" data-toggle="tooltip" data-placement="top" title="">Contact</a>
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->

			<br><hr>
<div class="row">
					<div class="col-md-12">
						<h1 class="jobdesc">Company Information</h1>
						<div class="highlight-black mTB20">
							With more than 65,000 employees and 18,000 agents serving more than 80 million policies and accounts, State Farm is proud to rely on the expertise of one of the nation’s largest IT teams. IT employees at State Farm benefit from size, security and the innovative spirit of an industry leader. With opportunities to work in select markets across the country, now’s the time to take your job to a better state and work for a company that values all you have to offer.
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				<div class="row">
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<iframe class="company-media" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/QRWDyu8boBQ?list=PLZdmq0GV_dGB2ripdKUILK88uWySk8xOf" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>
						</div>
					
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<img class="company-media" src="//assets.dice.com/techpro/companies/brandMax/StateFarm/rectangle-400.jpg">
</div>
					
				</div>
</body></html>
