<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CIWnhtSc7dcCFdMegQodS9gLQg" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Ann Arbor, MI" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="ETL, SQL Server, SSIS, T-SQL, queries, stored procedures, triggers, data modeling, data integration, functions, data relationships, data systems" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Data Integration Engineer" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				ETL, SQL Server, SSIS, T-SQL, queries, stored procedures, triggers, data modeling, data integration, functions, data relationships, data systems
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
				
					
					
						<span class="mL20">80 to 90K</span>
						<span itemprop="baseSalary" style="display:none"></span>
					
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<p>Data Integration Engineer Job Responsibilities:</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Supports data warehouse performance by planning and delivering data integration code</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Data Integration Engineer Job Duties:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Enhances data integration team accomplishments and competence by planning delivery of solutions;</p></li>
<li><p>Studies data sources by interviewing users; defining, analyzing, and validating data objects; identifying the relationship among data objects.</p></li>
<li><p>Plans data integration process by developing common definitions of sourced data; designing common keys in physical data structures; establishing data integration specifications; examining data applications; examining data models and data warehouse schema; determining best-fit data interchange methods; assessing middleware tools for data integration, transformation, and routing; developing project scope and specifications; identifying factors that negatively impact integration; establishing delivery timetables.</p></li>
<li><p>Delivers data integration by implementing shared databases; integrating data across environments; developing system modification specifications; mapping data; establishing interfaces; developing and modifying functions, programs, routines, and stored procedures to export, transform, and load data; meeting performance parameters; resolving and escalating integration issues; coordinating actions among users, operations staff, and outside vendors; recommending adjustments as objectives change; documenting operational procedures and data connections.</p></li>
<li><p>Validates data integration by developing and executing test plans and scenarios including data design, tool design, data extract/transform, networks, and hardware.</p></li>
<li><p>Maintains data warehouse performance by identifying and resolving data conflicts; upgrading data definitions;</p></li>
<li><p>Improves data integration by designing and evaluating new data interchange formats; improving physical design; rewriting data policy, standards, and procedures;</p></li>
<li><p>Maintains team accomplishments by communicating essential information; coordinating actions; obtaining expert input; reviewing open issues and action items; contributing information to team meetings and reports; transferring knowledge of data integration process, techniques, and issues to application and support teams.</p></li>
<li><p>Updates job knowledge by tracking ETL strategies and technologies; participating in educational opportunities; reading professional publications; maintaining personal networks; participating in professional organizations.</p></li>
<li><p>Accomplishes organization goals by accepting ownership for accomplishing new and different requests; exploring opportunities to add value to job accomplishments.</p></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Position Requirements</p>
<ul>
<li><p>A bachelor’s degree in information systems, computer science, mathematics, engineering or other related field</p></li>
<li><p>1 – 3 years’ experience in a data integration/ETL environment using SSIS, T-SQL or other ETL software</p></li>
<li><p>Strong SQL/T-SQL skills, including the ability to write queries, stored procedures, triggers, functions and etc.</p></li>
<li><p>Solid understanding of data systems, including data relationships and data modeling with the ability to learn and understand various data environments</p></li>
<li><p>Excellent analytical and problem solving skills</p></li>
<li><p>Effective written and oral communications skills in English</p></li>
<li><p>Ability to work with geographically dispersed teams</p></li>
<li><p>Sound planning and organizational skills with a strong attention to detail</p></li>
<li><p>Demonstrated ability to handle multiple concurrent projects and priorities in a fast-paced, evolving environment</p></li>
<li><p>Work independently and with others; self-directed and results-oriented</p></li>
<li><p>Excellent interpersonal skills</p></li>
<li><p>Willingness to learn new technologies to best solve data-related issues</p></li>
<li><p>MS SQL-Server experience preferred</p></li>
</ul>
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
	
	
		
			
				
					
						<button type="button" id="applybtn-2" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" onclick="signModule();">Apply Now</button>
					
					
				
			
			
		
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
				<h4 id="contact-name">Wendy Golla</h4>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
					38705 Seven Mile Road
				
				
					
						Livonia, MI, 48152
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
					<a data-original-title="Phone: 2485677338" id="contactTT" class="dice-btn-link" data-toggle="tooltip" data-placement="top" title="">Contact</a>
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
