<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CKfLrLO87tcCFYMUgQod2v8LUw" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Cleveland, WI" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Leadership, Collaboration, Business intelligence, Project management, Implementation management" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="WILM Chief Data Officer" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Leadership, Collaboration, Business intelligence, Project management, Implementation management
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
				
					
					
						<span class="mL20">$83,833 - $107,478</span>
						<span itemprop="baseSalary" style="display:none"></span>
					
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
					<span>Travel required to 10%.</span>
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<p>Job Title: WILM Chief Data Officer</p>
<p> </p>Employment  Classification: Management Group (Exempt Position) ~ $83,833 -  $107,478<p> </p>(Note: Salary will commensurate based on education and  related occupational experience.)<p> </p>Reports To: WILM Operations  Board<p> </p>Location: Lakeshore Technical College   Cleveland Campus<p></p> <p>Employment and Work Schedule: 52-week management  contract</p>
<p> </p>Flexible day/evening hours based upon needs of the college<p></p> <p>Purpose</p>
<p> </p>Serve as the lead in assuring shared information  services are provided to a three college consortium including  Wisconsin Indianhead, Lakeshore, and Mid-State Technical College.  Develop and implement Business Intelligence (BI) strategies to enhance  business processes, to align with data governance best practices, and  to manage BI initiatives. Provide leadership, strategic direction, and  project management to Campus Solutions, Academics, Business  Intelligence, and college administration.<p></p> <p>Job Description</p>
<p> </p>Business Intelligence Planning and  Management<p> </p>  Provide recommendations for the direction of  Business Intelligence to the WILM Board including use of best  practice, current BI trends, optimization of and use of BI,  integration of Balanced ScoreCard methodologies, and effective use of  BI.<p> </p>  Oversee data governance structures, policies, and  guidelines. Lead teams to incorporate best practice strategies in  managing and reporting data and maintaining data integrity.  <p> </p>  Oversee the activities for the design, development, and  implementation of the data warehouse architecture and the  configuration and auditing of the data warehouse to ensure efficiency  and quality control of data.<p> </p>  Provide oversight for data  architects, application development, and Business Intelligence staff  to design and implement BI applications.<p></p> <p>WILM Campus Solutions and Academics Planning and  Management</p>
<p> </p>  Deliver consortium-wide leadership and strategic  direction in the management and operation of shared information  services related to Student systems.<p> </p>  Provide guidance and  leadership to meet Campus Solutions  and Academics  needs and  requirements.  <p> </p>  Collaborate with stakeholders to establish  Campus Solutions  and Academics  project priorities, determine  staffing models, advocate for and manage necessary resources,  negotiate deliverables, monitor progress, resolve problems, and  communicate with stakeholders.<p> </p>  Coordinate internal resources  for flawless execution of projects. Ensure that all projects are  delivered on-time, within scope and budget. Develop project scopes and  objectives, involving all relevant stakeholders and ensuring technical  feasibility. Report and escalate issues appropriately. Create and  maintain comprehensive project documentation and progress reports on  activities.<p> </p>  Develop and continuously refine the vision and  roadmap for BI, Campus Solutions and Academics that align with the  Consortium strategic direction.<p> </p>  Provide 5 Star Service  throughout all customer interactions.<p></p> <p>Managerial Responsibilities</p>
<p> </p>Supervision is provided to the WILM  Business Intelligence Team. Responsible for the overall direction,  coordination, and evaluation of these staff. Design position  responsibilities, interview, hire, and train employees; plan, assign,  and direct work; supervise, mentor, and develop staff through the  Employee Performance review; reward and discipline employees. Carry  out managerial functions in accordance with LTC and WILM policies to  include: develop and manage annual WILM budget; address staff and  student issues in a timely and effective manner; advocate for the WILM  organization; and serve on teams and committees as necessary.<p></p> <p>Qualifications/Experience*</p>
<p> </p>  Masters  degree in Computer  Science, Information Technology, Business Intelligence, Management  Information Systems, Business Administration or related field  required.<p> </p>  Minimum 5 years leadership experience in the BI/data  warehouse field.<p> </p>  Minimum 5 years leadership experience in  higher education.<p> </p>  Training and/or certification on IBM Cognos  or related system.<p> </p>  Detailed knowledge of ETL, DMR, OLAP and  associated best practices.<p> </p>  Experience in project management  and/or project coordination.<p> </p>  Well-developed leadership skills  with highly effective written and verbal communication  skills.<p> </p>  Ability to investigate business problems, develop  effective recommendations, negotiate and/or present solutions, and  resolve problems in a highly professional and tactful  manner.<p> </p>  Proven track record of successfully managing multiple  complex enterprise projects of high visibility and  impact.<p> </p>  Excellent self-management skills. Experience working  independently with minimum supervision.<p> </p>  Exemplify college  values in all staff and student interactions, as well as services  delivered.<p> </p>  Ability to establish and maintain effective working  relationships and relate successfully with staff, students, and  citizens of diverse cultural, social or educational backgrounds.<p></p> <p>**Fluent, bilingual individual is desirable.</p> <p>*Note: Meeting the minimum requirements does not guarantee an  interview for a position.  </p> <p>Condition of Employment</p>
<p> </p>  Employment conditional on completion  of a Background Information Disclosure (BID) and the results  acceptable to the College.<p> </p>  Valid State of Wisconsin driver s  license required or access to reliable and flexible transportation to  commute from one job site to another.<p></p> <p>Benefits:</p>
<p> </p>Health Insurance Employee Assistance Program  (EAP) Vacation<p> </p>Dental Insurance Paid Leave of Absence  (PLOA) Health Reimbursement Account (HRA)<p> </p>Long Term  Disability Professional Development Flexible Spending  Program<p> </p>Life Insurance Tuition Reimbursement  On-Site Child  Care<p> </p>Wisconsin Retirement System (WRS) Holidays Wellness/Fitness Center<p></p> <p>Recruitment Period</p>
<p> </p>Beginning: Friday, November 10,  2017<p> </p>Closing: Applications will be accepted online until the  position is filled; however, to ensure full consideration, application  materials should be submitted for receipt no later than Friday,  December 15, 2017.<p></p> <p>Online Application Process</p>
<p> </p>The LTC online employment  application must be completed in its entirety to be considered for a  position at Lakeshore Technical College.  To access the online  application, visit www.gotoltc.edu, navigate to  Just for You  and  click on  Job Seekers , choose  View Employment Opportunities  to  create an account login and to apply for the position. For additional  assistance, please contact Human Resources.<p></p>
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
				<h4 id="contact-name">Bonnie Zorn</h4>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
					1290 North Avenue
				
				
					
						Cleveland, WI, 53015
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
