<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
						<!-- /4140/Dice/job_tools -->
						<div data-google-query-id="CLTIksXA7tcCFcIMgQodPjEBew" id="div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0" class="hidden-xs hidden-sm" style="height: 90px; width: 728px; margin-bottom: 10px;">
							<script type="text/javascript">
								googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-1478559205531-0'); });
							</script><div style="border: 0pt none;" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0__container__"><iframe srcdoc="" style="border: 0px none; vertical-align: bottom;" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" scrolling="no" name="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" title="3rd party ad content" id="google_ads_iframe_/4140/Dice/job_tools_0" frameborder="0" height="90" width="728"></iframe></div>
						</div>
<!--                         <div id='div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'>
                            <script type='text/javascript'>
                                googletag.cmd.push(function() { googletag.display('div-gpt-ad-136689231299775354-1'); });
                            </script>
                        </div> -->
                        <!-- End AdSlot 1 -->

                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Charlottesville, VA" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Python, Machine Learning, Predictive Analysis" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Sr Data Scientist" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Python, Machine Learning, Predictive Analysis
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br>S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence<br><br><b>The Role:  </b>Senior Data Scientist<br><br><b>The</b> <b>Location:  </b>Charlottesville or Richmond, VA<br><br><b>The Team:</b><br>The Data Science team is tasked with transforming S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence?s products and operations using machine learning and related data science techniques. We partner with business leaders to find new opportunities, implement solutions with the latest data science tools and technologies, and partner with engineering teams to deploy solutions into production software systems.<br><br><b>The Impact:</b><br>In this role, you will have the opportunity to work on a diverse range of data science projects that deliver creative, data-driven insights and novel data products that take on high-impact business problems for both the company?s customers and internal partners.<br><br><b>What?s in it for you:</b><br>We are a Fortune 500 company and recognized industry-leading provider of data and analytics; as such, we provide an unusually rich environment for data scientists to make an impact and grow personally and professionally. In addition to applying data science, you will have an opportunity to help establish the strategies and methodologies for a growing data science team.<br><br><b>Responsibilities:</b><ul>
<li>Design, execute and deploy projects aimed at solving high-impact business problems.</li>
<li>Play a central role in all stages of the data science project life cycle, including:</li>
<li>Identification of suitable data science project opportunities</li>
<li>Partnering with business leaders, domain experts, and end-users to gain business understanding, data understanding, and collect requirements</li>
<li>Data preparation</li>
<li>Data analysis/modeling</li>
<li>Evaluation/interpretation of results and presentation to business leaders</li>
<li>Partnering with software developers to provide specifications for deploying models/algorithms into production systems, when applicable</li>
<li>Prepare the exploratory data analyses, proof-of-concept modeling, and business cases necessary to generate partner consensus and internal support for your projects</li>
<li>Dedicatedly communicate the vision and status of your data science projects, ensuring that accurate expectations are set and met across all levels of partners</li>
</ul>
<br><br><b>What We?re Looking For:</b><br><br><b>Basic Qualifications:</b><ul>
<li>
<br>Bachelor?s Degree in Math, Statistics, Engineering, Computer Science, or related field; or equivalent experience</li>
<li>
<br>3-5+ yrs experience in a Data Science or other advanced data analytics role</li>
<li>
<br>Shown success in using large amounts of data to solve analytical problems</li>
<li>
<br>Strong English-speaking and writing skills required</li>
<li>
<br>Familiarity with data analysis scripting languages, such as Python or R (Python preferred)</li>
<li>
<br>Knowledge of advanced statistical data analysis and modeling</li>
<li>
<br>Experience with data mining, machine learning, natural language processing, and data visualization</li>
<li>
<br>Working knowledge of traditional data storage, relational databases, SQL, and ETL tools</li>
<li>
<br>Exposure to technologies such as Hadoop, Spark, NoSQL data stores</li>
<li>
<br>Ability to collaborate effectively with a diverse group of business, operational and technical partners</li>
<li>
<br>Ability to communicate complex mathematical models and processes in straightforward, non-technical language</li>
<li>
<br>Occasional travel is required.</li>
</ul>
<br><br><b>Preferred Qualifications:</b><ul>
<li>
<br>Graduate Degree in Math, Statistics, Engineering, Computer Science, or related field; or equivalent experience</li>
<li>
<br>Familiarity with conventional software development languages (Scala, JavaScript, C#, Java, etc.) a plus</li>
</ul>
<br><br><u><b>About S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence</b></u><br><br>At S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence, we know that not all information is important?some of it is vital. Accurate, deep and insightful. We integrate financial and industry data, research and news into tools that help track performance, generate alpha, identify investment ideas, understand competitive and industry dynamics, perform valuation and assess credit risk. Investment professionals, government agencies, corporations and universities globally can gain the intelligence essential to making business and financial decisions with conviction.<br><br>S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence is a division of S&amp;P Global (NYSE: SPGI), which provides essential intelligence for individuals, companies and governments to make decisions with confidence. For more information, visit, <a href="https://www.spcapitaliq.com/" target="_blank">S&amp;P Global Market Intelligence</a><br><br><b><i>To all recruitment agencies</i></b>: S&amp;P Global does not accept unsolicited agency resumes. Please do not forward such resumes to any S&amp;P Global employee, office location or website. S&amp;P Global will not be responsible for any fees related such resumes.<br><br><span>S&amp;P Global is an equal opportunity employer committed to making all employment decisions without regard to race/ethnicity, gender, pregnancy, gender identity or expression, color, creed, religion, national origin, age, disability, marital status (including domestic partnerships and civil unions), sexual orientation, military veteran status, unemployment status, or any other basis prohibited by federal, state or local law.</span>  <span>Only electronic job submissions will be considered for employment. </span><br><br><span>If you need an accommodation during the application process due to a disability, please send an email to: </span><a href="javascript:void(0)" target="_blank"><span><b><span style="cursor:pointer;" class="easyApplyTojob">Click here to Apply</span></b></span></a><span> and your request will be forwarded to the appropriate person. </span><br><br><span>The EEO is the Law Poster </span><a href="http://www.dol.gov/ofccp/regs/compliance/posters/pdf/eeopost.pdf" target="_blank"><span>http://www.dol.gov/ofccp/regs/compliance/posters/pdf/eeopost.pdf </span></a><span>describes discrimination protections under federal law.</span><br><img src="https://www.applytracking.com/track.aspx/i6EK6">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
