<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<!-- Adslot's refresh function: googletag.pubads().refresh([gptadslots[1]]) --><html><body>
<div class="top-ad hidden-xs" id="topad1">
                    
                </div>
				<!-- job description section start-->

				




<input value="Hollywood, CA" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="" data="" science engineer java hadoop storm spark learning id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="Senior Data Scientist" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				"Data Science"; Engineer; java; hadoop; storm; spark;avws; "machine learning"
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting not available</span>
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br>Job Summary:<br><b>Who we are.</b><br>We?re fans who help fans everywhere get in to the live events they love.  A proud division of Live Nation Entertainment, Ticketmaster has changed the way the world connects with their favorite artists, teams, and shows, and we continue to shape innovation every day. We?re not just selling tickets (though we do that better than anyone else), we?re enriching lives one amazing experience at a time. And we think <i>that?s</i> pretty amazing. If you?re passionate about the magic of live entertainment like we are, and you want to work at a company dedicated to helping millions of fans experience it, we want to hear from you.<br><br><b>Why you should work with us.</b><br>Our biggest investment is in our people. We offer comprehensive health benefits and 401k matching, student loan assistance, plus career-boosting opportunities like tuition reimbursement and targeted development sessions to help all eligible employees thrive. At Ticketmaster, expect the fast-paced excitement of a startup with the rock-solid support from an industry leader ? with plenty of ticket perks on the side.<br><u><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=01uyu27_tHo#action=share" target="_blank">See what it?s like working at Ticketmaster</a>. </u><br><br>You are an individual with a strong curiosity about, and appreciation for data. What excites you is the ability to work on large data sets representing complex events and summarize them using a broad range of algorithms and computational approaches.<br><br>At TicketMaster we have an incredibly rich collection of datasets and our site is one of the world's top 5 in terms of transaction volume and user reach.<br><br>In this role, you would be part of the Data Sciences team. You will have the opportunity to build models and see them all the way into production, eager to make an impact on the live entertainment industry. We value, as one of our core competencies, a data-driven approach. Our mandate is to use quantitative data on very large scales to deliver unique and novel insights into our customers' interests.<br><br>You will be working with some of the most exciting SW tools and frameworks like Hadoop, Hbase, Storm, Spark, just to name few, and be a key contributor to TicketMaster's new Verified Fan initiative which is one among many projects with the focus of getting tickets into hands of real fans. One of our missions is to bridge the gap between the fan and the artist.<br>Responsibilities:<br><br>In this role you will:<ul>
<li>Be part of a dynamic, highly-focused team that is responsible for providing machine-learning insights and SW products that engage TicketMaster's 170+MM users</li>
<li>Be collecting and analyzing very large data sets</li>
<li>Carry out tasks encompassing data cleansing and data normalization</li>
<li>Designing and implementing machine learning algorithms ranging from feature engineering, feature selection, clustering, predictive scoring and classification</li>
<li>Developing SW to prototype new algorithms for identifying trues fans, detecting abusive/nefarious entities, user segmentation, user interest discovery, performance optimization and user response prediction as part of a massively parallel and distributed near-real time collaborative filtering system/marketing platform</li>
<li>Be directly involved in the productization of your algorithms and ideas into full-fledged commercial-grade SW tools that will directly interact with, and affect the experience of million of users, both domestically and internationally</li>
<li>Participate in peer code reviews, write unit tests and provide feedback to other members of the team</li>
<li>Carry out rigorous model validation and model tuning/optimization as part of the natural model life-cycle</li>
</ul>
<br><br>Qualifications:<ul>
<li>
<br><span>4+ years of strong software engineering with a high-level programming language such as Java, C/C++, Python</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>Strong machine learning background inclusive of supervised and unsupervised algorithms</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>4+ years of industry experience building scalable solutions to real-world data problems, or equivalent and pertinent course work</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>Proficient in SQL and RDBMS's</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>Experience with unit testing frameworks like JUnit, Mockito or similar</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>Experience with/knowledge of frameworks like Hadoop, Spark and similar data platforms</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>Eduction: BS/MS/Ph.D. In CS, Math or Physics</span>
</li>
<li>
<br><span>Effective communication skills and enjoying work as part of a team</span>
</li>
</ul>
<br><br><b>Equal Employment Opportunity</b><br>Ticketmaster strongly supports equal employment opportunity for all applicants regardless of age (40 and over), ancestry, color, religious creed (including religious dress and grooming practices), family and medical care leave or the denial of family and medical care leave, mental or physical disability (including HIV and AIDS), marital status, domestic partner status, medical condition (including cancer and genetic characteristics), genetic information, military and veteran status, political affiliation, national origin (including language use restrictions), citizenship, race, sex (including pregnancy, childbirth, breastfeeding and medical conditions related to pregnancy, childbirth or breastfeeding), gender, gender identity, and gender expression, sexual orientation, or any other basis protected by applicable federal, state or local law, rule, ordinance or regulation. <br>We will consider qualified applicants with criminal histories in a manner consistent with the requirements of the Los Angeles Fair Chance Ordinance, for applicants in Los Angeles, California, and consistent with applicable laws in other areas.<br><br><b>Hiring Practices</b><br>The preceding job description has been designed to indicate the general nature and level of work performed by employees within this classification. It is not designed to contain or be interpreted as a comprehensive inventory of all duties, responsibilities, and qualifications required of employees assigned to this job.<br>Ticketmaster recruitment policies are designed to place the most highly qualified persons available in a timely and efficient manner. Ticketmaster may pursue all avenues available, including promotion from within, employee referrals, outside advertising, employment agencies, internet recruiting, job fairs, college recruiting and search firms. <img src="https://www.applytracking.com/track.aspx/iGAO4">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->


				<!-- job description section end-->
</body></html>
