<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD HTML 4.0 Transitional//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-html40/loose.dtd">
<html><body>
<input value="Minnetonka, MN" id="estJLoc" type="hidden"><input value="Analyst, CSP, Database, Development, Excel, Genetic, Management, MS Office, Oracle, PowerPoint, QA, QA Testing, Research, SAS, SQL, Teradata, Testing" id="estSkillText" type="hidden"><input value="IT Data Analyst, UHC Clinical Business Enablement - Telecommute" id="estJTitle" type="hidden"><input value="Full Time" id="taxTermsTextId" type="hidden"><input value="99.104.168.146" id="pcip" type="hidden"><input id="easyapplyCountries" value="united states, canada" type="hidden"><input id="maxCountNonEasyApply" value="5" type="hidden"><div class="row job-info">
		<div class="col-md-12">
			<div class="pull-left">
				<span class="icon-plugin-1 icons"></span>
			</div>
            <div class="iconsiblings" itemprop="skills">
				Analyst, CSP, Database, Development, Excel, Genetic, Management, MS Office, Oracle, PowerPoint, QA, QA Testing, Research, SAS, SQL, Teradata, Testing
			</div>
		</div>
	</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-briefcase"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
				
					<span>Full Time, Full-time</span>
					<meta itemprop="employmentType" content="full-time ">
</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icon-bank-note icons"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
			
				
					
					
						<span class="mL20">Competitive</span>
						<span itemprop="baseSalary" style="display:none"></span>
					
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row job-info">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<div class="pull-left">
			<span class="icons icon-network-2"></span>
		</div>
		<div class="iconsiblings">
			
				
					<span class="mL20">Telecommuting available</span>
				
				
			
			
				
				
					<span>Travel not required</span>
				
			
		</div>
	</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12">
		<h2 class="jobdesc">Job Description</h2>
		<div class="highlight-black" id="jobdescSec" itemprop="description">
			<br>UnitedHealth Group is a company that's on the rise. We're expanding in multiple directions, across borders and, most of all, in the way we think. Here, innovation isn't about another gadget, it's about transforming the health care industry. Ready to make a difference? Make yourself at home with us and start doing your life's best work.(sm)<br><br><b><br><b>Primary Responsibilities:</b></b><br><br>Working in a small clinical analytics-oriented team and in a dynamic rapid prototyping environment, perform data analytics<br><br><b>This includes and is not limited to:</b> <br><br>Gathering requirements <br>Defining data needs <br>Delivering data and associated findings for solutions<br>Incorporate operational understanding of how the data is created as part of the solution-ing process <br>Ensure complete and quality artifacts that can be consumed in the downstream development processes <br>Apply critical thinking and research skills to interpret data for recommendations of usage and creation of interface requirements<br><br><b><br><b>Required Experience:</b></b><br><br>5+ years of experience in healthcare data analytics <br>Experience with eligibility, claims and clinical data <br>Inquisitive mind and the ability to questions experts and provide input to best source alternatives <br>Proven track record of determining data remediation options <br>Undergraduate degree in applicable area of expertise or equivalent experience (Mathematics, Economics, Computer Science, Information Management or Statistics) <br>Knowledge of SQL, Teradata, SAS, Oracle <br>Working knowledge of any of the following internal systems: ICUE, CareOne, V360, NDB, CDB, TOPS, COSMOS, CSP Facets, or Linx <br>Proficiency with MS Office including Word, PowerPoint, Visio and Excel <br>Experience writing technical documentation<br><br><b><br><b>Preferred Experience:</b></b><br><br>Broad understanding of all health plan operational processes and systems <br>Data Profiling <br>User Acceptance Testing and/or QA testing experience <br>Knowledge of UHG data across (E&amp;I, M&amp;R and C&amp;S) <br>Strong organizational and interpersonal skills <br>Knowledge of relational databases, database structures<br>Careers with UnitedHealthcare. Let's talk about opportunity. Start with a Fortune 6 organization that's serving more than 85 million people already and building the industry's singular reputation for bold ideas and impeccable execution. Now, add your energy, your passion for excellence, your near-obsession with driving change for the better. Get the picture? UnitedHealthcare is serving employers and individuals, states and communities, military families and veterans where ever they're found across the globe. We bring them the resources of an industry leader and a commitment to improve their lives that's second to none. This is no small opportunity. It's where you can do your life's best work.(sm)<br><br><b>Diversity creates a healthier atmosphere:</b> UnitedHealth Group is an Equal Employment Opportunity/Affirmative Action employer and all qualified applicants will receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, age, national origin, protected veteran status, disability status, sexual orientation, gender identity or expression, marital status, genetic information, or any other characteristic protected by law.<br><br>UnitedHealth Group is a drug-free workplace. Candidates are required to pass a drug test before beginning employment.<br><br><b>Job Keywords:</b> healthcare data analytics, clinical data, ICUE, CareOne, V360, NDB, CDB, TOPS, COSMOS, CSP Facets, Linx, Minnetonka, MN, telecommute, remote, work from home<br><br><br><b>Job Title: </b> IT Data Analyst, UHC Clinical Business Enablement - Telecommute <br><b>Shift: </b> Day Job <br><b>Travel: </b> No <br><b>Business: </b> Clin Business Enablement/A&amp;R <br><b>Family: </b> Information Technology <br><b>Telecommuter Position: </b> Yes <br><b>Job Level: </b> Individual Contributor <br><b>Overtime Status: </b> Exempt <br><b>City: </b> Minnetonka <br><b>State: </b> MN <br><b>Country: </b> United States <br><b>Department: </b> Clinical Business Enablement
		</div>
	</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
	<div class="col-md-12 applySec lowerApply" id="lowerApplyBtn">
		




	
	
	
	
		
		
	
	

	
		
			
				<button type="button" class="btn btn-primary btn-lg dice-btn apply disableButton" id="applybtn" onclick="checkModalHTML();">Apply Now</button>
			
			
		
	
	
	


		<button data-original-title="Save" type="button" id="saveBtn2" isclicksavedjob="false" class="btn btn-default dice-btn-secondary hidden-md hidden-lg hidden-xl" issavedjob="false" onclick="saveJob(this)">
			
				
				
					<span class="icon-star-1"></span> Save this job
				
			
		</button>
	</div>
</div>

	<div class="row">
		<div id="contact-container" class="col-md-12 contact-info">
			<h3>Posted By</h3>
			
			<p id="contact-location">
				
					P.O. Box 1459
				
				
					
						Minneapolis, MN, 55440
					
					
					
				
			</p>
			
				
				
					<a data-original-title="Phone: (800) 328-5979" id="contactTT" class="dice-btn-link" data-toggle="tooltip" data-placement="top" title="">Contact</a>
				
				
			
		</div>
	</div>


<!-- DJV Estimated Salaries Section -->

			<br><hr>
<div class="row">
					<div class="col-md-12">
						<h1 class="jobdesc">Company Information</h1>
						<div class="highlight-black mTB20">
							We have modest goals: Improve the lives of others. Change the landscape of health care forever. Leave the world a better place than we found it. Such aspirations tend to attract a certain type of person. Crazy talented. Compassionate. Driven. To these individuals, we offer the global reach, resources and can-do culture of a Fortune 14 company. We provide an environment where you’re empowered to be your best. We encourage you to take risks and in return, offer a world of rewards and benefits for performance. Exceeding your limits is an exceptional start to your life's best work.(SM) Just like you, we are driven by a set of fundamental principles that are guiding our way forward. Our values of integrity, compassion, relationships, innovation, and performance serve as a foundation to transform health care. Are you in? Learn more about your future at UnitedHealth Group at http://careers.unitedhealthgroup.com
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
				<div class="row">
					
						<div class="col-md-6 wrap-l">
							<iframe class="company-media" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/7iNvN3d3HNA" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe>
						</div>
					
					
				</div>
</body></html>
